<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/feeds/category/conference.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://predragtasevski.com/</id><updated>2014-07-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Stockholm Internet Forum 2014</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2014/07/stockholm-internet-forum-2014/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2014-07-07:posts/2014/07/stockholm-internet-forum-2014/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Usually May in Stockholm is cold, chilly and indeed refreshing. However, this year the weather surprised all the participants of &lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/" title="Stockholm Internet Forum 2014"&gt;Stockholm Internet Forum 2014&lt;/a&gt;. Although it is one of the most beautiful cities in Europe, it was even more with rising sun every day. Especially coming from Nice where the weather was under storm, and sunny and long days in Stockholm were unforgettable. Before I continue with description and the nature of this year SIF, first would like to apologize for late post – I was under busy with examination, second would like to thank the organization for selecting me as a valuable participant.&lt;span id="more-1158"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being in Stockholm for the second time it is a privilege. And indeed, this year SIF surprised me with the invitation. Usually the organizers are selecting each year new participant. From their explanation only 10% of previous year participants are invited where the rest are new. Consequently, there were around 450 participants, from different countries in this year SIF14. Nonetheless, it was an event for great opportunities for networking and meeting interesting people, or see the rear ones from the previous year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which the event and the panel discussions I might say that I’m a bit disappointed, because of the repeating of the participant from SIF13. Another point that I would like to stress out regarding the event is that in this event the participants are not only a hacktivists, policy makers, whistleblowers, activities, NGO, etc., but also companies and so forth. I love the idea of selecting for each panel to have one enterprise represent, however bear in mind that people will might exploit this and take and pursue a totally different aspect of the discussion. Therefore, I suggest for the organization to select wisely the enterprise panelists. For instance, make sure that the topic and the theme of the panels are emphasized and understood by the wide audience, as well as that the chair man and the panelists will control the floor and that the topic will not go outside of content. This is due to this event, some panel discussions were totally misunderstood by the audience and indeed some participants were frustrated, for instance me, but also many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, coming back to the selection of percentage of the participant. I frankly love the idea that you like to bring different audience and different people each year event, however in my opinion and as well as from other that we discussed during the event is that will be much better that from the 10% is either 15-20%. This is due to fact that most if the time these topics and events only and usually bring new topics and questions, and not give answers to them. So in this respect you will have a continuing discussions and most probably some answers, coupled with outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I would like to take an opportunity to respond to the participant that were emphasizing the participation of one of the hot topic and indeed well known person, today – Edward Snowden. In respect to their request where is Snowden and so on, I would like to point out few things: first in international law it is firstly impossible to bring him in Sweden because of his status in Russia; moreover there is no need for him to take participation in the event where we talk about freedom of Internet, as well as the espionage, privacy, policy, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sum, again thanks to the organization for inviting me once again to the event. Second, by taking into account the above suggestions, personally thing that the event will be more progressive, as well as proactive by having outcome. Further, bring people, panelists which are wisely selected compliance to the topic and theme of the event and/or discussion. In the end, looking forward seeing you in the next year, as well hope that I will be taking place this time as one of panelist. Where not only that I could contribute with the discussion but also bring some new important questions in the podium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Presentation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="400" height="300"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705209908%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705209908%2F&amp;set_id=72157648705209908&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705209908%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705209908%2F&amp;set_id=72157648705209908&amp;jump_to=" width="400" height="300"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="sctockholm"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="freedom"></category><category term="forum"></category><category term="2014"></category><category term="cyber security"></category></entry><entry><title>Belgrade Security Forum 2013 – Session 7: Assuring Cyber-Security in the Western Balkans and the Rest of Europe</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/10/belgrade-security-forum-2013-session-7-assuring-cyber-security-in-the-western-balkans-and-the-rest-of-europe/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2013-10-10:posts/2013/10/belgrade-security-forum-2013-session-7-assuring-cyber-security-in-the-western-balkans-and-the-rest-of-europe/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I have received the invitation letter from administration of Belgrade Security Forum, within goal of inviting me to be a speaker in one of the break out sessions. In particular the session topic is: &lt;strong&gt;Assuring Cyber-Security in the Western Balkans and the Rest of Europe.&lt;/strong&gt; And of course, I have accepted the invitation. Speak of which, the &lt;em&gt;Belgrade Security Forum&lt;/em&gt; has been in past few years. This – 2013 year was the third in the row event. And with it, we have continue the talk from the previous year session about cyber security: &lt;a href="http://2012.belgradeforum.org/agenda/session3.html%20&amp;amp;quot;Belgrade%20Security%20Forum%202012"&gt;Cyber War and Cyber Crime: Responding to the Governance Challenges&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turning to this year session, we had a very good chance to boost the enthusiasm from other panel discussion where chairman – Richard Thomson called me in between the discussion of Helsinki Plus 40: Strengthening the Security Community to Meet Current Security Challenges. Where he raise the issue of what and if it is possible with one click that someone could stop the energy, power supply or even telecommunication systems. And, my answer was very straightforward, indeed it is! This was a very good spur of inspiration of our breakout session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with other speaker we came to conclusion that the best way to go ahead and to have an effective discussion is to open the most important questions relating to cyber security: &lt;strong&gt;Who? What? and How?&lt;/strong&gt; But before further to the answers the above question, I would like also to mention that the speakers where kind of divided, in a good sense where we came from different regions as well as specialized fields in cyber security. In details, &lt;strong&gt;Baroness Pauline Neville-Jones&lt;/strong&gt; was in related fields in government issues and challenges in cyber security. Where on other hand, I was a representative from the Wester Balkan region representative. Furthermore, &lt;strong&gt;Alexander Klimburg&lt;/strong&gt; was more concentrating of different stakeholder, in other words multi stakeholders approach. Where last but not least, &lt;strong&gt;Jovan Kurbalija&lt;/strong&gt; was in diplomacy, civil society and information technology. And finally, the moderator of the session was &lt;strong&gt;Vladimir Radunović&lt;/strong&gt;, who manage to create a nice vibe between the speakers and the audience from the beginning until the end of the session. For more details of the session please follow the Breakout session report: &lt;a href="http://belgradeforum.org/info/news/459/Session+7%3A+Assuring+Cyber-Security+in+the+Western+Balkans+and+the+Rest+of+Europe.html" title="Session 7: Assuring Cyber-Security in the Western Balkans and the Rest of Europe"&gt;Session 7: Assuring Cyber-Security in the Western Balkans and the Rest of Europe&lt;/a&gt;. For more information of the issues that we follow and given answers are available on the &lt;a href="http://www.belgradeforum.org/agenda/sesija5.html" title="Agenda"&gt;Agenda&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From left to right: Vladimir Radunović, Predrag Tasevski, Jovan Kurbalija, Alexander Klimburg and Baroness Pauline Neville-Jones&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I would like to make some quick notes on the main cyber threats and possible effects that are linked to Western Balkan region. The most known and presented cyber threats are among the cybercrime. For instance in one hand are: employee fraud, minor and child pornography; using of mobile telephones and smartphones as tools to commit other crime; identity theft and credit card fraud. Where on the other hand are among the political, moral, ethical and other motivation reasons. Such as, web-based attacks, mostly committed by defacement or denial-of-service attacks. Then we have phising and spoofing social networking sites. Where the possible effects are for instance for individuals loss of money, and of course political or ethical doctrine. Moreover, awareness of roles and responsibilities of different actors, such as government, regulators, industry and civil society of risk are taken into consideration only the implementation of law. For instance, data protection law and so on. Turning to the industry and civil society is almost the same, although some of them are implementing the very known standards, such as ISO 27001 and so on. However, is this enough? The roles and responsibilities are only described in the data protection law and criminal law. Unfortunately, it is not carried out by the framework or even a strategy. Likelihood, awareness level in Western Balkans presented by my paper back book that I have conducted last year, &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Interactive-Cyber-Security-Awareness-Program/dp/3659207985/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;amp;qid=1367779682&amp;amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;amp;keywords=Interactive+Cyber+Security+Awareness+Program" title="Interactive Cyber Security Awareness Program"&gt;Interactive Cyber Security Awareness Program Cyber Security Awareness Program&lt;/a&gt;. This book outlines the survey done around 1000 participants, from 11 to 63 years old. In diversity of carries, such as schools, universities, private and public organizations. In total we had 35% people using computers/internet from home and 26% from office. In particular and most interesting figures for us are results about the knowledge of protecting their IT assets, and in details: 16% are very knowledgeable, least knowledgeable are 13% and last but not least somewhat knowledgeable are 40%. Therefore from the results presented we can see that awareness level among the end users is vary. Coming to the end, if we want to make sure the involvement of end users in raising trust and securing the cyberspace we firstly have to start from strategy, than legal framework, followed by implementation, and so on. However, when it comes to step to get done by governments should be as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop and create strategy framework for Cyber-security, in particular, not to cover the area only of cyber crime, but also how to mitigate happened incidents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rewrite and review the cyber crime law and data protection law.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create NGO or NPO that will deal not only for a concrete country but of course the entire region, as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end I have noted that some countries in Wester Balkans do not have &lt;strong&gt;yet&lt;/strong&gt; either, CERT – Critical Emergency Response Team nor CIRT – Critical Incident Response Team. Therefore, this action should be taken as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, hope that the above notes will take effect, as well as will raise the awareness of the important in fact issue. Therefore we have to be simple and follow just simple three steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strategical plan which will aim in business continuity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partnership between Groups, such as government, private and civil. As well as to provide awareness on the share bases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education the public, where we need to take an action of re-informing the school materials, and to provide the young generations guide of how to protect in cyber space and skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to the participant, speakers, guest, organizers and everyone for such a lovely stay in Belgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="400" height="300"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648695812727%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648695812727%2F&amp;set_id=72157648695812727&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648695812727%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648695812727%2F&amp;set_id=72157648695812727&amp;jump_to=" width="400" height="300"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="conference"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="balkans"></category><category term="western"></category><category term="assurance"></category><category term="europe"></category></entry><entry><title>Stockholm Internet Forum 2013</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/06/stockholm-internet-forum-2013/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2013-06-06:posts/2013/06/stockholm-internet-forum-2013/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year the Stockholm Internet Forum 2013 was addressing the freedom of Internet, human rights, freedom of speech, censorship, privacy as well as importance of security. Among the topics, also we have touched the cyber security, surveillance, importance of information security coupled with critical information infrastructure and critical infrastructure. Once Alex Levin has said – “The reason there is so little crime in Germany is that it’s against the law.” – What a hack he was talking? Was he right or wrong? For this reason, the SIF was held this year with more than 94 different countries participants, from all over the world. And indeed, it was one of the best conference organized so far. Nevertheless the number of differential participants let the talks and the conference topics just to flow. Even that the four days of talking was not enough. However, this was just a start, or for someone the beginning of an idea due to the poverty of our thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The opening speech was by Carl Bildt where he presented in fact an importance of digital revolution, African development through connectivity, political debates for freedom of Internet. In addition, he gave a couple of great examples, such as legislations of blocking sites in Russia, violations of human rights in Syria, Vietnam among the others. Also, he noted the security importance of cyber security, where security should be thought but of course should not be used in purpose to limit the human rights. One very good quote, even after two weeks from the conference I still have it in my head, is &lt;strong&gt;*“Free societies are strong societies”&lt;/strong&gt;. Last but not least, was that we should take an examples from the leading nations of ICT, such as, Sweden, where the security coupled with human rights are presented on Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frankly, in the opening session we have touched the issue with surveillance and software used for this purpose, coupled with the viability of digital divide popular in Africa and among others. Moreover, we have purse the issue of Internet jurisdiction projects, as well as that we have to boost the awareness of regulations united with the important factor to increased the civil societies in freedom. For more info please visit the summaries notes from the session, &lt;a title="Opening session" href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/opening-session/"&gt;Opening session&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To continue with the first session again we have to come back some example of the above issue, surveillance, where Mexico has &lt;a title="Closed-circuit television - Wikipedia" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Closed-circuit_television"&gt;CCTV&lt;/a&gt; in private sector for 3 to 4 years. Among the surveillance we have discuss the issue during the riots in London, Syria and Panama as a recent examples where they have shutdown the mobile phone network. Additionally, point in some countries is that people do trust the law enforcement in privacy, where opposite such as in Pakistan they trust only the companies, and not law enforcement agencies. Moreover, hate speech, digital freedom and democracy of freedom was carried out, along with how the law works on Internet with civil societies and that the police need to do their own job. Nevertheless, the note was that vocabulary of cyber security is missing, and it should become a national security and of course the security is a huge problem. This problem is done due to the lack of new laws, by definition of what we mean by a single law treaty. Whom we should secure? What should be asked? In sentence of security importance, civil society. We really need a cyber security strategy, by introducing the legislation and laws throughout experience. In spite of vocabulary e should define and terms, such as, &lt;a title="Hacktivism - Wiki" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hacktivism"&gt;hacktivism&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="Cyberterrorism - Wiki" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cyberterrorism"&gt;cyberterrorism&lt;/a&gt;. One important note was mentioned that we do not want global cyber security law. For more info of the session please visit the following link &lt;a title="Session 1: Reconciling freedom and security in cyberspace" href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/session-1/informal-summary/"&gt;Reconciling freedom and security in cyberspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned above the frustration was between the west and developing countries in sentence of digital divide. Also one note was that Sweden people trust to the government agencies, as well as that e-voting system in Sweden will help ICT to boost. The session where split into three parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title="1A Global security and human rights in the internet age" href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/session-1a/informal-summary-of-session-1a/"&gt;1A Global security and human rights in the internet age&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title="1B Distributed security in a national context" href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/session-1b/informal-summary/"&gt;1B Distributed security in a national context&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a title="1C Free and secure communication in a multinational context" href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/session-1c/informal-summary/"&gt;1C Free and secure communication in a multinational context&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next day, the second day of the forum (SIF13) we have touched a facts about the free and open Internet and open communications. The second day I will remember forever for speech of the famous Cuban blogger Yoani Sánchez, which said very good quote “Cuba Internet on Internet” or another one is that if your relatives or you personally travel to Cuba bring the old and unused gadgets with you and leave them in Cuba or just give them, rather than you should just dispose them or throw them into the trash. For more info please visit the &lt;a title="Summaries 2013 | Stockholm Internet Forum" href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/summaries-2013/" target="_blank"&gt;Summaries 2013 page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I might say that the SIF 13 was very successful, as well as very important questions and topics were discussed. However, we should concentrate for the next year forum on more specific topics, either freedom or only a security. It is very difficult when we speak about freedom coupled with security. Does two topics are very linked and fragile. In the end, I would like to thank a lot to the organizers, &lt;a title=".SE" href="https://www.iis.se/" target="_blank"&gt;.SE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a title="Ministry for Foreign Affairs - Sweden" href="http://www.government.se/sb/d/2059" target="_blank"&gt;Ministry for Foreign Affairs – Sweden&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title="SIDA" href="http://www.sida.se/Svenska/" target="_blank"&gt;SIDA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Pictures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="400" height="300"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648696553859%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648696553859%2F&amp;set_id=72157648696553859&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648696553859%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648696553859%2F&amp;set_id=72157648696553859&amp;jump_to=" width="400" height="300"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="internet"></category><category term="forum"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="stockholm"></category><category term="freedom"></category></entry><entry><title>Collective Cyber Defence – The Role of Newer Members and Opportunities for Specialization of Bulgaria in the Alliance Questions and answers</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/03/collective-cyber-defence-the-role-of-newer-members-and-opportunities-for-specialization-of-bulgaria-in-the-alliance-questions-and-answers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2013-03-12:posts/2013/03/collective-cyber-defence-the-role-of-newer-members-and-opportunities-for-specialization-of-bulgaria-in-the-alliance-questions-and-answers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;November is a month of &lt;a href="http://www.paneuropa.bg/en/news/38/PanEuropa-Bulgaria-organizes-international-conference-with-the-special-support-of-NATO" title="PanEuropa Bulgaria organizes international conference with the special support of NATO"&gt;Smart&amp;nbsp;Defense and Open – Door Policy – New Synergies for Euro –Atlantic Security&lt;/a&gt;. Not only in Europe, but also in South-East European region as well. The following international event was organized by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.paneuropa.bg/" title="PanEuropa Bulgaria"&gt;PanEuropa&amp;nbsp;Bulgaria&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and it was supported by NATO. Furthermore, I was invited to take a participation as a speaker on the panel discussion&amp;nbsp;Collective Cyber Defence – The Role of Newer Members and Opportunities for Specialization of Bulgaria in the Alliance Questions and answers. In details, the event main points ware to highlight the need for specialization of each member state in terms of the principles of Smart Defense and the joint participation in future military operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the event had splendid video addressing in the opening session of Neelie Kroes, the Vice – President of European Commission. Emphasizing the current online spying crisis as well as the importance of cyber security strategy. In additional, she highlighted the importance of new legal threats, information norms coupled to boost the trust among the Europe. As well as, that the weakest link in the chain should be able to raise and boost the awareness, coupled with the future investments in research and innovations, and projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the collective cyber defense panel discussion, I was delighted to be speaker with such strong&amp;nbsp;extensive and experienced experts from different fields. Such as private, public, academy and business sectors. Speaking of which, the moderator of the panel was Prof. Veselin Tselkov, D. Sc., Member of the Board, Commission for Personal Data Protection in Bulgaria. The lectures where: unfortunately Col. Associate Prof. Dr. Stoyan Balabanov, Director, Institute for Defense, Ministry of Defense Bulgaria, was not able to attend the panel, however we had representative from MoD. Also from Bulgaria was Zlatogor Minchev from Institute of Information and Communication Technologies, Bulgaria. From Macedonian was Dr. Metodi Hadji-Janev (LtC), Assistant Prof., Military Academy ” General Mihailo Apostolski”, Skopje, Macedonia. From business prospective I was the presenter of &lt;a href="http://cybersecurity.mk" title="CyberSecurity.mk"&gt;CyberSecurity.mk&lt;/a&gt; copmany, based in Macedonia. In addition, Mr. Robert Griffin, Director Business Development – Security Systems, RSA. From all the above, we also had video addressing from Mr. Detlef Puhl, Senior Advisor at the Emerging Security Challenges Division, NATO&amp;nbsp;Headquarters, and Mr. Philippe Roggeband, Security Sales Business Development Manager, EBG EMEAR, Cisco Systems. However, due to the security measures in the building where the event was held the video addressing was interrupted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, here is my short presentation notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyberspace has become one of the most essential and distinguished bridge between government and their inhabitants. Thus, the people are able to get access to government services 24/7, as well as their life becomes more easier. However, all in this has led to advance of producing cyberspace to be vulnerable, coupled with information’s that should not be available to others. For this reason I would like to share three important points that are fundamental to emphasis when we discuss about the Cyber defense in general. First, we have to understand and highlight the difference between Cyber Security vs IT Security. Second, it is the important to boost the awareness level tailored to national level, social society, private sector and indeed multistakeholder cooperation in the region. Last but not least, we have to brake the lack of communications between the neighboring countries and to create a trusted, same level, and collaboration of cyber security. Where national agencies and parties should work together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, first the main goal of IT security is to protect information from a wide range of threats in order to ensure business continuity, reduce business damages and maximize return on investments and business opportunity. Likewise the cyber security is protecting Information and Communication Technologies (ICT) systems and Critical Infrastructure (CI). However the most important protection element in IT security is to reduce business risk to accepted levels and the protection of entire information and information systems essential to the organizations. Alternatively, cyber security aims at assuring critical IT service for CI and CII on accepted levels, in addition to the protection of critical information. In other words the security objective determiner in information security is an organization’s business process, while in cyber security it is for the entire state. Emphasizing that states may have different or complementary interests compared to an organization’s business interests. On one hand, handling cyber security problems is considered to be both a nationally and internationally coordinated activity to protect national CII. Similarly, to information security goals: confidentiality, availability and integrity, in cyber security the additional goals are non-repudiation, authentication, information systems importance and criticality from the standpoint of state CII/CI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turning to awareness, I would like to share my recent research that have been published as book, title: Interactive Cyber Security Awareness Program. It is highlighting the method, approach and the importance of current awareness level in Western Balkans. Coupled how to boost the awareness on the national level. I would not like to go in details, however, just want to mention that the positive results were presented, and that the awareness level among the end users are varied. Moreover, in particular we have to create and recognize the importance of establishing cyber security awareness strategy, coupled with influence of the weakest link in cyber security, which is the human factor, or in other words, social-technical aspects. In spite of our investment in technologies and in the applications, still the weakest link in cyber defense and security will the human behavior. Therefore, we will have to conceive an awareness/education to raise the awareness on the national behalf, such as, from the young to the oldest generation, tailored through social society, private sector and multistakeholder cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, in recent years we are witnesses of acts that have taken into place between neighboring countries in the region. Such acts were followed by different motivations of attacks. Where mostly they were done through defacement’s or denial-of-service attacks. Thus, motivations where divers. Nevertheless, in this last point is I would like to stress the importance of merging the best practices learned from past event occurrence as well as to improve the role of newer members and opportunities into the collective roles of cyber defence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, I am keen that after this discussion/panel will lead into further actions. And also thanks to the organizers for the invitation and done a good job in organizing such an important event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="400" height="300"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157646785203333%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157646785203333%2F&amp;set_id=72157646785203333&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157646785203333%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157646785203333%2F&amp;set_id=72157646785203333&amp;jump_to=" width="400" height="300"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="cyber defence"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="bulgaria"></category><category term="balkan"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="nato"></category></entry></feed>