<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece - art of war</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/feeds/art-of-war.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://predragtasevski.com/</id><updated>2011-04-20T23:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Major changes in warfare from antiquity to modern</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2011/04/major-changes-in-warfare-from-antiquity-to-modern/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-04-20T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2011-04-20T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2011-04-20:/posts/2011/04/major-changes-in-warfare-from-antiquity-to-modern/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Analyse the major changes in warfare from antiquity to modern days. What are the most significant changes? What has remained unchanged?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we start the discussion about the major changes in warfare from
antiquity to present day we will precede with definition of War and its
significant and remained unchanged …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Analyse the major changes in warfare from antiquity to modern days. What are the most significant changes? What has remained unchanged?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we start the discussion about the major changes in warfare from
antiquity to present day we will precede with definition of War and its
significant and remained unchanged changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WAR in its literal meaning is fighting, for fighting alone is the
efficient principle in the manifold activity which, in a wide sense, is
called war. But fighting is a trial of strength of the moral and
physical forces by means of the latter. That the moral cannot be omitted
is evident of itself, for the condition of the mind has always the most
decisive influence on the forces employed in war (Graham, 2002).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humanity has wedged war since antiquity through nowadays for million
causes, national and religious freedom, hatred, grudge, human rights,
liberating the enslaved etc. But one principle in war has always been
present from the depths of history till today, that is, wars are fought
for one purpose only, conquest of new territory from which economic
benefit is to be acquired for the soul use of the conqueror. Nowhere is
this more obvious than in the armed clashes of the beginning of the XXI
century, when under the pretext of human rights countries are being
robed from their natural resources and air-raids are killing those whom
should protect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we met with the theory of war and moral principles, it is time to
consider changes that have occurred between the ancient and modern
times. The military of ancient Egypt had introduced the new technologies
of metal, where they used bronze in the Middle Kingdom as main weapons
source, after it changed to iron in the New Kingdom and all during the
Late Dynastic Period. The Old Kingdom soldiers were equipped with a
great variety of weapons: shields, spears, cudgels, maces, daggers, bows
and arrows. The New Kingdom carried spears, battle axes, sickleswords
(MdC transliteration: xpS – khepesh or khopesh) and daggers. After the
bowmen, either on foot or on chariots, had softened up the enemy forces
with a shower of arrows (Dollinger, Dynasties XVIII to XX, 2004), the
infantry would rush in, breaking their ranks with hand weapons, maces
with wooden handles and stone – later metal – heads, battle axes,
hatchets, clubs, swords, sickleswords and daggers (Dollinger, Weapons,
2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Persian Army had only three wars, started from 490 BC until 478BC, the
army was very multicultural, were organizes in a decimal basis,
regiments, units and corps were grouped in tens, hundreds and thousands
(Drury, 2006). Officers were being responsible for ten men, another for
one hundred, one thousand and ten thousand. Heavily equipped with
weapons, which are: Thrusting Spear, palta, Akinakes , Xiphos, kopis,
bow etc (Wildfiregames, 2004).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greece war, first nine years of the war consisted of both war in Troy
and war against the neighbouring regions, where destroyed Trojan
economy, allowed Greeks to getter a large amount of resources. The
Greeks won most of the battles, but they still could not break the walls
of Troy. The weapons that were used in those battles were bows and
arrows. As for strategies the famous Trojan horse, when Odysseus had a
perfect idea to build a big wooden horse where inside will be field with
the soldiers, which bring and invasion of Troy from the Greeks (Rita,
2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Army of Macedonia was the army of ancient Kingdom of Macedonia. It
considers a grate military force where there were reforms constructed
from the suggestion of King Philip II of Macedon and then his son
Alexander the Great. The introduction was in innovation of weapons and
new tactics, along with unique elements combination of military
elements, which bring a great intercontinental empire (Ellis, 1979).
Philip II had implemented in Macedonian phalanx army separation which
one group were on a mission to conquer a city and the other to conquer
castles. Each phalangite carried as his primary weapon a sarissa, but
the phalangite were not the focal point for the battle, they have used
other forces like: skirmishers, range troops, reserves of allied
hoplites, and artillery (Hellenica, 2005).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rome in the wars had adapted weapons, armour and tactics of many enemies
they fought. Main weapons of Rome soldiers were Spanish sword – gladius,
it had two throwing spears, a large shield, body armour and a helmet.
They have also operated with the fire supported weapons, scorpios,
carroballistas, onagers. For a fest moves they started to build bridges,
so that the soldiers and the army can move faster. The army can march up
to 30 km a day. They were very evil, trained to stab a 5 cm deep wound,
after breaking the enemy, Romans tended to kill as many enemies as
possible and their cavalry pursued fleeing enemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Rome the medieval Europe warfare followed, which was the war
of legal and acceptable justification, nobility (knights) and the main
force on the battlefield was a heavy cavalry, where the law of the armed
conflict was born. The second largest empire in human history was the
Mongol empire. Mongols army had the capacity to move up to 150 km a day.
The weapons of the army consisted of massive fire (bow) speed and
manoeuvres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wars of the XVI Century were mostly protracted and indecisive. There was
insistency on building a fortress that was very difficult to conquer.
The most important improvement is the side of the weapons with adoption
of light guns and gunpowder. Gustavus Adolphus had guns in his army, he
had 1 gun per 83, but his enemies had 1 gun per 2000 men. The main thing
was to build and modify the fortresses for safety and hard to conquer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;World War I, sometimes described as ‘the war to end all wars’ (Creveld,
2000, p. 162), the strategies were based on first manoeuvre, and then
attrition. Forces and armaments were infantry, cavalry artillery, and
surface navy (initially); later – tanks, planes, submarines, chemical
weapons. The tactics were manoeuvre, frontal assaults, fortified
defence, artillery concentration (initially); the theoretical thinking:
seeking the way out of dead end, but not finding the means and ways. The
first known bombardment from the sky, using airplanes was by Bulgarian
army on the 16 of October 1912 at battle of Adrianople, where they were
captivated by the Turkish army. From the German newspaper “Geschichte
des Luftkriegs”, Militarverlag der DDR, Berlin, 1975, though the 1912
United Kingdom had 23 air planes, Russian – 99, German – 46, Italian –
22, Japan – 10 and USA – 3 air planes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second World War, where the technology and the concept of the war were
getting bigger, developed into a prolonged and extremely deadly struggle
of attrition. The Germans invented the rockets (vau1 and vau2).
Hiroshima and Nagasaki are the first and only events of deployments of
nuclear weapons in the world.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second half of the 20th century, after the valuable technical point, the
arms forward for an outbreak of terrorism. That means that wars are no
longer big and global; the enemy is no longer in uniforman in force. And
size is no longer as great as it was the enemy can attack from anywhere.
Therefore, no longer wars head-do met the two armies, but running by
partisan / guerillas. Terrorism is an unconventional war de facto, i.e.
anti-insurgent operation, i.e. counter insurgency. Which create the kind
of combat actions that are performed nowadays in Afghanistan and Iraq.
In the 20th century, has one goal, redistribution of resources, i.e. to
get to justify the need to test before the war for democracy and human
rights. Macedonia is the country that is inclined towards terrorism, the
early 20th century, April 28 1903rd in Thessaloniki, the boatmen of
Thessaloniki have committed terrorist actions against the capital of
Western Europe and Turkey, i.e. have planted bombs in the Ottoman Bank
in Thessaloniki, the main post office, and planted a bomb in a ship
(Sotros, 2004 December).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As can read above the changes are very drastic. Humanity is fighting for
the different purpose; starting from the antiquity to nowadays, not only
in weapons that were used and presented, but in the strategies in a
tactics and theoretical thinking. Therefore, there are no more battles
wars, people are grouping and they can embattle from anywhere, which
gives a content of the terroristic activities of the wars. Today the
humanity and the scholars should getter together to work around of the
problems and solutions for the future, possibilities of internet (social
networks, VOIP, IM etc.), net generations1, thus today it is the main
source of grouping the population for massive protests or any other
actions, which can end-up to a war or scandal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently the technology and science are rising, the possibilities
and the changes in an aspect of wars will change. For instant is Russian
– Georgian conflict in 2008 as a result of territorial attack and in
sequence with it there was an cyber-attack in progress2; or powerful
internet worm repeatedly targeted five nuclear industrial facilities in
Iran and many others3. Therefore, nowadays this actions and concept of
warfare is different, no more uniforms, battles etc. Warfare’s are
getting new aspect and new ways to approach through the technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Reference&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creveld, M. V. (2000). THE INTERWAR PERIOD. In M. v. Creveld, The Art of
War – War and Military Thought. London: Cassell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dollinger, A. (2004, November). Dynasties XVIII to XX. Retrieved from
Ancient Egyptian history:
&lt;a href="http://www.reshafim.org.il/ad/egypt/history18-20.htm#merneptah"&gt;http://www.reshafim.org.il/ad/egypt/history18-20.htm#merneptah&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dollinger, A. (2010, March). Weapons. Retrieved from Pharaonic Egypt:
&lt;a href="http://www.reshafim.org.il/ad/egypt/weapons/index.html#rem4"&gt;http://www.reshafim.org.il/ad/egypt/weapons/index.html#rem4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drury, M. (2006, February). Battles of the Achaemenid Empire . Retrieved
from A History Resource by Mark Drury:
&lt;a href="http://members.ozemail.com.au/~ancientpersia/batt_frm.html"&gt;http://members.ozemail.com.au/~ancientpersia/batt_frm.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ellis, J. R. (1979). Philip II and Macedonian Imperialism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graham, C. J. (2002). On The Theory Of War, Section: Branches of the Art
of War. Retrieved 2011, from Clausewitz, ON WAR:
&lt;a href="http://www.clausewitz.com/readings/OnWar1873/BK2ch01.html"&gt;http://www.clausewitz.com/readings/OnWar1873/BK2ch01.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hellenica. (2005, 04). Macedonian phalanx. Retrieved from Hellenica:
&lt;a href="http://www.mlahanas.de/Greeks/LX/MacedonianPhalanx.html"&gt;http://www.mlahanas.de/Greeks/LX/MacedonianPhalanx.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rita. (2010). The Trojan War. Retrieved from Stanford University:
&lt;a href="/http://www.stanford.edu/~plomio/history.html#anchor202941"&gt;http://www.stanford.edu/\~plomio/history.html#anchor202941&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sotros, J. (2004 December). The Greek Speaking Anarchist and
Revolutionary Movement (1830–1940) Writings for a History. No God-No
Masters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wildfiregames. (2004, September). Persia: Arms of the Shah-an-Shah –
Persian Arms an. Retrieved from 0 A.D. :: Wildfire Games:
&lt;a href="http://wildfiregames.com/0ad/page.php?p=1581"&gt;http://wildfiregames.com/0ad/page.php?p=1581&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] The Net Generation Brain by Don Tapscott (2009)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="http://zdnet.com/blog"&gt;ZDnet.com/blog&lt;/a&gt; – Coordinated Russia vs
Georgia cyber attack in progress  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3] &lt;a href="http://bbc.co.uk/technology"&gt;BBC.co.uk/technology&lt;/a&gt; – Stuxnet virus
targets and spread revealed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="antiquity"></category><category term="art of war"></category><category term="changes warfare"></category><category term="cyber"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="cyber warfare"></category><category term="history"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="modern"></category><category term="networking"></category><category term="new war"></category><category term="nework crime"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="war"></category><category term="war strategy"></category></entry><entry><title>Information society and information warfare</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2011/01/information-society-and-information-warfare/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2011-01-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2011-01-06:/posts/2011/01/information-society-and-information-warfare/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Meaning of victory in conflict in the information age. What has changed? What has remained unchanged? How information society and information warfare influences achieving the victory?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rapid development of information technology (IT) over the past three
decades has led to many changes for example in military and defense
circles …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Meaning of victory in conflict in the information age. What has changed? What has remained unchanged? How information society and information warfare influences achieving the victory?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rapid development of information technology (IT) over the past three
decades has led to many changes for example in military and defense
circles, social society, and economy in the information age. Nowadays
many scholars are in a process of developing theories and concept of
affective influence of victory in conflicts in the information age. In
this essay the main discussions are about the interchanges of victory in
conflict in the information age in aspect of divers’ view of anatomy of
information warfare; different views and approaches to information
warfare/operation in a couple of countries, which will end with
conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, much of the enthusiasm for the information-led revolution in
military affairs (RMA) or military transformation (as the newly
preferred term of art), specifically in Gulf War model of decisive
action appeared to demonstrate how total victory could be achieved
reliably in the future (Gray, April 2002, p. 30). RMA’s are immoderate,
abrupt prose changes in paths of warfare waged and they are brought by
development of technology and social changes. Therefore, in the end of
Cold War development has formed the basis of RMA, where the present is
usually defined as a transition to network-based/network-centric warfare
(NCW), for instance: stealth technology, precision-guided munitions
(PGM), computer technologies (Internet), etc. In addition the examples
of implementing RMA are Afghanistan (2001) and Iraq (2003) war, where
they started as traditional conflicts and transformed into insurgencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Carl von Clausewitz’s book On War, “War is an act of
violence whose object is to compel the enemy to do our will”. Yet, 2000
years earlier Sun Tzu, established a benchmark for a mastery of war “To
subdue the enemy without fighting is the acme of skill.” Underlying
those statements is an appreciation of the psychology of war. Indeed, by
combining the statements Commander Randall G. Bowdish made a dissent
statement of information age psychological operations “to compel the
enemy to do our will without fighting. (Bowdish, December1998 – February
1999)”. Another view made by other commander remark “In war there can be
no substitute for victory.” General Douglas MacArthur, 1951 (Gray, April
2002).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the history of 20th century sufficesto remind us that
there are many ways to win a war, but still various ways are not
equivalent, and final victory does not necessarily belong to the side
that dictates the conditions of peace. Which lends to viewpoint of how
should we determine whether the victory is at hand, and define the time
end of major battlefield to see if the post-war payoffs have been
archived. Yet, there are moral considerations, archiving peace, e.g.
humanitarian intervention, fair treatment may accelerate cessation of
hostilities and surrender and law of armed conflict sets strict rules of
behaviours by using weapon systems, treatment of prisoners, etc.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, in the past, before World War I, there are fewer clear
victories, of 311 wars from 1480 to 1970; only 137 wars were concluded
with a peace treaty. Specifically, after World War II, almost 50% of the
wars have been followed by a renewed fighting after initial cessation of
hostilities. But, since the end of Cold War acceptability of armed force
have continued and even escalated, particularly in open political
systems. Such as, globalization is a strong impediment waging a total
war. Therefore, today in the era of democracy, wars are hard to start,
but even harder to bring to an end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, the modern wars/information warfare consists on different
vector of victory. Today is unacceptable to have extreme violence, such
as losing small wars. Thus, victory today has changed drastically and
vector consists of six aspects: informational(e.g. intelligence in
internal and external sources, protection of information system with
manipulation or disruption of its enemy), military (e.g. military
security, action itself, enemy’s attack against the action and defense
for the action against enemy’s attack), political (e.g. political
stability, national interests, etc.) , economical (e.g. rebuilding of
economical infrastructure, integration into the regional and global
economy, trading of shares), social (e.g. ethnic, religious,
nationalistic, social society violence to resolve in internal and
external conflicts) and diplomatic (e.g. involving reliable approval and
tangible support for the war outcome from the victory domestic public,
foreign allies, international organizations and other observers)
(Ahvenainen, January 2000).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a consequence these changes mean decreased importance of nation
states, increased importance of virtual reality, network organizations
and dominance of economy, information, technical intelligence and other
information and network based organizations (Ahvenainen, January 2000).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another change in information age is terrorism. Information age
terrorism may take on three distinct forms: conventional terrorism,
technoterrorism, and cyberterrorism. The purpose weapons of the
cyberterrorist are not designed to kill people or break physical
objects. Rather, they exist exclusively to destroy or modify computer
data. The weapons and the targets are the electrons moving within
cyberspace. While it is possible to attack this data without any human
interfaces, the human is usually the weakest link in a computer system
(Littleton, December 1996).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To illustrate historically, there have been observed four waves of
modern terrorism:1880-1920: anarchist terrorism (began in Russia),
1920-1960: terrorism in support of national liberation (IRA, Irgun,
PLO), 1960-1980: neo-leftist terrorism (Action Directe, BrigateRosso,
Rote ArmeeFraktion) and 1980-present: religious terrorism (Hamas,
al-Qaeda, Islamic Jihad) (Cronin &amp;amp; James , 2004).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand of information terrorism there is modern insurgency,
likelihood counterinsurgency. Modern insurgency is supported by a wide
variety of non-state actors from abroad and it consists of many
foreign/local society fighters in addition to local population. They
still need support of the local population, but as it does not aspire
for straight military victory. Nowadays insurgency, could be weaker than
previous generations (hence the use of terrorism) as there are no
powerful states directly behind it and they disseminate information
about its activities all over the world, which does not rely only on
official mass-media, it also uses of effectively Internet (Hammes &amp;amp; T.,
July-August 2006).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Analogous to, strategic asymmetry in modern counterinsurgency (CI) and
modern insurgency (I) are respectful goals. Like, (CI) victory means
building up a stable state less than (I) getting rid of victorious
state/coalition. As to win, (CI) needs “hearts and minds” of the
majority of population, rather than (I) needs support of sufficient part
of population. For instance, (CI) must deal successfully with tactical
military activities to provide security, where (I) need to be successful
only to a certain extent – inflicted casualties attack the will of
(CI’s) strategic leadership. More (CI) must win, less (I) must
persuade(CI) that winning is impossible. Due to winning state building
takes time, whereas persuading could happen fast.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, evolution of insurgency in the information age is into
persuasion/communication campaign which naturally increased resort to
terrorism and relying on external support of non-state actors. Opposite
to strategic victory of counterinsurgent arises from series of tactical
victories and a state build-up, whereas only one tactical victory of
insurgent might in the worst case lead to a strategic victory –
withdrawal of the coalition.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, we can see seven different species of information warfare:
command and control warfare, C2W (or C4I – command, control,
communications, computers, and intelligence (Joint Publication 1-02, 8
November 2010)); intelligence-based warfare, IBW; electronic warfare,
EW; psychological warfare, PSYOP; hacker warfare, HW; economical
information warfare, ECOIW and netwar / cyberwar (Lubicki, 3 August
1995). Therefore, different types of IW, first add the power of
conventional warfare, which create new means of victory and defeat.
Next, more important are possibilities to change the entity of warfare
in a way that tanks, airplanes and HF -radios changed the warfare
between the world wars. Today the best aspect of IW is the American
doctrine in military adaptation and Information Operations (IO)
(Ahvenainen, January 2000), which is going to be discussed in the
following lines, comparing with view aspects of IW in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different countries, different approaches in process of implementation
of IW, US, China and Russia, are intense examples. First US views in IO
are to complementing traditional military means and allowing influencing
enemy decision-making. More or less, Chinese views in IW are tool to
compensate for their military inferiority and accelerate their economic
development, which could enable the country to expert control over many
developments in the world. Then US has series of offensive IO’s, but has
been in trouble in accommodating to modern information society where the
enemy can attack directly the will of state national leadership.
Opposite, Chinese military in IW are focused on the person of enemy
commander and strives to alter his decisions and perceptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, US strength in the IO fields is in its technical
capabilities and weakness in seeking excessive control and understanding
various cultures and capabilities to include EW , CNO and tradition
PSYOPS, MILDEC , OPSEC . Where Chinese are attempting to mobilize its
population in accordance with the concept of people’s war in
capabilities in development in CNA, especially CNR , CND, which bring
worries of the danger of globalization (Pufeng, Spring 1995), (Anderson,
The first edition 2001), (Bowdish, December1998 – February 1999).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nerveless, the IW for Soviet Union and subsequently to Russia its means
ranging from controlling own society to demoralizing the enemy,
gathering intelligence and attacking the enemy through CNO. There taking
step further, where we had dealing with enemy with technology in US and
thinking in China, Russia is trying to manipulate the biological parts
of the enemy dealing with information (Liaropoulos, 2007).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, the information age is creating or will create new means of
influence and new ends to influence. This process will create new means
of victory, new troops and added complexity. It is important, that these
new things will add new possibilities between war and peace and it will
increase possibilities to act before war and to avoid conventional
warfare (Ahvenainen, January 2000).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, to achieve victory in information warfare, the central issue is
the control of information. Such as, Chinese approaches to use old
tactics and strategies to win victory in information warfare and Russia
is educating talented people and facilities to produce high quality
cyber warriors for state, private business and crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Reference&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahvenainen, S. (January 2000). ABOUT INFORMATION WARFARE. Finland:
Finnish Defence Forces, Lt.Col (Ret.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anderson, R. (The first edition 2001). Chapter16: Electronic and
Information Warfare. In R. Anderson, Security Engineering (p.
Chapter16). Cambridge: University of Camrbidge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Apr-Jun 1999). Journal of the Signapore armed forces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bowdish, R. G. (December1998 – February 1999). Information-Age
Psychological Operations. USA: US Navy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cronin, A., &amp;amp; James , M. (2004). Four Waves of Modern Terrorism.
Washington DC: Georgetown University Press: Rapoport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DJIM. (Volume 4 – Spring 2009). Information Warfare — Doing Battle in
the 21st Century.
&lt;a href="http://djim.management.dal.ca/"&gt;djim.management.dal.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gray, C. S. (April 2002). DEFINING AND ACHIEVING DECISIVE VICTORY. USA:
Strategic Studies Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hammes, C., &amp;amp; T., X. (July-August 2006). Countering Evolved Insurgent
Networks. Military Review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="art of war"></category><category term="cyber crime"></category><category term="cyber war"></category><category term="history"></category><category term="Information"></category><category term="information warfare"></category><category term="network crime"></category><category term="society"></category><category term="warfare"></category></entry></feed>