<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece - Balkan</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/feeds/balkan.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://predragtasevski.com/</id><updated>2017-03-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Cyber Security Challenges for 2018</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2017/03/IT-security-2018-challenges/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-03-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2017-03-27:/posts/2017/03/IT-security-2018-challenges/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cold March and cold Struga, I had an opportunity to present a talk at Second Regional Internet Freedom Summit, organized by American Bar Association Rule of Law Initiative's (ABA ROLI'S) on a topic: Development and Enhancement of Legal Frameworks in Eastern Europe and Eurasia to Protect Internet Freedom Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyber …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cold March and cold Struga, I had an opportunity to present a talk at Second Regional Internet Freedom Summit, organized by American Bar Association Rule of Law Initiative's (ABA ROLI'S) on a topic: Development and Enhancement of Legal Frameworks in Eastern Europe and Eurasia to Protect Internet Freedom Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyber Security Challenges for 2018 in order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyber crime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ransomware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Critical Infrastructure/Critical Information Infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crypto currencies and blockchain exploits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IoT vulnerabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GDPR and privacy implementation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fake News&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyber Espionage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk was about Cybersecurity Challenges for 2018. Please see below presentation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/viewer?srcid=10T9PlD2CX0u7yg8mUarSneDV8PAtVQBe&amp;pid=explorer&amp;efh=false&amp;a=v&amp;chrome=false&amp;embedded=true" width="580px" height="480px"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or here is the link &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/10T9PlD2CX0u7yg8mUarSneDV8PAtVQBe/view?usp=sharing"&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="IT security"></category><category term="prediction"></category><category term="interview"></category><category term="ransomware"></category><category term="data breaches"></category><category term="botnet"></category><category term="awareness"></category><category term="privacy"></category><category term="encryption"></category><category term="predictions"></category><category term="challenges"></category><category term="Balkan"></category></entry><entry><title>Cyber Culture by Franco "Bifo" Berardi - Belgrade</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2015/12/bifo-digital-devide/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-06T18:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-12-06T18:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2015-12-06:/posts/2015/12/bifo-digital-devide/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Early December usually in Belgrade is cold and freezing, however this time it was not so cold and frankly speaking don't know is it because the city was crowded with police forces in every corner due to the 22nd OSCE Ministerial Summit, or it was just a good luck. Additionally …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Early December usually in Belgrade is cold and freezing, however this time it was not so cold and frankly speaking don't know is it because the city was crowded with police forces in every corner due to the 22nd OSCE Ministerial Summit, or it was just a good luck. Additionally, what made the December special month for Belgrade is that the Philosophical Theater (Drama) hosted the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Franco_Berardi"&gt;Franco “Bifo” Berardi&lt;/a&gt; on 1th December at &lt;a href="http://www.narodnopozoriste.rs/en/--not-5169-9255-1299-2308"&gt;National Theatre in Belgrade&lt;/a&gt;. I was invited by a friend of mine to attend the discussion with one of the most known philosopher from Italy, and indeed I enjoyed a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bifo - Belgrade" src="https://scontent-frt3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xfp1/v/t1.0-9/12346300_10153864400614575_6689430077986305516_n.jpg?oh=b44028c36e0f36a4769ca692d7d730a9&amp;amp;oe=56EB8EE9"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I will try to highlight only the discussion in the field of cyber culture and digital divide that was reflected, and not going too much in details about the philosophy and so on. The discussion began within the reading notes from the “&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/After-Future-Franco-Bifo-Berardi/dp/1849350590"&gt;After the Future&lt;/a&gt;” book where Bifo reflected on the cyber culture by putting the emphasis that we must stop working due to the fact that  we have been working for the past 300-3000 years. In the background there was a song from &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Tgcc5V9Hu3g"&gt;David Bowie – Heroes&lt;/a&gt; which made the discussion much fruitful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, Bifo also share an example of well-known social networking platform Twitter where the main and initial idea was to be an activist platform, rather what is now, and in the end soon was taken over from a big venture capitalist. In some view I might conclude that Bifo it might be a technophobe who is afraid of new technologies, however in the end he is positive and optimistic man. Furthermore, he talked a bit about the Julian Assange and Edward Snowden example, as well of hacktivist &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aaron_Swartz"&gt;Aaron Swartz&lt;/a&gt;. Then, he noted the symptom of hard side of advertising and how to make conspicuous and distinguishing the distances between body versus voice, as Thom Yorke has expressed his vision of a society, where people are increasingly more obsessed with pointless technology, selfishness and mindless entertainment than life itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="National Theatre in Belgrade" src="https://scontent-frt3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xfl1/v/t1.0-9/12341197_10153847782034575_2115013709091603844_n.jpg?oh=0e889d9f582e5beca4fbabc44fd77731&amp;amp;oe=56E5ECA2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something what made me curious is his view of terrorism and terrorists attacks today, where he mentioned that they are not due to the fact of killing someone or have something regarding religion, but in fact the main goal is to kill themselves. Questions were fruitful and he gave indeed philosophical answers, such as &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zenitism"&gt;Zenitism&lt;/a&gt; as an art movement in Yugoslavia. Further than about UN or different organization what is his view where he noted that the problem between society and politics are in fact relations, where male politicians governs the females – emphasizing that democracy is dead even after the elections or so on. Another question was about view of artificial intelligence how does he see it as a threat or killing the modern capitalism and he shared a positive view by highlighting that the world is smart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, after two hours and a half discussion, it was a pleasure to be there and see different views of cyber culture and digital divide opinions. Definitely it made me to over think my thoughts for sure, and at the same time to have a different opinion and to change my view of technology. However, I'm not sure yet what it is? Therefore, I will continue to search for the right answer and draw a map between security and privacy, which unfortunately in end was not discussed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Balkan"></category><category term="digital devide"></category><category term="IoT"></category><category term="philosophy"></category><category term="Bifo"></category><category term="Franco Berardi"></category><category term="hacktivist"></category><category term="cyber"></category><category term="future"></category><category term="artificial intelligence"></category><category term="zenitism"></category><category term="policy"></category><category term="security"></category></entry><entry><title>Secrets for eavesdropping - respublica.edu.mk</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2015/10/eavesdropping-secrets/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-19T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-10-19T18:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2015-10-19:/posts/2015/10/eavesdropping-secrets/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In September I have joined the academic team for writing a blog about public interest topics and actual situation in Macedonia - &lt;a href="http://respublica.edu.mk/" title="Respublica Academic Blog"&gt;ResPublica&lt;/a&gt;. My particular role is writing about policy and security concerns in IT and activists point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, for October release I've published an blog about the wiretapping …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In September I have joined the academic team for writing a blog about public interest topics and actual situation in Macedonia - &lt;a href="http://respublica.edu.mk/" title="Respublica Academic Blog"&gt;ResPublica&lt;/a&gt;. My particular role is writing about policy and security concerns in IT and activists point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, for October release I've published an blog about the wiretapping scandals in Macedonia, Balkans and elsewhere. Such topic is very attractive due to the wiretapping release of recording (i.e. bombs) from the opposition party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless, following post is written in Macedonian language and it is available at &lt;a href="http://respublica.edu.mk/blog/2015-10-19-08-05-42" title="Respublica - Тајните за прислушкувањето"&gt;Тајните за прислушкувањето&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://faktor.mk/2015/10/20/tajnite-za-prislushkuvaneto/"&gt;Фактор&lt;/a&gt;, where English version translated with google translator is &lt;a href="https://translate.google.com/translate?hl=en&amp;amp;sl=mk&amp;amp;tl=en&amp;amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Frespublica.edu.mk%2Fblog%2F2015-10-19-08-05-42" title="Respublica - Secrets for eavesdropping"&gt;Secrets for eavesdropping&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally live TV interview on TOP Tema at Telma TV in Macedonian language discussion about wiretapping scandal in Macedonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/759ofTnyIeg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="surveillance"></category><category term="wiretapping"></category><category term="eavesdropping"></category><category term="mobile"></category><category term="phone"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="privacy"></category><category term="censorship"></category><category term="freedom"></category><category term="public interests"></category><category term="Balkan"></category></entry><entry><title>Balkans capacity towards cyber defense</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2015/09/yata-comments-of-the-week/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-27T13:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-09-27T13:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2015-09-27:/posts/2015/09/yata-comments-of-the-week/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following texts is captured interview for YATA Comments of the week video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LAfOPIBoj8Q" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Predrag Tasevski and I’m an independent cyber security researcher from Macedonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we talk about Balkan region it is actually neither one step further nor one step backwards regarding cyber threats and cyber security …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following texts is captured interview for YATA Comments of the week video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LAfOPIBoj8Q" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Predrag Tasevski and I’m an independent cyber security researcher from Macedonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we talk about Balkan region it is actually neither one step further nor one step backwards regarding cyber threats and cyber security. And at the same time progression of ICT is improving the  connectivity and its utilities from the rest of the world. For this reason discussing about cyber defense and security capacity in the region is in fact crucial and important topic.
However before we continue we have to understand the difference between IT security and cyber security. IT security is to protect business and individual assets, whereas cyber security it involved IT security as well as national, state security and security of Critical Information Infrastructure point of view.
To be able to have safer cyber space, we need to take an actions. Such as, ratifying conventions for instance Budapest Convention, moreover, adapting legal framework with international and of course social society needs. Than pursue establishment of National Bodies that will deal with occurrence and the frequency of cyberspace attacks and threats. And last but not least, develop national cyber security strategy. Among the mentioned actions, also important is to take into consideration the general approaches, as multi stakeholders and multi-level approach.
Cyberspace could not be 100% secured, therefore each country should introduce national cyber security culture and at the same time raising the awareness level to the weakest link in cyber security - that is the human behaviors.
Moreover, when we discuss about the cyber security and defense another important questions should be raised, by providing of course and answers:
Who? determines the target of who you are planning to secure.
What? determines the content of what to secure.
How? is the means by how you are going to secure it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turning back to Balkan vision toward cyber defense and security, we might say that several countries a much further progressing, such as Slovenia, Croatia, Albania, Montenegro and Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina, in contrast to slowly progressing countries: Macedonia, Serbia and etc.
Nevertheless, the region has taken under the umbrella and understood the importance of such topics and for this reason are taking hence actions. Such actions are as we mentioned previously making their legal framework compliance with the international perspectives. And establishing national bodies to react and countermeasure the incident occurred in cyberspace. And finally establishing national cyber security strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the end I would like to provide recommendation actions that could help other countries in pursuing and capacity building towards cyber defense and security.
Such as:
1. Understand cyber defense from a global perspective, don't feel nervous and foolish when it comes to the word “Cyber”. Use common and simple language that everyone could understand it.
2. Define and implement a national cyber security/defence strategy, followed by cyber security frameworks by supporting it initiatives and international cooperation.
3. Develop public awareness, cyber security culture and education that will touch entire population needs.
4. Improve resilience against cyber terrorism, cyber espionage, hybrid war and cyber warfare by sharing knowledge, documents, continues education and training, military and non-military capabilities.
5. Enforcing ICT infrastructures security in order to obtain confidence and security in the use of ICT. By investing in research and development.
6. And finally, continuance of public meetings and networking are in fact needed and essential on yearly basis for secure cyber space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The first step toward encouraging security and defence is awareness, followed by the implementation, acceptance and so forth”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="balkan"></category><category term="awareness"></category><category term="cyber defense"></category><category term="YATA"></category><category term="video"></category><category term="interview"></category><category term="Macedonia"></category><category term="ICT"></category><category term="strategy"></category></entry><entry><title>Collective Cyber Defence – The Role of Newer Members and Opportunities for Specialization of Bulgaria in the Alliance Questions and answers</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/03/collective-cyber-defence-the-role-of-newer-members-and-opportunities-for-specialization-of-bulgaria-in-the-alliance-questions-and-answers/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2013-03-12:/posts/2013/03/collective-cyber-defence-the-role-of-newer-members-and-opportunities-for-specialization-of-bulgaria-in-the-alliance-questions-and-answers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;November is a month of &lt;a href="http://www.paneuropa.bg/en/news/38/PanEuropa-Bulgaria-organizes-international-conference-with-the-special-support-of-NATO" title="PanEuropa Bulgaria organizes international conference with the special support of NATO"&gt;Smart Defense and Open – Door Policy – New
Synergies for Euro –Atlantic
Security&lt;/a&gt;.
Not only in Europe, but also in South-East European region as well. The
following international event was organized
by &lt;a href="http://www.paneuropa.bg/" title="PanEuropa Bulgaria"&gt;PanEuropa Bulgaria&lt;/a&gt; and
it was supported by NATO. Furthermore, I was invited to take …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;November is a month of &lt;a href="http://www.paneuropa.bg/en/news/38/PanEuropa-Bulgaria-organizes-international-conference-with-the-special-support-of-NATO" title="PanEuropa Bulgaria organizes international conference with the special support of NATO"&gt;Smart Defense and Open – Door Policy – New
Synergies for Euro –Atlantic
Security&lt;/a&gt;.
Not only in Europe, but also in South-East European region as well. The
following international event was organized
by &lt;a href="http://www.paneuropa.bg/" title="PanEuropa Bulgaria"&gt;PanEuropa Bulgaria&lt;/a&gt; and
it was supported by NATO. Furthermore, I was invited to take a
participation as a speaker on the panel discussion Collective Cyber
Defence – The Role of Newer Members and Opportunities for Specialization
of Bulgaria in the Alliance Questions and answers. In details, the event
main points ware to highlight the need for specialization of each member
state in terms of the principles of Smart Defense and the joint
participation in future military operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the event had splendid video addressing in the opening session
of Neelie Kroes, the Vice – President of European Commission.
Emphasizing the current online spying crisis as well as the importance
of cyber security strategy. In additional, she highlighted the
importance of new legal threats, information norms coupled to boost the
trust among the Europe. As well as, that the weakest link in the chain
should be able to raise and boost the awareness, coupled with the future
investments in research and innovations, and projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding the collective cyber defense panel discussion, I was delighted
to be speaker with such strong extensive and experienced experts from
different fields. Such as private, public, academy and business sectors.
Speaking of which, the moderator of the panel was Prof. Veselin Tselkov,
D. Sc., Member of the Board, Commission for Personal Data Protection in
Bulgaria. The lectures where: unfortunately Col. Associate Prof. Dr.
Stoyan Balabanov, Director, Institute for Defense, Ministry of Defense
Bulgaria, was not able to attend the panel, however we had
representative from MoD. Also from Bulgaria was Zlatogor Minchev from
Institute of Information and Communication Technologies, Bulgaria. From
Macedonian was Dr. Metodi Hadji-Janev (LtC), Assistant Prof., Military
Academy ” General Mihailo Apostolski”, Skopje, Macedonia. From business
prospective I was the presenter of
&lt;a href="http://cybersecurity.mk" title="CyberSecurity.mk"&gt;CyberSecurity.mk&lt;/a&gt; copmany,
based in Macedonia. In addition, Mr. Robert Griffin, Director Business
Development – Security Systems, RSA. From all the above, we also had
video addressing from Mr. Detlef Puhl, Senior Advisor at the Emerging
Security Challenges Division, NATO Headquarters, and Mr. Philippe
Roggeband, Security Sales Business Development Manager, EBG EMEAR, Cisco
Systems. However, due to the security measures in the building where the
event was held the video addressing was interrupted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, here is my short presentation notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyberspace has become one of the most essential and distinguished
bridge between government and their inhabitants. Thus, the people are
able to get access to government services 24/7, as well as their life
becomes more easier. However, all in this has led to advance of
producing cyberspace to be vulnerable, coupled with information’s that
should not be available to others. For this reason I would like to
share three important points that are fundamental to emphasis when we
discuss about the Cyber defense in general. First, we have to
understand and highlight the difference between Cyber Security vs IT
Security. Second, it is the important to boost the awareness level
tailored to national level, social society, private sector and indeed
multistakeholder cooperation in the region. Last but not least, we
have to brake the lack of communications between the neighboring
countries and to create a trusted, same level, and collaboration of
cyber security. Where national agencies and parties should work
together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, first the main goal of IT security is to protect
information from a wide range of threats in order to ensure business
continuity, reduce business damages and maximize return on investments
and business opportunity. Likewise the cyber security is protecting
Information and Communication Technologies (ICT) systems and Critical
Infrastructure (CI). However the most important protection element in
IT security is to reduce business risk to accepted levels and the
protection of entire information and information systems essential to
the organizations. Alternatively, cyber security aims at assuring
critical IT service for CI and CII on accepted levels, in addition to
the protection of critical information. In other words the security
objective determiner in information security is an organization’s
business process, while in cyber security it is for the entire state.
Emphasizing that states may have different or complementary interests
compared to an organization’s business interests. On one hand,
handling cyber security problems is considered to be both a nationally
and internationally coordinated activity to protect national CII.
Similarly, to information security goals: confidentiality,
availability and integrity, in cyber security the additional goals are
non-repudiation, authentication, information systems importance and
criticality from the standpoint of state CII/CI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning to awareness, I would like to share my recent research that
have been published as book, title: Interactive Cyber Security
Awareness Program. It is highlighting the method, approach and the
importance of current awareness level in Western Balkans. Coupled how
to boost the awareness on the national level. I would not like to go
in details, however, just want to mention that the positive results
were presented, and that the awareness level among the end users are
varied. Moreover, in particular we have to create and recognize the
importance of establishing cyber security awareness strategy, coupled
with influence of the weakest link in cyber security, which is the
human factor, or in other words, social-technical aspects. In spite of
our investment in technologies and in the applications, still the
weakest link in cyber defense and security will the human behavior.
Therefore, we will have to conceive an awareness/education to raise
the awareness on the national behalf, such as, from the young to the
oldest generation, tailored through social society, private sector and
multistakeholder cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, in recent years we are witnesses of acts that have taken into
place between neighboring countries in the region. Such acts were
followed by different motivations of attacks. Where mostly they were
done through defacement’s or denial-of-service attacks. Thus,
motivations where divers. Nevertheless, in this last point is I would
like to stress the importance of merging the best practices learned
from past event occurrence as well as to improve the role of newer
members and opportunities into the collective roles of cyber defence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, I am keen that after this discussion/panel will lead into
further actions. And also thanks to the organizers for the invitation
and done a good job in organizing such an important event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Pictures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="375"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157646785203333%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157646785203333%2F&amp;set_id=72157646785203333&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157646785203333%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157646785203333%2F&amp;set_id=72157646785203333&amp;jump_to=" width="500" height="375"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="cyber defence"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="bulgaria"></category><category term="balkan"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="nato"></category></entry><entry><title>Cyber Security Group in South Eastern Europe</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/01/cyber-security-group-in-south-eastern-europe/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-01-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-01-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2013-01-03:/posts/2013/01/cyber-security-group-in-south-eastern-europe/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently we have heard and read about the importance of cybersecurity
around the
&lt;a href="http://www.csmonitor.com/USA/Politics/2013/0213/Why-Obama-s-executive-order-on-cybersecurity-doesn-t-satisfy-most-experts"&gt;US&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a href="http://ec.europa.eu/digital-agenda/en/news/eu-cybersecurity-plan-protect-open-internet-and-online-freedom-and-opportunity-cyber-security"&gt;EU&lt;/a&gt;.
Firstly Obama administration get order intended to bolster
cybersecurity, where the move comes after the White House tried, and
indeed failed to get tough cybersecurity legislation through Congresses
last year. Secondly, EU released the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently we have heard and read about the importance of cybersecurity
around the
&lt;a href="http://www.csmonitor.com/USA/Politics/2013/0213/Why-Obama-s-executive-order-on-cybersecurity-doesn-t-satisfy-most-experts"&gt;US&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a href="http://ec.europa.eu/digital-agenda/en/news/eu-cybersecurity-plan-protect-open-internet-and-online-freedom-and-opportunity-cyber-security"&gt;EU&lt;/a&gt;.
Firstly Obama administration get order intended to bolster
cybersecurity, where the move comes after the White House tried, and
indeed failed to get tough cybersecurity legislation through Congresses
last year. Secondly, EU released the cybersecurity plan to protect open
Internet and online freedom and opportunity – Cyber Security strategy
and Proposal for a Directive. Frankly, where are the countries of South
Eastern Europe (SEE) in here, such as the ones that are not in EU, for
instance: Macedonia, Serbia, Montenegro, Bosnia, Albania and Kosovo?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, my plan, as a founder of
&lt;a href="http://cybersecurity.mk"&gt;Cybersecurity.mk&lt;/a&gt; would like to make a
proposal of creating and teaming a group which will meet once a month to
talk over another the importance of such as beneficial and in fact
essential cybersecurity issues, as well as to exchange knowledge.
Sharing is caring. Additionally, in every meeting we will merge and
invite important people either over the remote or in the place speakers
to give, share and offer us a knowledge what we should do in a near
future. How we could fix and raise not only the awareness, but also the
importance of cybersecurity in South Eastern Europe (Macedonia, Serbia,
Montenegro, Bosnia, Albania, Kosovo, Croatia, Slovenia, Bulgaria,
Romania and Greece).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this proposal to be success we would need a help from NGO’s, NPO’s
and any other institutes from the region and elsewhere. In addition I
would like to ask hackers, crackers, ethical and non-ethical, designers,
freelancers and many other to help us with the following problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Name of the group. I will be more than happy if you could give as
proposals on the comment section for the name of the group. Let us
contribute together in this matter and we will be all God Fathers for
the group which will help us in improving and boosting awareness level
in cyber and IT security in our region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logo. We would like to hear from any of you to design the logo of
South Eastern Europe – Cyber Security Group. Please feel free to give us
a link of the design in the comment section (below) and then we will
select together the best proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsorship for the speakers to invite them to meet with us in face to
face, either is NGO, NPO, financial, telecommunication, insurance
institutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proposal of speakers, list for the next meetings and place, indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further great ideas or proposals please do not hesitate
to share them with us. We would be more than happy to take them in
consideration. Nevertheless, I really hope that forming the group, such
as Google Developer Group etc. will help on one hand. And on the other
hand, will aid to meet one another, to discuss and share our knowledge.
To learn from the best people and scholars in cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, more frequently in SEE region we have seen targets to attackers
on the Internet. How do we handle this matter of facts and how we deal
against? How we protect our online space? And indeed why we should take
actions? Those are just a start-up questions that everyone of us should
be able to answer them. Therefore, we hope that you all will contributes
in the above problem that we face and will HELP us in creating this
group in SEE region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="NGO"></category><category term="group"></category><category term="south eastern europe"></category><category term="macedonia"></category><category term="balkan"></category></entry></feed>