<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece - conference</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/feeds/conference.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://predragtasevski.com/</id><updated>2014-08-31T23:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Kaspersky – CyberSecurity European Round 2014, Milan, Italy</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2014/08/kaspersky-cybersecurity-european-round-2014-milan-italy/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-08-31T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-08-31T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2014-08-31:/posts/2014/08/kaspersky-cybersecurity-european-round-2014-milan-italy/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Predrag Tasevski, presenting Methodological approach to security
awareness – Kaspersky CyberSecurity Round 2014, Politecnico di Milano,
Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;December was a last month of 2013, and for sure the best month. Not
because of the parties, holidays and vacation that they were coming. But
it is because I was selected in a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Predrag Tasevski, presenting Methodological approach to security
awareness – Kaspersky CyberSecurity Round 2014, Politecnico di Milano,
Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;December was a last month of 2013, and for sure the best month. Not
because of the parties, holidays and vacation that they were coming. But
it is because I was selected in a final round of &lt;a href="http://academy.kaspersky.com/cybersecurity/european-round-2014/"&gt;Kaspersky Academy
European Round
2014&lt;/a&gt;
in Milan, Italy. The conference was a part of &lt;a href="http://academy.kaspersky.com/cybersecurity/"&gt;CyberSecurity for the
Next Generation&lt;/a&gt; events
that are happening all over the world. The event took place in 11 until
13 of December 2013, in beautiful and unfortunate at that time foggy
city Milan, and hosted at Politecnico di Milano. Nevertheless, we had a
wonderful time. Before I continue with the presentation of my research
paper I would like to thanks the organizers for such a great
organization and full and frankly not that busy and indeed interesting
agenda. Nice work guys, love you and of course miss you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning to research paper that I presented, "Methodological approach to
security awareness", the presentation is available below as well as my presentation notes.
Without any further ado I will let the notes to speak for themself, as
well as the presentation and the pictures. Hope that you enjoy the
reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ladies and gentlemen, dear committee, my name is Predrag Tasevski from
Macedonia and currently I’m a post-master student in Eurecom, France.
Today I will present you my research study Methodological approach to
security awareness. But before we start I would like to share a short
story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously I was studying MSc in Cyber security in Estonia. When I was
in the middle of the studies, in the 2011, it was one year after
finished the first year. I went home for the Christmas holidays. At
that time I was curious in opening a company in Macedonia. And for
this reason I went to Central register office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I reached the room number 10 I knocked on the door. Once, two,
three times, and still there was no answer. I push the door and I
entered in empty room full of 6 computers. I shouted few times,
however there was no answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started to watch the screens. Unlikely from Estonia, frankly in
Macedonia people love paper-work. Indeed, in the bureaus there where
open documents and the computer’s ware unlocked. Usually, I always I
have with me an external hard drive…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the good side and bad side of me come out .…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a few minutes to decide,… and likely the good side of me
won. After 30 minutes I was able to get the answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us just stop for a second and thing what I could do with this data
…. Could you imagine how reach I would be nowadays if I backup the
data…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was on the way back home, I started to think why people are so
careless about the information. In reality it just takes one second to
lock the computer. Why people coupled with human factor are actually
the weakest link in security? And therefore for this reason, we
introduce you this study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we will discuss the problem statement and related work. Coupled
with the current awareness level. Secondly, methods and approached
that we have introduced in this study and the curriculum. Last but not
least, we will present the results of the syllabus as a consequence of
the implementation in schools, universities, private and public
organizations. And finally we will conclude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerous amounts of awareness programs exist in the last 20 years.
However their approaches and methods are different. Up to now almost
all the academic effort in information security training has
concentrated on solving the technical and policy aspects, rather than
designing security systems to take into account the human factor. The
human factor is being the most vulnerable threat in the system, and it
could jeopardize the overall efficiency of the organization and
nation. Lastly, few of them have the questionnaire quizzes
implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ideas for the awareness program we have implemented are usually
not new, but the uniqueness of our awareness program lies in the style
of communication, the systematic approach of the targeted groups and
the content delivered. Other unique factors are the baseline survey
and questionnaire quiz, and lastly the topic adviser. We believe that
no other previously related work as mention in this study has used
such systematic approach, methods and targeted groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three systematical target groups in the syllabus: basic,
advance and management. Each part contains certain number of modules,
divided into units, which are pursued into separate curriculum. In
fact the idea of the target groups is to elevate the awareness level
of three different types of groups of information security. We
emphasize that the weakest element is human behavior, followed by the
socio-technical aspect. Please bear in mind, that this syllabus does
not cover the legal aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study provided the entrance for participants only with the Basic
curriculum. The focus is to examine the response of the prior concern
about safety and knowledge of protection of IT assets compared to the
scores earned. In total we had around 1000 participants, from 11 to 63
years old and around 700 of them where male and the rest female. Most
of the them use the computers either at home or work. In the content
of how they want to get education about the IT security is that around
430 answered through Online training. Turning to the current awareness
level before they entered the course is in fact that only 400 of them
were somewhat knowledgeable of how to secure their assets. Also
another interesting fact is that a greater number of the participants
are least concerned about protecting their mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In comparison with the current awareness level we also demonstrate the
average percentage score gained in each unit. Subsequently it allows
us to pin-point modules which participants are more and less
knowledgeable. So as to take tailored measurements for future actions.
For instance Network &amp;amp; Internet Security is the most knowledgeable,
rather than Physical security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the threats to cybersecurity are constantly evolving. Thus we
need to ensure that not only the specialist who are protecting IT
systems get a proper awareness education, but also the basic, everyday
users and managers should too. Every manager can be a user, but every
user can not be a manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thereby, only significant changes in user perception, culture and
education can effectively reduce the number of information and
cybersecurity breaches. Consequently this will raise the awareness
level of the human factor in using technologies in everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The strength of our study lies in the results and evidence of
implemented syllabus and it improve everyday work and usage of
technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe that this approach could be implemented effectively in
private, public, military, nations, etc. without a significant
degradation in performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as future studies should examine broader views on policy and
legal aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I did not win, however let me just remind the others that we
are all winners. There were around 60 papers submitted and only 15 were
selected for finale round. We should be proud of our self. And of course
each one of us did a perfect job in presenting own work. Hope that you
all will continue in this path, as well as to see you soon. Friendship
and networking that we had there is my gift from others and Kaspersky.
Thank you once again. Congrats to the winners. Here is a short note from
Kaspersky about the conference, &lt;a href="http://academy.kaspersky.com/cybersecurity-in-milano/" title="CyberSecurity in Milan - Kaspersky"&gt;CyberSecurity in
Milan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Presentation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/file/d/0B1472nuKPMN5ZjRJeEhKczdQS0E/preview" width="640" height="480"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Pictures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="375"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705166198%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705166198%2F&amp;set_id=72157648705166198&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705166198%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705166198%2F&amp;set_id=72157648705166198&amp;jump_to=" width="500" height="375"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="kaspersky"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="european round"></category><category term="milan"></category><category term="italy"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="research"></category></entry><entry><title>Camp in Plav – Montenegro with Young, Smart and Enthusiast people – REACT 2013 Montenegro</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/12/camp-in-plav-montenegro-with-young-smart-and-enthusiast-people-react-2013-montenegro/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-12-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-12-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2013-12-09:/posts/2013/12/camp-in-plav-montenegro-with-young-smart-and-enthusiast-people-react-2013-montenegro/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m always in big favor when it comes to share, discuss and to spend six
days in camp with young, smart, enthusiast, academical, non-academical,
scholars, military, history critics and politicians in a venue in wild
beauty of Montenegro, near the Plavsko lake in Plav. The location of the
camp …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m always in big favor when it comes to share, discuss and to spend six
days in camp with young, smart, enthusiast, academical, non-academical,
scholars, military, history critics and politicians in a venue in wild
beauty of Montenegro, near the Plavsko lake in Plav. The location of the
camp was in a such a beautiful area. My eyes could not stop looking for
something, such as either it was the top of the mountain, or the Plavsko
lake, or even the green hills and valleys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, let me return to the main point here. Firstly I will like to
share a couple of history background of &lt;a href="http://www.reactmontenegro.me/"&gt;Regional Euro Atlantic Camp
REACT&lt;/a&gt;, organized by &lt;a href="http://www.alfacentar.org/"&gt;ALFA Center
Montenegro&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First REACT camp took place in 2008, since then it takes place every
year, until now six years. The best and intriguing part of this camp is
that each year the venue of the event is in different place, therefore
the participants have a change to meet the beauty of Montenegro. The
idea in behalf of the organizers is very good, and I do support them in
this matter. Sometimes Montenegro routs could be a very heavy for the
drivers, however still this beauty should be exposed to the rest of the
world. Additionally, each year the number of participants varies
depending on the applications. However, this year there where
participants from 25 different countries, which make is in total 75
participants from elsewhere, such as, Balkans countries, Ex-Soviet Union
countries, Hungary, Slovakia, Czech Republic and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning to the
&lt;a href="http://www.reactmontenegro.me/agenda/agenda.html"&gt;agenda&lt;/a&gt; of REACT
2013, it was quite densely deployed, with lectures, panel discussions,
etc. Although it was heavy still the best side was the picnic adventures
and cultural evenings. Please feel free to see the pictures below of the
post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I would like to take a time to concentrate more on the issue
of cyber security. During the event the
&lt;a href="http://www.reactmontenegro.me/agenda/list-of-speakers.html"&gt;speakers&lt;/a&gt;
where representative of governments from sixteen countries, as well as
NGOs, media, students, researchers, among the others. Mostly, the topics
where concentrating on intention to see the pros and cons of join to
NATO, where indeed the countries from this region have in mind. However,
when it comes to the goals of NATO, and new threats, such as cyber
threats, cyber crime coupled with strategies, framework and so on, only
one speaker it emphasized the importance of cyber security as one of the
greatest risk now a day and in future, of course. I will not delay too
much, as you might all unravel it was the USA Deputy Chief of Mission in
Montenegro, Mr. Jones. Mr. Jones was very precise in his speech,
moreover he mentioned the importance of infrastructure as well as the
stability and security in Balkan region. I would like to cite one of the
lectures, Mr. Petric he said “Together we are stronger!”. How the days
go by, I was just wondering and always trying to ask questions about the
cyber security, and the importance of this issue, however, most of the
speakers where no that specialized or somehow not interested of in fact
important unit of integration requirements in NATO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I was a moderator to a topic Kosovo open or close? The
question was which topics, fields are close or open, regarding the
Kosovo as a new country in the region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short summary, please feel free to see the pictures below and I hope
that in future to REACT Camp we will have much more discussions and
panels and topics about the new threats that we are facing. Likewise, I
always say, no matter how much we pour money in infrastructure and
security, still the weakest chain will be the human factor, because it
is not a aware of the importance of cyber security. Consequently, we
will have to keep in mind that this issue and importance of cyber
security is in benefits to wide security, economy and political aspects,
by process of joining and integrating the region to the path of NATO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Pictures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="375"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705121698%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705121698%2F&amp;set_id=72157648705121698&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705121698%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705121698%2F&amp;set_id=72157648705121698&amp;jump_to=" width="500" height="375"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="camp"></category><category term="react"></category><category term="nato"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="montenegro"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="cyberwar"></category><category term="cyber"></category><category term="plav"></category></entry><entry><title>Belgrade Security Forum 2013 – Session 7: Assuring Cyber-Security in the Western Balkans and the Rest of Europe</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/10/belgrade-security-forum-2013-session-7-assuring-cyber-security-in-the-western-balkans-and-the-rest-of-europe/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-09T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2013-10-09T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2013-10-09:/posts/2013/10/belgrade-security-forum-2013-session-7-assuring-cyber-security-in-the-western-balkans-and-the-rest-of-europe/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I have received the invitation letter from
administration of Belgrade Security Forum, within goal of inviting me to
be a speaker in one of the break out sessions. In particular the session
topic is: &lt;strong&gt;Assuring Cyber-Security in the Western Balkans and the Rest
of Europe.&lt;/strong&gt; And …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I have received the invitation letter from
administration of Belgrade Security Forum, within goal of inviting me to
be a speaker in one of the break out sessions. In particular the session
topic is: &lt;strong&gt;Assuring Cyber-Security in the Western Balkans and the Rest
of Europe.&lt;/strong&gt; And of course, I have accepted the invitation. Speak of
which, the &lt;em&gt;Belgrade Security Forum&lt;/em&gt; has been in past few years. This –
2013 year was the third in the row event. And with it, we have continue
the talk from the previous year session about cyber security: &lt;a href="http://2012.belgradeforum.org/agenda/session3.html%20&amp;amp;quot;Belgrade%20Security%20Forum%202012"&gt;Cyber War
and Cyber Crime: Responding to the Governance
Challenges&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning to this year session, we had a very good chance to boost the
enthusiasm from other panel discussion where chairman – Richard Thomson
called me in between the discussion of Helsinki Plus 40: Strengthening
the Security Community to Meet Current Security Challenges. Where he
raise the issue of what and if it is possible with one click that
someone could stop the energy, power supply or even telecommunication
systems. And, my answer was very straightforward, indeed it is! This was
a very good spur of inspiration of our breakout session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together with other speaker we came to conclusion that the best way to
go ahead and to have an effective discussion is to open the most
important questions relating to cyber security: &lt;strong&gt;Who? What? and How?&lt;/strong&gt;
But before further to the answers the above question, I would like also
to mention that the speakers where kind of divided, in a good sense
where we came from different regions as well as specialized fields in
cyber security. In details, &lt;strong&gt;Baroness Pauline Neville-Jones&lt;/strong&gt; was in
related fields in government issues and challenges in cyber security.
Where on other hand, I was a representative from the Wester Balkan
region representative. Furthermore, &lt;strong&gt;Alexander Klimburg&lt;/strong&gt; was more
concentrating of different stakeholder, in other words multi
stakeholders approach. Where last but not least, &lt;strong&gt;Jovan Kurbalija&lt;/strong&gt; was
in diplomacy, civil society and information technology. And finally, the
moderator of the session was &lt;strong&gt;Vladimir Radunović&lt;/strong&gt;, who manage to
create a nice vibe between the speakers and the audience from the
beginning until the end of the session. For more details of the session
please follow the Breakout session report: &lt;a href="http://belgradeforum.org/info/news/459/Session+7%3A+Assuring+Cyber-Security+in+the+Western+Balkans+and+the+Rest+of+Europe.html" title="Session 7: Assuring Cyber-Security in the Western Balkans and the Rest of Europe"&gt;Session 7: Assuring
Cyber-Security in the Western Balkans and the Rest of
Europe&lt;/a&gt;.
For more information of the issues that we follow and given answers are
available on the
&lt;a href="http://www.belgradeforum.org/agenda/sesija5.html" title="Agenda"&gt;Agenda&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From left to right: Vladimir Radunović, Predrag Tasevski, Jovan
Kurbalija, Alexander Klimburg and Baroness Pauline Neville-Jones&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also I would like to make some quick notes on the main cyber threats and
possible effects that are linked to Western Balkan region. The most
known and presented cyber threats are among the cybercrime. For instance
in one hand are: employee fraud, minor and child pornography; using of
mobile telephones and smartphones as tools to commit other crime;
identity theft and credit card fraud. Where on the other hand are among
the political, moral, ethical and other motivation reasons. Such as,
web-based attacks, mostly committed by defacement or denial-of-service
attacks. Then we have phising and spoofing social networking sites.
Where the possible effects are for instance for individuals loss of
money, and of course political or ethical doctrine. Moreover, awareness
of roles and responsibilities of different actors, such as government,
regulators, industry and civil society of risk are taken into
consideration only the implementation of law. For instance, data
protection law and so on. Turning to the industry and civil society is
almost the same, although some of them are implementing the very known
standards, such as ISO 27001 and so on. However, is this enough? The
roles and responsibilities are only described in the data protection law
and criminal law. Unfortunately, it is not carried out by the framework
or even a strategy. Likelihood, awareness level in Western Balkans
presented by my paper back book that I have conducted last year,
&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Interactive-Cyber-Security-Awareness-Program/dp/3659207985/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;amp;qid=1367779682&amp;amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;amp;keywords=Interactive+Cyber+Security+Awareness+Program" title="Interactive Cyber Security Awareness Program"&gt;Interactive Cyber Security Awareness Program Cyber Security Awareness
Program&lt;/a&gt;.
This book outlines the survey done around 1000 participants, from 11 to
63 years old. In diversity of carries, such as schools, universities,
private and public organizations. In total we had 35% people using
computers/internet from home and 26% from office. In particular and most
interesting figures for us are results about the knowledge of protecting
their IT assets, and in details: 16% are very knowledgeable, least
knowledgeable are 13% and last but not least somewhat knowledgeable are
40%. Therefore from the results presented we can see that awareness
level among the end users is vary. Coming to the end, if we want to make
sure the involvement of end users in raising trust and securing the
cyberspace we firstly have to start from strategy, than legal framework,
followed by implementation, and so on. However, when it comes to step to
get done by governments should be as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop and create strategy framework for Cyber-security, in
    particular, not to cover the area only of cyber crime, but also how
    to mitigate happened incidents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rewrite and review the cyber crime law and data protection law.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create NGO or NPO that will deal not only for a concrete country but
    of course the entire region, as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end I have noted that some countries in Wester Balkans do not
have &lt;strong&gt;yet&lt;/strong&gt; either, CERT – Critical Emergency Response Team nor CIRT –
Critical Incident Response Team. Therefore, this action should be taken
as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, hope that the above notes will take effect, as well as will
raise the awareness of the important in fact issue. Therefore we have to
be simple and follow just simple three steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strategical plan which will aim in business continuity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partnership between Groups, such as government, private and civil.
    As well as to provide awareness on the share bases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education the public, where we need to take an action of
    re-informing the school materials, and to provide the young
    generations guide of how to protect in cyber space and skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to the participant, speakers, guest, organizers and everyone
for such a lovely stay in Belgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Pictures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="375"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648695812727%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648695812727%2F&amp;set_id=72157648695812727&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648695812727%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648695812727%2F&amp;set_id=72157648695812727&amp;jump_to=" width="500" height="375"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="conference"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="balkans"></category><category term="western"></category><category term="assurance"></category><category term="europe"></category></entry><entry><title>Stockholm Internet Forum 2013</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/06/stockholm-internet-forum-2013/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-06-05T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2013-06-05T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2013-06-05:/posts/2013/06/stockholm-internet-forum-2013/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year the Stockholm Internet Forum 2013 was addressing the freedom
of Internet, human rights, freedom of speech, censorship, privacy as
well as importance of security. Among the topics, also we have touched
the cyber security, surveillance, importance of information security
coupled with critical information infrastructure and critical
infrastructure. Once …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year the Stockholm Internet Forum 2013 was addressing the freedom
of Internet, human rights, freedom of speech, censorship, privacy as
well as importance of security. Among the topics, also we have touched
the cyber security, surveillance, importance of information security
coupled with critical information infrastructure and critical
infrastructure. Once Alex Levin has said – “The reason there is so
little crime in Germany is that it’s against the law.” – What a hack he
was talking? Was he right or wrong? For this reason, the SIF was held
this year with more than 94 different countries participants, from all
over the world. And indeed, it was one of the best conference organized
so far. Nevertheless the number of differential participants let the
talks and the conference topics just to flow. Even that the four days of
talking was not enough. However, this was just a start, or for someone
the beginning of an idea due to the poverty of our thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opening speech was by Carl Bildt where he presented in fact an
importance of digital revolution, African development through
connectivity, political debates for freedom of Internet. In addition, he
gave a couple of great examples, such as legislations of blocking sites
in Russia, violations of human rights in Syria, Vietnam among the
others. Also, he noted the security importance of cyber security, where
security should be thought but of course should not be used in purpose
to limit the human rights. One very good quote, even after two weeks
from the conference I still have it in my head, is &lt;strong&gt;*“Free societies
are strong societies”&lt;/strong&gt;. Last but not least, was that we should take an
examples from the leading nations of ICT, such as, Sweden, where the
security coupled with human rights are presented on Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frankly, in the opening session we have touched the issue with
surveillance and software used for this purpose, coupled with the
viability of digital divide popular in Africa and among others.
Moreover, we have purse the issue of Internet jurisdiction projects, as
well as that we have to boost the awareness of regulations united with
the important factor to increased the civil societies in freedom. For
more info please visit the summaries notes from the session, &lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/opening-session/" title="Opening session"&gt;Opening
session&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To continue with the first session again we have to come back some
example of the above issue, surveillance, where Mexico has
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Closed-circuit_television" title="Closed-circuit television - Wikipedia"&gt;CCTV&lt;/a&gt;
in private sector for 3 to 4 years. Among the surveillance we have
discuss the issue during the riots in London, Syria and Panama as a
recent examples where they have shutdown the mobile phone network.
Additionally, point in some countries is that people do trust the law
enforcement in privacy, where opposite such as in Pakistan they trust
only the companies, and not law enforcement agencies. Moreover, hate
speech, digital freedom and democracy of freedom was carried out, along
with how the law works on Internet with civil societies and that the
police need to do their own job. Nevertheless, the note was that
vocabulary of cyber security is missing, and it should become a national
security and of course the security is a huge problem. This problem is
done due to the lack of new laws, by definition of what we mean by a
single law treaty. Whom we should secure? What should be asked? In
sentence of security importance, civil society. We really need a cyber
security strategy, by introducing the legislation and laws throughout
experience. In spite of vocabulary e should define and terms, such as,
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hacktivism" title="Hacktivism - Wiki"&gt;hacktivism&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cyberterrorism" title="Cyberterrorism - Wiki"&gt;cyberterrorism&lt;/a&gt;.
One important note was mentioned that we do not want global cyber
security law. For more info of the session please visit the following
link &lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/session-1/informal-summary/" title="Session 1: Reconciling freedom and security in cyberspace"&gt;Reconciling freedom and security in
cyberspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned above the frustration was between the west and
developing countries in sentence of digital divide. Also one note was
that Sweden people trust to the government agencies, as well as that
e-voting system in Sweden will help ICT to boost. The session where
split into three parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/session-1a/informal-summary-of-session-1a/" title="1A Global security and human rights in the internet age"&gt;1A Global security and human rights in the internet
    age&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/session-1b/informal-summary/" title="1B Distributed security in a national context"&gt;1B Distributed security in a national
    context&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/session-1c/informal-summary/" title="1C Free and secure communication in a multinational context"&gt;1C Free and secure communication in a multinational
    context&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next day, the second day of the forum (SIF13) we have touched a facts
about the free and open Internet and open communications. The second day
I will remember forever for speech of the famous Cuban blogger Yoani
Sánchez, which said very good quote “Cuba Internet on Internet” or
another one is that if your relatives or you personally travel to Cuba
bring the old and unused gadgets with you and leave them in Cuba or just
give them, rather than you should just dispose them or throw them into
the trash. For more info please visit the &lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/summaries-2013/" title="Summaries 2013 | Stockholm Internet Forum"&gt;Summaries 2013
page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I might say that the SIF 13 was very successful, as well
as very important questions and topics were discussed. However, we
should concentrate for the next year forum on more specific topics,
either freedom or only a security. It is very difficult when we speak
about freedom coupled with security. Does two topics are very linked and
fragile. In the end, I would like to thank a lot to the organizers,
&lt;a href="https://www.iis.se/" title=".SE"&gt;.SE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.government.se/sb/d/2059" title="Ministry for Foreign Affairs - Sweden"&gt;Ministry for Foreign Affairs –
Sweden&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href="http://www.sida.se/Svenska/" title="SIDA"&gt;SIDA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Pictures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="375"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648696553859%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648696553859%2F&amp;set_id=72157648696553859&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648696553859%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648696553859%2F&amp;set_id=72157648696553859&amp;jump_to=" width="500" height="375"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="internet"></category><category term="forum"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="stockholm"></category><category term="freedom"></category></entry><entry><title>Collective Cyber Defence – The Role of Newer Members and Opportunities for Specialization of Bulgaria in the Alliance Questions and answers</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/03/collective-cyber-defence-the-role-of-newer-members-and-opportunities-for-specialization-of-bulgaria-in-the-alliance-questions-and-answers/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2013-03-12:/posts/2013/03/collective-cyber-defence-the-role-of-newer-members-and-opportunities-for-specialization-of-bulgaria-in-the-alliance-questions-and-answers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;November is a month of &lt;a href="http://www.paneuropa.bg/en/news/38/PanEuropa-Bulgaria-organizes-international-conference-with-the-special-support-of-NATO" title="PanEuropa Bulgaria organizes international conference with the special support of NATO"&gt;Smart Defense and Open – Door Policy – New
Synergies for Euro –Atlantic
Security&lt;/a&gt;.
Not only in Europe, but also in South-East European region as well. The
following international event was organized
by &lt;a href="http://www.paneuropa.bg/" title="PanEuropa Bulgaria"&gt;PanEuropa Bulgaria&lt;/a&gt; and
it was supported by NATO. Furthermore, I was invited to take …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;November is a month of &lt;a href="http://www.paneuropa.bg/en/news/38/PanEuropa-Bulgaria-organizes-international-conference-with-the-special-support-of-NATO" title="PanEuropa Bulgaria organizes international conference with the special support of NATO"&gt;Smart Defense and Open – Door Policy – New
Synergies for Euro –Atlantic
Security&lt;/a&gt;.
Not only in Europe, but also in South-East European region as well. The
following international event was organized
by &lt;a href="http://www.paneuropa.bg/" title="PanEuropa Bulgaria"&gt;PanEuropa Bulgaria&lt;/a&gt; and
it was supported by NATO. Furthermore, I was invited to take a
participation as a speaker on the panel discussion Collective Cyber
Defence – The Role of Newer Members and Opportunities for Specialization
of Bulgaria in the Alliance Questions and answers. In details, the event
main points ware to highlight the need for specialization of each member
state in terms of the principles of Smart Defense and the joint
participation in future military operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the event had splendid video addressing in the opening session
of Neelie Kroes, the Vice – President of European Commission.
Emphasizing the current online spying crisis as well as the importance
of cyber security strategy. In additional, she highlighted the
importance of new legal threats, information norms coupled to boost the
trust among the Europe. As well as, that the weakest link in the chain
should be able to raise and boost the awareness, coupled with the future
investments in research and innovations, and projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding the collective cyber defense panel discussion, I was delighted
to be speaker with such strong extensive and experienced experts from
different fields. Such as private, public, academy and business sectors.
Speaking of which, the moderator of the panel was Prof. Veselin Tselkov,
D. Sc., Member of the Board, Commission for Personal Data Protection in
Bulgaria. The lectures where: unfortunately Col. Associate Prof. Dr.
Stoyan Balabanov, Director, Institute for Defense, Ministry of Defense
Bulgaria, was not able to attend the panel, however we had
representative from MoD. Also from Bulgaria was Zlatogor Minchev from
Institute of Information and Communication Technologies, Bulgaria. From
Macedonian was Dr. Metodi Hadji-Janev (LtC), Assistant Prof., Military
Academy ” General Mihailo Apostolski”, Skopje, Macedonia. From business
prospective I was the presenter of
&lt;a href="http://cybersecurity.mk" title="CyberSecurity.mk"&gt;CyberSecurity.mk&lt;/a&gt; copmany,
based in Macedonia. In addition, Mr. Robert Griffin, Director Business
Development – Security Systems, RSA. From all the above, we also had
video addressing from Mr. Detlef Puhl, Senior Advisor at the Emerging
Security Challenges Division, NATO Headquarters, and Mr. Philippe
Roggeband, Security Sales Business Development Manager, EBG EMEAR, Cisco
Systems. However, due to the security measures in the building where the
event was held the video addressing was interrupted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, here is my short presentation notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyberspace has become one of the most essential and distinguished
bridge between government and their inhabitants. Thus, the people are
able to get access to government services 24/7, as well as their life
becomes more easier. However, all in this has led to advance of
producing cyberspace to be vulnerable, coupled with information’s that
should not be available to others. For this reason I would like to
share three important points that are fundamental to emphasis when we
discuss about the Cyber defense in general. First, we have to
understand and highlight the difference between Cyber Security vs IT
Security. Second, it is the important to boost the awareness level
tailored to national level, social society, private sector and indeed
multistakeholder cooperation in the region. Last but not least, we
have to brake the lack of communications between the neighboring
countries and to create a trusted, same level, and collaboration of
cyber security. Where national agencies and parties should work
together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, first the main goal of IT security is to protect
information from a wide range of threats in order to ensure business
continuity, reduce business damages and maximize return on investments
and business opportunity. Likewise the cyber security is protecting
Information and Communication Technologies (ICT) systems and Critical
Infrastructure (CI). However the most important protection element in
IT security is to reduce business risk to accepted levels and the
protection of entire information and information systems essential to
the organizations. Alternatively, cyber security aims at assuring
critical IT service for CI and CII on accepted levels, in addition to
the protection of critical information. In other words the security
objective determiner in information security is an organization’s
business process, while in cyber security it is for the entire state.
Emphasizing that states may have different or complementary interests
compared to an organization’s business interests. On one hand,
handling cyber security problems is considered to be both a nationally
and internationally coordinated activity to protect national CII.
Similarly, to information security goals: confidentiality,
availability and integrity, in cyber security the additional goals are
non-repudiation, authentication, information systems importance and
criticality from the standpoint of state CII/CI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning to awareness, I would like to share my recent research that
have been published as book, title: Interactive Cyber Security
Awareness Program. It is highlighting the method, approach and the
importance of current awareness level in Western Balkans. Coupled how
to boost the awareness on the national level. I would not like to go
in details, however, just want to mention that the positive results
were presented, and that the awareness level among the end users are
varied. Moreover, in particular we have to create and recognize the
importance of establishing cyber security awareness strategy, coupled
with influence of the weakest link in cyber security, which is the
human factor, or in other words, social-technical aspects. In spite of
our investment in technologies and in the applications, still the
weakest link in cyber defense and security will the human behavior.
Therefore, we will have to conceive an awareness/education to raise
the awareness on the national behalf, such as, from the young to the
oldest generation, tailored through social society, private sector and
multistakeholder cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, in recent years we are witnesses of acts that have taken into
place between neighboring countries in the region. Such acts were
followed by different motivations of attacks. Where mostly they were
done through defacement’s or denial-of-service attacks. Thus,
motivations where divers. Nevertheless, in this last point is I would
like to stress the importance of merging the best practices learned
from past event occurrence as well as to improve the role of newer
members and opportunities into the collective roles of cyber defence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, I am keen that after this discussion/panel will lead into
further actions. And also thanks to the organizers for the invitation
and done a good job in organizing such an important event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Pictures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="375"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157646785203333%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157646785203333%2F&amp;set_id=72157646785203333&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157646785203333%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157646785203333%2F&amp;set_id=72157646785203333&amp;jump_to=" width="500" height="375"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="cyber defence"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="bulgaria"></category><category term="balkan"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="nato"></category></entry></feed>