<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece - internet</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/feeds/internet.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://predragtasevski.com/</id><updated>2014-07-06T23:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Stockholm Internet Forum 2014</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2014/07/stockholm-internet-forum-2014/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-06T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-07-06T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2014-07-06:/posts/2014/07/stockholm-internet-forum-2014/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Usually May in Stockholm is cold, chilly and indeed refreshing. However,
this year the weather surprised all the participants of &lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/" title="Stockholm Internet Forum 2014"&gt;Stockholm
Internet Forum
2014&lt;/a&gt;.
Although it is one of the most beautiful cities in Europe, it was even
more with rising sun every day. Especially coming from Nice where the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Usually May in Stockholm is cold, chilly and indeed refreshing. However,
this year the weather surprised all the participants of &lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/" title="Stockholm Internet Forum 2014"&gt;Stockholm
Internet Forum
2014&lt;/a&gt;.
Although it is one of the most beautiful cities in Europe, it was even
more with rising sun every day. Especially coming from Nice where the
weather was under storm, and sunny and long days in Stockholm were
unforgettable. Before I continue with description and the nature of this
year SIF, first would like to apologize for late post – I was under busy
with examination, second would like to thank the organization for
selecting me as a valuable participant.&lt;span id="more-1158"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being in Stockholm for the second time it is a privilege. And indeed,
this year SIF surprised me with the invitation. Usually the organizers
are selecting each year new participant. From their explanation only 10%
of previous year participants are invited where the rest are new.
Consequently, there were around 450 participants, from different
countries in this year SIF14. Nonetheless, it was an event for great
opportunities for networking and meeting interesting people, or see the
rear ones from the previous year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which the event and the panel discussions I might say that
I’m a bit disappointed, because of the repeating of the participant from
SIF13. Another point that I would like to stress out regarding the event
is that in this event the participants are not only a hacktivists,
policy makers, whistleblowers, activities, NGO, etc., but also companies
and so forth. I love the idea of selecting for each panel to have one
enterprise represent, however bear in mind that people will might
exploit this and take and pursue a totally different aspect of the
discussion. Therefore, I suggest for the organization to select wisely
the enterprise panelists. For instance, make sure that the topic and the
theme of the panels are emphasized and understood by the wide audience,
as well as that the chair man and the panelists will control the floor
and that the topic will not go outside of content. This is due to this
event, some panel discussions were totally misunderstood by the audience
and indeed some participants were frustrated, for instance me, but also
many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, coming back to the selection of percentage of the
participant. I frankly love the idea that you like to bring different
audience and different people each year event, however in my opinion and
as well as from other that we discussed during the event is that will be
much better that from the 10% is either 15-20%. This is due to fact that
most if the time these topics and events only and usually bring new
topics and questions, and not give answers to them. So in this respect
you will have a continuing discussions and most probably some answers,
coupled with outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also I would like to take an opportunity to respond to the participant
that were emphasizing the participation of one of the hot topic and
indeed well known person, today – Edward Snowden. In respect to their
request where is Snowden and so on, I would like to point out few
things: first in international law it is firstly impossible to bring him
in Sweden because of his status in Russia; moreover there is no need for
him to take participation in the event where we talk about freedom of
Internet, as well as the espionage, privacy, policy, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum, again thanks to the organization for inviting me once again to
the event. Second, by taking into account the above suggestions,
personally thing that the event will be more progressive, as well as
proactive by having outcome. Further, bring people, panelists which are
wisely selected compliance to the topic and theme of the event and/or
discussion. In the end, looking forward seeing you in the next year, as
well hope that I will be taking place this time as one of panelist.
Where not only that I could contribute with the discussion but also
bring some new important questions in the podium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Pictures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="375"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705209908%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705209908%2F&amp;set_id=72157648705209908&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705209908%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705209908%2F&amp;set_id=72157648705209908&amp;jump_to=" width="500" height="375"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="sctockholm"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="freedom"></category><category term="forum"></category><category term="2014"></category><category term="cyber security"></category></entry><entry><title>Stockholm Internet Forum 2013</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/06/stockholm-internet-forum-2013/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-06-05T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2013-06-05T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2013-06-05:/posts/2013/06/stockholm-internet-forum-2013/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year the Stockholm Internet Forum 2013 was addressing the freedom
of Internet, human rights, freedom of speech, censorship, privacy as
well as importance of security. Among the topics, also we have touched
the cyber security, surveillance, importance of information security
coupled with critical information infrastructure and critical
infrastructure. Once …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year the Stockholm Internet Forum 2013 was addressing the freedom
of Internet, human rights, freedom of speech, censorship, privacy as
well as importance of security. Among the topics, also we have touched
the cyber security, surveillance, importance of information security
coupled with critical information infrastructure and critical
infrastructure. Once Alex Levin has said – “The reason there is so
little crime in Germany is that it’s against the law.” – What a hack he
was talking? Was he right or wrong? For this reason, the SIF was held
this year with more than 94 different countries participants, from all
over the world. And indeed, it was one of the best conference organized
so far. Nevertheless the number of differential participants let the
talks and the conference topics just to flow. Even that the four days of
talking was not enough. However, this was just a start, or for someone
the beginning of an idea due to the poverty of our thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opening speech was by Carl Bildt where he presented in fact an
importance of digital revolution, African development through
connectivity, political debates for freedom of Internet. In addition, he
gave a couple of great examples, such as legislations of blocking sites
in Russia, violations of human rights in Syria, Vietnam among the
others. Also, he noted the security importance of cyber security, where
security should be thought but of course should not be used in purpose
to limit the human rights. One very good quote, even after two weeks
from the conference I still have it in my head, is &lt;strong&gt;*“Free societies
are strong societies”&lt;/strong&gt;. Last but not least, was that we should take an
examples from the leading nations of ICT, such as, Sweden, where the
security coupled with human rights are presented on Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frankly, in the opening session we have touched the issue with
surveillance and software used for this purpose, coupled with the
viability of digital divide popular in Africa and among others.
Moreover, we have purse the issue of Internet jurisdiction projects, as
well as that we have to boost the awareness of regulations united with
the important factor to increased the civil societies in freedom. For
more info please visit the summaries notes from the session, &lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/opening-session/" title="Opening session"&gt;Opening
session&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To continue with the first session again we have to come back some
example of the above issue, surveillance, where Mexico has
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Closed-circuit_television" title="Closed-circuit television - Wikipedia"&gt;CCTV&lt;/a&gt;
in private sector for 3 to 4 years. Among the surveillance we have
discuss the issue during the riots in London, Syria and Panama as a
recent examples where they have shutdown the mobile phone network.
Additionally, point in some countries is that people do trust the law
enforcement in privacy, where opposite such as in Pakistan they trust
only the companies, and not law enforcement agencies. Moreover, hate
speech, digital freedom and democracy of freedom was carried out, along
with how the law works on Internet with civil societies and that the
police need to do their own job. Nevertheless, the note was that
vocabulary of cyber security is missing, and it should become a national
security and of course the security is a huge problem. This problem is
done due to the lack of new laws, by definition of what we mean by a
single law treaty. Whom we should secure? What should be asked? In
sentence of security importance, civil society. We really need a cyber
security strategy, by introducing the legislation and laws throughout
experience. In spite of vocabulary e should define and terms, such as,
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hacktivism" title="Hacktivism - Wiki"&gt;hacktivism&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cyberterrorism" title="Cyberterrorism - Wiki"&gt;cyberterrorism&lt;/a&gt;.
One important note was mentioned that we do not want global cyber
security law. For more info of the session please visit the following
link &lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/session-1/informal-summary/" title="Session 1: Reconciling freedom and security in cyberspace"&gt;Reconciling freedom and security in
cyberspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned above the frustration was between the west and
developing countries in sentence of digital divide. Also one note was
that Sweden people trust to the government agencies, as well as that
e-voting system in Sweden will help ICT to boost. The session where
split into three parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/session-1a/informal-summary-of-session-1a/" title="1A Global security and human rights in the internet age"&gt;1A Global security and human rights in the internet
    age&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/session-1b/informal-summary/" title="1B Distributed security in a national context"&gt;1B Distributed security in a national
    context&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/session-1c/informal-summary/" title="1C Free and secure communication in a multinational context"&gt;1C Free and secure communication in a multinational
    context&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next day, the second day of the forum (SIF13) we have touched a facts
about the free and open Internet and open communications. The second day
I will remember forever for speech of the famous Cuban blogger Yoani
Sánchez, which said very good quote “Cuba Internet on Internet” or
another one is that if your relatives or you personally travel to Cuba
bring the old and unused gadgets with you and leave them in Cuba or just
give them, rather than you should just dispose them or throw them into
the trash. For more info please visit the &lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/summaries-2013/" title="Summaries 2013 | Stockholm Internet Forum"&gt;Summaries 2013
page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I might say that the SIF 13 was very successful, as well
as very important questions and topics were discussed. However, we
should concentrate for the next year forum on more specific topics,
either freedom or only a security. It is very difficult when we speak
about freedom coupled with security. Does two topics are very linked and
fragile. In the end, I would like to thank a lot to the organizers,
&lt;a href="https://www.iis.se/" title=".SE"&gt;.SE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.government.se/sb/d/2059" title="Ministry for Foreign Affairs - Sweden"&gt;Ministry for Foreign Affairs –
Sweden&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href="http://www.sida.se/Svenska/" title="SIDA"&gt;SIDA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Pictures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="375"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648696553859%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648696553859%2F&amp;set_id=72157648696553859&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648696553859%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648696553859%2F&amp;set_id=72157648696553859&amp;jump_to=" width="500" height="375"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="internet"></category><category term="forum"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="stockholm"></category><category term="freedom"></category></entry><entry><title>Company Brochure and Founder Notes, Cybersecurity.mk</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2012/09/company-brochure-and-founder-notes-cybersecuritymk/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-20T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2012-09-20T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2012-09-20:/posts/2012/09/company-brochure-and-founder-notes-cybersecuritymk/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;COMPANY BROCHURE: Cybersecurity.mk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your IT infrastructure could be taken under the shoulder of
professionals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;September 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founder Notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, Macedonian government has announced to open a CERT agency.
This news was not only shock to us, but to everyone else, indeed.
However, we are supporting this initiative and hope …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;COMPANY BROCHURE: Cybersecurity.mk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your IT infrastructure could be taken under the shoulder of
professionals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;September 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founder Notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, Macedonian government has announced to open a CERT agency.
This news was not only shock to us, but to everyone else, indeed.
However, we are supporting this initiative and hope that will be able to
elaborate and corporate within organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Macedonian situation in a field of information and cyber security is not
on very surprising or signification level. Therefore our main goal is to
increase and merge the collaboration with neighbour countries as well as
with international organizations and agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, our belief lies that we will be able to bring better
understanding of very important issues that concern information and
cyber security, and to lead to better national awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this matter, our company will continue to expend the partnership as
well as international collaboration. We will constantly checking for
updates for existing solutions, also to search for new solutions to
update our offerings and services. And further development of our
projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this brochure we would like to introduce you with our company
profile, such as, our services, partners, clients, projects and our blog
posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link to PDF version of the brochure is on the following link:
&lt;a href="http://cybersecurity.mk/about.html"&gt;http://cybersecurity.mk/about.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="cert"></category><category term="CIRT"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="cybersecurity"></category><category term="cybersecurity.mk"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="macedonia"></category><category term="mkd"></category><category term="online"></category><category term="security"></category></entry><entry><title>Hate Speech on Internet, 01 Dec. 2012</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2012/04/hate-speech-on-internet-01-dec-2012/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-04-11T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2012-04-11T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2012-04-11:/posts/2012/04/hate-speech-on-internet-01-dec-2012/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Discussing in one of the highest mountains in Macedonia, around 1250m
above sea level, in theme to Hate Speech on Internet is always a great
idea.&lt;span id="more-503"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the event was performed from 30 of November until 3rd of
December by non-governmental, non-profit youth voluntary organization,
&lt;a href="http://www.cid.mk/index.php"&gt;The Centre for Intercultural Dialogue …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Discussing in one of the highest mountains in Macedonia, around 1250m
above sea level, in theme to Hate Speech on Internet is always a great
idea.&lt;span id="more-503"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the event was performed from 30 of November until 3rd of
December by non-governmental, non-profit youth voluntary organization,
&lt;a href="http://www.cid.mk/index.php"&gt;The Centre for Intercultural Dialogue
(CID)&lt;/a&gt;. In the request to the organization
I was invited to deliver training-speech as an expert in the cyber
security to the above topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get an idea of what was the content of training I have provided you
with the slides below, as well as the pictures taken during training.
Unfortunately, the presentation slides are only in Macedonian language.
If anyone needs the content on the slides in English please fell free to
contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, I would like to thank the organizers for the invitation, as
well as, for a great organized event and kindly words from the trainees.
The group to the panel discussion was very enthusiasts, knowledgeable
and experience to share and to give an interesting ideas for the hence
actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conclusion from the discussion was made. As well as, that this is
just a step to bring the topic into Macedonia, and for the organizations
and groups to become more familiar and aware about the Hate Speech on
Internet as extremely important topic to be taken into consideration. In
additions, to emphases that in Macedonia is widespread in different
categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Slides:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/file/d/0B1472nuKPMN5WmtHNW56OEU2V1k/preview" width="640" height="480"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="hate speech"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="macedonia"></category><category term="sapka"></category><category term="cid"></category></entry><entry><title>Clever solution by making site more resilient by optimization</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2012/03/clever-solution-by-making-site-more-resilient-by-optimization/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-03-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-03-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2012-03-23:/posts/2012/03/clever-solution-by-making-site-more-resilient-by-optimization/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;PURPOSE &amp;amp; SCENARIO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective of this laboratory test, scenario is to make explore
alternative “clever” solutions (as opposed to making the site more
resilient by optimizing it) to protect your site against attacks.
Moreover, DDoS [1] attacks, malicious code, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, we need to develop countermeasures for the &lt;strong&gt;working&lt;/strong&gt;
attacks …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;PURPOSE &amp;amp; SCENARIO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective of this laboratory test, scenario is to make explore
alternative “clever” solutions (as opposed to making the site more
resilient by optimizing it) to protect your site against attacks.
Moreover, DDoS [1] attacks, malicious code, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, we need to develop countermeasures for the &lt;strong&gt;working&lt;/strong&gt;
attacks simulated with a standard DoS attack from a single IP address
(performed with AB [2] or Jmeter). Limitations for this scenarios is
highlighted:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No additional hardware can be used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The wordpress installation can not be optimized: no caching plugins,
    no reverse-proxy (varnish, squid etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No reactive measures that automatically block incoming traffic: the
    site must respond to at least some of the requests coming from the
    attacker at all times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The countermeasures must not have negative effects on “normal usage
    pattern”. Normal usage pattern is defined as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bursts of 10 connections per IP address in 1 second&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Page load times not over 10 seconds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
-   Normal usage must be possible from the same IP address that the
attack originated from after a 20 second delay maximum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, we have to make much of the rules for the scenario. Rules
as follow: Fresh installation of the latest version of Ubuntu Server and
the most recent WordPress as of 20.10.2011. First priority: No normal
usage pattern connections can be dropped! Second priority: service speed
of normal connections. Defined by number of connections / second (easy
to measure). Third priority: How fast after the attack is stopped, the
site can be accessed from the attacking IP again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each test and measured results will be exposed in to Test section.
Whereas, the process of installation of clever solution and attacking
scripts will be provided in to Appendixes section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the measurement results will be compared with the first state
without attack and any security solutions applied. Alternatively,
providing measurement results with one solution and attack will help us
to identify the most beneficial security solution. Therefore, in
Conclusion section comparison results will be highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;TESTS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of requirements of our scenario we need to display the results
before security solution is applied and attacker performance. For this
purpose we are going to use an AB script to display the response time of
the server:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ab -t 10 -n 10 -c 10 http://192.168.56.102/wordpress/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above script provides detail information, yet only important is
Request per second. Thus, with an fresh installation and without any
security solution, it provided with result of 3.95 [#/sec]. With other
word, 3.95 number of request per second. After applying different
security solution and performing an attack to the server, results will
be divers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, test were done by two different virtual environment
machines. One is for testing results and the other one is to perform
attack with the following script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ab -n 100 -c 10 http://192.168.56.102/wordpress/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;TEST 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First test is to install libapache2-mod-evasive
[libapache2-mod-evasive]. Where, mod_evasive is an evasive maneuvers
module for Apache is to provide some protection in the event of an HTTP
DoS or DDoS attack or brute force attack. It is also designed to be a
detection tool, and can be easily configured to talk to ipchains,
firewalls, routers, and etcetera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process of installation and configuration refer to the Appendix 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After completed the installation and configuration process it is time to
test the security solution and to highlight the results. Before
performing the attack the results were somehow, lower then, before
installing the mod-evasive, 2.06 number request per second. When we
start the attack and in same time analysis the server responded with
timeout. The conclusion is that mod-evasive it is not enough solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;TEST 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From previous test we can see that the solution was not enough clever
for our needs. The server somehow was dead. However, we are going to
install now &lt;code&gt;mod_security&lt;/code&gt; module for apache, with side of previous
test. For more detail information of installation process and
configuration refer to Appendix 2 or to the following source
[mod_security].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three points that we should consider and to see which proposal
was more accurate and it did the job that was required in the scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the above proposals are nice and good example to have an
view of how and with what tools we should perform script kiddie
techniques. How to shutdown access to a server. On the whole, it show as
how to use tools and methods of measuring the bandwidth of network and
how to limit the transfer in comfortable way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;APPENDIXES&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appendix 1 is connected with the Method 1, which highlighted points are
illustration on what information we should check, to clarify that the
virtual environment has limitation of the network interface. Where
Appendix 2 is for installation process of Ubuntu Server 10.04 LTS and
wordpress, mysql installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;APPENDIX 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install libapache2-mod-evasive&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configuration process is followed and gather from the following source
[Evasive Module], for addition proposal please refer to[Blacklist]:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    sudo mkdir /var/log/apache2/mod_evasivesudo chown www-data /var/log/apache2/mod_evasive

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, create its configuration file with a default content, with
the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    sudo nano /etc/apache2/apache2.conf IfModule mod_evasive20.c;DOSHashTableSize 3097DOSPageCount 2DOSSiteCount 50DOSPageInterval 1DOSSiteInterval 1DOSBlockingPeriod 10DOSLogDir /var/log/apache2/mod_evasiveDOSEmailNotify root@localhostDOSWhitelist 127.0.0.1DOSSystemCommand &amp;amp;quot;/sbin/iptables -I INPUT -p tcp --dport 80 -s %s -j DROP/IfModule;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above changes to take effect please restart the apache service by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo service apache2 restart&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can test whether it works using a script included in the deb
package:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;perl /usr/share/doc/libapache2-mod-evasive/examples/test.pl&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;APPENDIX 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation and configuration of mod_security:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install libapache2-modsecurity /etc/init.d/apache2 force-reload&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation media: Ubuntu 11.10 32bit iso image;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HW: Virtualbox, 1CPU 32bit, 512MB RAM, 8GB HD (dynamic allocation);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC1 NAT;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC2 host only (for ssh and http access from host);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language used in installation process: English and country Estonia;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyboard Layout English;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no http proxy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install lamp phpmyadmin&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;wget -c http://wordpress.org/latest.tar.gz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;tar xvjf latest.tar.gz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo cp wordpress /var/www/wordpress&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nano /var/www/wordpress/wp-config.php&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the settings to your needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[libapache2-mod-evasive] Canonical Ltd., Package: libapache2-mod-evasive
(1.10.1-1), 2011,
&lt;a href="http://packages.ubuntu.com/hardy/libapache2-mod-evasive"&gt;http://packages.ubuntu.com/hardy/libapache2-mod-evasive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[modsecurity] How to Forge, Secure Your Apache With mod_security, 2006,
&lt;a href="http://www.howtoforge.com/apache_mod_security"&gt;http://www.howtoforge.com/apache_mod_security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Evasive Module] Deep Logic, Inc., Apache Evasive Maneuvers Module,
2005,
&lt;a href="http://fossies.org/unix/www/apache_httpd_modules/mod_evasive_1.10.1.tar.gz:t/mod_evasive/README"&gt;http://fossies.org/unix/www/apache_httpd_modules/mod_evasive_1.10.1.tar.gz:t/mod_evasive/README&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Blacklist] Jeff Starr, Eight Ways to Blacklist with Apache’s
mod_rewrite, Feb 2009,
&lt;a href="http://perishablepress.com/press/2009/02/03/eight-ways-to-blacklist-with-apaches-mod_rewrite/"&gt;http://perishablepress.com/press/2009/02/03/eight-ways-to-blacklist-with-apaches-mod_rewrite/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] DDoS – Denial-of-service attack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] AB - &lt;a href="http://httpd.apache.org/docs/2.0/programs/ab.html"&gt;http://httpd.apache.org/docs/2.0/programs/ab.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="ab"></category><category term="attacks"></category><category term="clever solution"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="DDoS"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="jmeter"></category><category term="malicious code"></category><category term="wordpress"></category></entry><entry><title>Testing SNORT – IDS rulesets</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2012/03/testing-snort-ids-rulesets/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-03-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-03-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2012-03-13:/posts/2012/03/testing-snort-ids-rulesets/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;SCENARIO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective of this laboratory test, scenario is to create a solution
and instructions for testing an IDS^1^ systems usefulness for detecting
attacks against a wordpress site. In addition, we have to
develop/download/find/whatever a SNORT configuration (rulesets,
preprocessors, whatever) that performs better than the default …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;SCENARIO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective of this laboratory test, scenario is to create a solution
and instructions for testing an IDS^1^ systems usefulness for detecting
attacks against a wordpress site. In addition, we have to
develop/download/find/whatever a SNORT configuration (rulesets,
preprocessors, whatever) that performs better than the default
configuration in previous post. By better we mean:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less false positives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less false negatives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The objectives are contradictory so the rule of thumb is one false
    negative per 10 false positives eg. solution with 10 false positives
    and 2 false negatives is better than the solution with 100 false
    positives and 1 false negatives, but the solution with 10 false
    positives and 1 false negative is better than the solution with 1
    false positive and 2 false negatives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attack is defined by a single invocation of all the test scripts in
    a row.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the new rules have to be able to detect not only the default
attacks that are set to a default snort configuration, yet they have to
be able to detect SQL injection, brute force password, apache killer
script, pytbull, etc. Furthermore, in figure 1 we are illustrating the
scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration 1: Illustration of Scenario&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, in the proposal section we will present two proposals that
have been submitted due to this laboratory test and additionally in
result section we will highlighted the identification numbers made by
snort set new rules. In section appendixes we will provide you with more
details configuration procedures, configuration of VM’s – Virtual
Machines, attacks, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, closing with an conclusion and the results of best set of rules
made of the proposals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;SETUP of SNORT&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To setup snort in a right way, that will work for the second Host only
network please following the instruction link provided with a full
description and configuration of snort [SNORT2].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;PROPOSALS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In total two proposals are presented in next sub-sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;PROPOSAL 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add &lt;a href="http://www.tud.ttu.ee/~t061780/attacks/robert.rules"&gt;http://www.tud.ttu.ee/~t061780/attacks/robert.rules&lt;/a&gt; to your Snort.
On your Snort machine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    cd /etc/snort/ruleswget http://www.tud.ttu.ee/~t061780/attacks/robert.rules

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you have the rules, add them to your snort conf file (default
/etc/snort/snort.conf). To do that inser:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;include $RULE_PATH/robert.rules&lt;/code&gt; somewhere with rest of the rules after
line 800. Run Snort and test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;PROPOSAL 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the following rules: &lt;a href="http://predragtasevski.com/src/predrag.rules"&gt;http://predragtasevski.com/src/predrag.rules&lt;/a&gt;.
To be able to insert the snort rules in to the snort file please double
check where it is located. You can find the location with the following
command: find / -name snort.conf Before you continue please change the
IP address to your server address on line number #6, example alert tcp
any any -&gt; 192.168.56.X where x is your octet. Then to add the
following rules at the conf file do the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cat predrag.rules &amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;gt; snort.conf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it is time to start or restart snort. It should work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;RESULTS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After executing the above proposal we will highlight the results into
the table bellow. Result are presented from the total amount of reports,
registered alerts in the snort. This is done by help of web interface of
Basic Analysis and Security Engine in addition Analysis Console for
Intrusion Databases (ACID) project tool [ACID]. Therefore, the result
from the proposals are highlighted below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;th align="right"&gt;
Attack performed

&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;th align="center"&gt;
Proposal number

&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;th align="center"&gt;
Baseline Total number of Alerts

&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;th align="center"&gt;
Total number of Alerts

&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;th align="right"&gt;
Unique Alerts

&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
SQL injection

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
1

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
0

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
0

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
0

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
SQL injection

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
2

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
0

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
52

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
1

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
Pytbull – evasion

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
1

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
N/A

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
128

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
6

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
SQL injection + nmap

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
Combine both

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
N/A

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
36

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
5

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
Pytbull

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
Combine both

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
N/A

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
844

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
7

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Table 1: Details of total report numbers of alerts made by SNORT and the
different proposal rule sets. Details of the attacks conducted in the
table are presented in appendixes section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, figure 2 is presenting the pine chart of the total number
alerts recognized by Snort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration 2: Total number of Alerts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, figure 3 is representing the pine chart of total number of
unique alerts recognized by Snort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration 3: Total number of Unique Alerts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the above results we came to conclusion that the new applied rules
were successful and were able to recognize alerts more then the default
rule set of Snort. Meanwhile, only proposal 2 was able to recognized an
SQL injections without any additional tweaking. Although proposal 1 was
still useful, on the other hand the best solution is when we combine the
both rule sets proposals. Then the Snort is able to recognized an
significant number of total alerts and additionally for our laboratory
report more interesting is unique total number alerts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Closing, even the default Snort rules configuration is good, yet when
you tweak it by&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;your own needs, you will have much better IDS system for your network.
In future it should be recommended always refer to [snort_rules], to
gather more available advance Snort rules, made by experts. Where will
help you to configure and setup Snort IDS system to detecting attacks
against a wordpress site, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;APPENDIXES&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appendix 1 is the configuration of the attacker virtual machine, in more
detail Blacktrack 5 distribution. Secondly, Appendix 2 is the ubuntu
wordpress configuration server and additional is the configuration and
setup process and refer links of IDS Snort virtual machine. Appendix 4,
5 and 6 are providing brief details about the attacks that were
conducted during this laboratory test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;APPENDIX 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation media: Black Track 5 GNOME 32bit iso image;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HW: Virtualbox, 1CPU 32bit, 512MB RAM, 8GB HD (dynamic allocation);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC1 NAT;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC2 host only (for ssh and http access from host);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downloadable link: &lt;a href="http://www.backtrack-linux.org/downloads/"&gt;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/downloads/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;
APPENDIX 2

&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation media: Ubuntu 10.04 32bit iso image;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HW: Virtualbox, 1CPU 32bit, 512MB RAM, 8GB HD (dynamic allocation);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC1 NAT;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC2 host only (for ssh and http access from host);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language used in installation process: English and country Estonia;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyboard Layout English;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hostname: pece&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partition methods: Guided, use entire disk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username: pece&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no http proxy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    sudo apt-get install lamp phpmyadminwget -c http://wordpress.org/latest.tar.gztar xvjf latest.tar.gzsudo cp wordpress /var/www/wordpresssudo nano /var/www/wordpress/wp-config.php Change the settings to your needs

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;APPENDIX 3&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation media: Ubuntu 10.04 32bit iso image;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HW: Virtualbox, 1CPU 32bit, 512MB RAM, 8GB HD (dynamic allocation);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC1 NAT;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC2 host only (for ssh and http access from host);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language used in installation process: English and country Estonia;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyboard Layout English;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hostname: pece&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partition methods: Guided, use entire disk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username: pece&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no http proxy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snort configuration and installation refer to [SNORT1] in addition,
    please refer to [SNORT2].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;APPENDIX 4&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we test typical SQL- injection in URLs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commands used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    wget "http://192.168.56.101/?p=1'%20OR%20'1'='1"wget "http://192.168.56.101/?p=1'%20AND%201=(SELECT%20COUNT(*)%20FROM%20tabname);%20—"

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snort by default does not detect this, where in applying the proposal 2
rules, it did detect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;APPENDIX 5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test Snort and acidbase, perform a portscan of the Snort host.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nmap -p1-65535 -sV -sS -O 192.168.56.102&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;APPENDIX 6&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To setup pytbull it is a bit of pain, yet if you follow the rules and
the documentation it will work like shark. For documentation please
refer to [pytbull_doc].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[SNORT2] Nick Moore, Snort 2.8.4.1 Ubuntu 9 Installation Guide, June
2009, &lt;a href="http://www.snort.org/assets/113/Snort_2.8.4.1_Ubuntu.pdf"&gt;http://www.snort.org/assets/113/Snort_2.8.4.1_Ubuntu.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ACID] Basic Analysis and Security Engine, Welcome to the Basic Analysis
and Security Engine (BASE) project ,
2008,&lt;a href="http://base.secureideas.net/about.php"&gt;http://base.secureideas.net/about.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[snort_rules]
&lt;a href="http://rules.emergingthreats.net/open/snort-2.9.0/rules/"&gt;http://rules.emergingthreats.net/open/snort-2.9.0/rules/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[SNORT1] kat-amsterdam, SnortIDS, December 2010,
&lt;a href="https://help.ubuntu.com/community/SnortIDS"&gt;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/SnortIDS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[pytbull_doc] Sébastien Damaye, Official documentation for pytbull v1.3
-, 2011, &lt;a href="http://pytbull.sourceforge.net/index.php?page=documentation"&gt;http://pytbull.sourceforge.net/index.php?page=documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] IDS – Intrusion detection system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="DDoS"></category><category term="ids"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="networking"></category><category term="online"></category><category term="Port scan"></category><category term="snort"></category><category term="snort rules"></category><category term="SYN flood"></category><category term="testing ids"></category><category term="vulnerability scanning"></category></entry><entry><title>Testing IDS</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2012/01/testing-ids/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-01-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-01-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2012-01-03:/posts/2012/01/testing-ids/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;SCENARIO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective of this laboratory test, scenario is to create a solution
and instructions for testing an IDS\^1 systems usefulness for detecting
attacks against a wordpress site. In addition, a repeatable process to
evaluate vendor claims. Whatever passive IDS system sample delivered as
a VM or a dedicated …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;SCENARIO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective of this laboratory test, scenario is to create a solution
and instructions for testing an IDS\^1 systems usefulness for detecting
attacks against a wordpress site. In addition, a repeatable process to
evaluate vendor claims. Whatever passive IDS system sample delivered as
a VM or a dedicated box. Creating the IDS system itself is out of scope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process must be detailed enough so that somebody else can get the
same results when applying that. The “other person” is expected to have
IT knowledge sufficient to install and run a Linux desktop. Budget
requirements: Modest – 2 machines + a tester (Joe) + networking
equipment to connect the two machines and an IDS together. The process
must test at least the following attacks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Port scan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SYN flood&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Regular” DoS overwhelming attack (Ab)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Optionally the process may test:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;slowloris/pyloris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache Range header DoS vulnerability
&lt;a href="http://httpd.apache.org/security/CVE-011-3192.txt"&gt;http://httpd.apache.org/security/CVE-011-3192.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An attack targeting any other fairly recent (not older than 3-4 years)
known vulnerability that could in theory apply to the target system
(wordpress server)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However the competition rules are: The highest number of attacks
evaluated. Limits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each attack must be relevant eg. if it attacks IIS it’s NOT relevant.
If it attacks Windows RPC it’s not relevant. If it attacks some other
CMS eg. Drupal it’s NOT relevant. * Basically equivalent attacks count
as one (different port scanners for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must be able to explain in broad terms what the attack does eg:
attacks the vulnerability #X in Apache server If the #attacks is
equal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lab instaractions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install 3 VM-s: Attacker IDS and Target&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
​1. Make sure all VM-s have two network adapters: NAT and Host-Only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​2. Install Snort and it’s GUI called “acidbase” on IDS
&lt;a href="https://help.ubuntu.com/community/SnortIDS"&gt;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/SnortIDS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​3. Install Apache, Mysql and WordPress on Target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​4. Execute an attack on Attacker towards the IP address on the Host
Only network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​5. Take notice of the results displayed on Acid console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​6. Reset counters, move on to next attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, illustration 1 describes the overview of above scenario&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration 1: Lab 5 Illustration of Scenario&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, setup procedure of snort, secondly available proposals and
thirdly illustrating the results and the functionality of proposals.
Finally, closing this laboratory report with conclusion. In addition,
appendixes is configuration of VM’s – Virtual Machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;SETUP of SNORT&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To setup snort in a right way, that will work for the second Host only
network please following the instruction link provided with a full
description and configuration of snort [SNORT2].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After completing the setup and configuration to run snort on the second
interface use the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;snort -c /etc/snort/snort/conf -i eth1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;PROPOSALS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In total three proposals and each one is highlighted in the next
sub-sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;PROPOSAL 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​1. Set up IDS (Snort) and WordPress on the first PC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​2. Install Ubuntu server on the second PC . Then install all attacking
tools there:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;```wget enos.itcollege.ee/\~avein/lab4i.sh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sudo sh lab4i.sh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    After that you should have:- ```ab.sh``` – DoS attack script – uses ab to generate traffic flood- ```apachekiller.pl``` – Apachekiller attack script More info: http://www.hackersgarage.com/apache-killer-denial-of-service-flaw-in-apache-webserver.html- ```README.txt``` – extra instructions- ```scan.sh``` - Port scanning script - uses nmap- ```sloworis.pl``` - Sloworis attack script More info: http://ha.ckers.org/slowloris/- ```synf.sh``` - syn flood attack script - uses hping33. Start your IDS/wordpress server and the server with attack tools. 4. Run each attack tool ONE AT A TIME (targeting the wordpress/IDS server of course) . Monitor the logs/notifications on yours IDS system (SNORT) and check whether wordpress site is still accessible. Let each attack tool run 2 minutes, then stop the attack by pressing CTRL+C on the terminal window where the attack tool is running. The only exeption is port scan- its better to wait until it finishes. After each attack save the IDS log and wait atlest 5 minutes before trying next tool (to give server time to recover). Best practice is to manually check if the server load is at normal (one can use htop for that).a) To run DoS attack:```sh ab.sh {target} eg sh ab.sh 192.168.56.101```b) For port scan:```sh scan.sh {target IP} eg sh scan.sh 192.168.56.101```c) For Syn flood (with hping3)```sh synf.sh {target} eg synf.sh 192.168.56.101/wordpress```d) For Sloworis attack:```perl slowloris.pl -dns {target} eg perl sloworis.pl -dns 192.168.56.101/wordpress```e) For Apachekiller attack:```perl apachekiller.pl {target IP} eg perl apachekiller.pl 192.168.56.101```## PROPOSAL 2### IntroFor this scenario we need to run several different attacks and scans to be able to compare the results with different IDS setups and rulesets. We might also want to test it with legitimate traffic to see that we dont get false positives in our alarms. We dont have that much legitimate traffic possibilities with 1 blog on our servers right now, but if we start tweaking the IDS false positives becomes an important metric and we might want to test normal usage and create traffic to run with tcpreplay for example. My proposal is to test the IDS with pytbull running on BackTrack. Pytbull is IDS testing framework and BackTrack a Linux ditribution. I will assume that we have WordPress server with running default Snort set up on it and working. No extensive testing has been done with different snort setups so we might have to tune the methods, but basic things should be covered.### DL and install BackTrack- &lt;a href="http://www.backtrack-linux.org/downloads/" target="_blank"&gt;backtrack-linux.org/downloads/&lt;/a&gt;Install it rather than running a live version for this scenario. Boot it up in default mode, start GUI and launch installation from desktop. Default login root / toor. Standard setup comes with pytbull and several pieces of software the IDS test-system depends on like nmap, hping3, nikto and others.### Setup connectionsConnect the machines and install ftp and ssh on server. We need ftp to get snort alert files and ssh to run attacks against.```apt-get install vsftpd openssh-server```### Setup pytbullYou will find pytbull from ```/pentest/enumeration/ids/pytbull/``` or Applications -&gt; BackTrack -&gt; Information Gathering -&gt; Network Analysis -&gt; IDS IPS Identification -&gt; pytbull when using the GUI. Change the configuration file values to have correct connection information, user credentials and locations of dependencies. Here you also select which test modules out of the 9 available you want to run. ClientSideAttacks needs extra configuration.

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cd /pentest/enumeration/ids/pytbull/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;gedit config.cfg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example conf file: http://www.tud.ttu.ee/\~t061780/attacks/config.cfg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now get custom DoS module to have hping SYN flood and ApacheBench DoS
tests covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cd modules&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mv denialOfService.py denialOfService.py-backup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;wget http://www.tud.ttu.ee/\~t061780/attacks/denialOfService.py&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may want to refer to Pytbull documentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    ### Run```/pentest/enumeration/ids/pytbull/pytbull -t WP/Snort server IP;```If everything works you will find html report file under /reports. If you have problems add -d on run for debugging.###(optional) SlowlorisTo have slowloris attack test for pytbull we need to get custom slowloris that allows to set how many packets to send because we dont want the tests to run forever. I added argument s that tells the script to stop after we have sent s packets.

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cd /pentest/stressing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;wget www.tud.ttu.ee/\~t061780/attacks/slowloris.pl&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slowloris attack has been written into DoS module, you have to uncomment
it. Lines 47-52.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;gedit /pentest/enumeration/ids/pytbull/modules/denialOfService.py&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    ## PROPOSAL 3For this proposal I will suggest to use open source tool OpenVas for vulnerability scanning, to test our IDS system. It contains many security tools integrated. The security and analysis tools are: Nikto, nmap, ike-scan, snmpwalk, amap, ldapsearch, SLAD (John-the-Ripper, Chkrootkit, LSOF, ClamAV, Tripwire, TIGER, logwatch, trapwatch, lm-sensors, snort and ovaldi), pnscan, portbunny, strobe, w3af, etc.Instructions of installation process, for further more information please refer to &lt;a href="http://www.openvas.org/setup-and-start.html" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.openvas.org/setup-and-start.html&lt;/a&gt;### Step 1: Configure OBS Repository```sudo apt-get -y install python-software-propertiessudo add-apt-repository "deb http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/security:/OpenVAS:STABLE:/v4/xUbuntu_10.04/./"sudo apt-key adv --keyserver hkp://keys.gnupg.net --recv-keys BED1E87979EAFD54 sudo apt-get update

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Step 2: Quick-Install OpenVAS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    sudo apt-get -y install greenbone-security-assistant gsd openvas-cli openvas-manager openvas-scanner openvas-administrator sqlite3 xsltproc

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Step 3: Quick-Start OpenVAS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(copy and paste whole block, during first time you will be asked to set
a password for user “admin”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    test -e /var/lib/openvas/CA/cacert.pem || sudo openvas-mkcert -qsudo openvas-nvt-sync test -e /var/lib/openvas/users/om || sudo openvas-mkcert-client -n om -i sudo /etc/init.d/openvas-manager stopsudo /etc/init.d/openvas-scanner stopsudo openvassdsudo openvasmd --migratesudo openvasmd --rebuildsudo killall openvassdsleep 15sudo /etc/init.d/openvas-scanner startsudo /etc/init.d/openvas-manager startsudo /etc/init.d/openvas-administrator restartsudo /etc/init.d/greenbone-security-assistant restarttest -e /var/lib/openvas/users/admin || sudo openvasad -c add_user -n admin -r Admin

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Step 4: Log into OpenVAS as “admin”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open &lt;code&gt;https://localhost:9392/&lt;/code&gt; or start &lt;code&gt;“gsd”&lt;/code&gt; on a command line as a
regular user (not as root!). Optional we can use and the Slowloris and
Pyloris DoS attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download link for Slowloris is:
&lt;a href="http://ha.ckers.org/slowloris/slowloris.pl"&gt;http://ha.ckers.org/slowloris/slowloris.pl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above solution and tool will help us to check and test our IDS
system usefulness. It tests the following attacks: Port scan, SYN flood,
DoS, etc. The results are presented with nice GUI interface. For more
info about the project please refer to
&lt;a href="http://www.openvas.org/"&gt;www.openvas.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;RESULTS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After executing the above proposal we will highlight the results.
Nevertheless, only the Proposal 1 was able to run the test. Others two,
Proposal 2 and Proposal 3 were unsuccessful of installation process and
configuration and to run the attacks. Moreover, the result are presented
from the total amount of reports, registered alerts in the snort. This
is done by help of web interface of Basic Analysis and Security Engine
in addition Analysis Console for Intrusion Databases (ACID) project tool
[ACID]. Therefore, the result from the Proposal 1 and from the rest are
highlighted below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proposal 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DoS – registered alerts: 2;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Port scan : 8;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;synf.sh: 1344;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slowloris.pl: 1782;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;apachekiller.pl: not working;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
-   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proposal 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
-   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pytbull: 0, the message was: Error: FTP error, 550 failed to open
file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
-   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proposal 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
-   Too complicated to be configured and installed. The instructions and
the procedures should be more easy. After few hours of configuring
and test, tweaks are is still not working. Yet there are many good
tutorials how to configure OpenVAS please refer [OpenVas1] and
[OpenVas2].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Primarily, setting-up IDS, the Snort, it is not an easy task to
complete. On the other hand, configuring, installing, etc. the testing
tools for IDS system is even more complicated. Therefore, the Proposal 1
has the best solution and installation process of the test tools.
Despite, that it was the only one that worked. Finally, recommendation
for the IDS solutions and in addition to the penetrating tools to test
the usefulness of IDS has to be more simple and stepwise solution.
However, the above scenario and proposals are great tools and solutions
for a future reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;APPENDIXES&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appendix 1 is the configuration of the attacker virtual machine, in more
detail Blacktrack distribution. Secondly, Appendix 2 is the ubuntu
wordpress configuration server and additional is the configuration and
setup process and refer links of IDS Snort virtual machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;APPENDIX 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation media: Black Track 5 GNOME 32bit iso image;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HW: Virtualbox, 1CPU 32bit, 512MB RAM, 8GB HD (dynamic allocation);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC1 NAT;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC2 host only (for ssh and http access from host);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downloadable link: &lt;a href="http://www.backtrack-linux.org/downloads/"&gt;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/downloads/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;APPENDIX 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation media: Ubuntu 10.04 32bit iso image;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HW: Virtualbox, 1CPU 32bit, 512MB RAM, 8GB HD (dynamic allocation);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC1 NAT;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC2 host only (for ssh and http access from host);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language used in installation process: English and country Estonia;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyboard Layout English;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hostname: pece&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partition methods: Guided, use entire disk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username: pece&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no http proxy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    sudo apt-get install lamp phpmyadminwget -c http://wordpress.org/latest.tar.gztar xvjf latest.tar.gzsudo cp wordpress /var/www/wordpresssudo nano /var/www/wordpress/wp-config.php&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change the settings to your needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;APPENDIX 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation media: Ubuntu 10.04 32bit iso image;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HW: Virtualbox, 1CPU 32bit, 512MB RAM, 8GB HD (dynamic allocation);  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC1 NAT;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC2 host only (for ssh and http access from host);  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language used in installation process: English and country Estonia;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyboard Layout English;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hostname: pece  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partition methods: Guided, use entire disk  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username: pece  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no http proxy  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default applications  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snort configuration and installation refer to [SNORT1] in addition,
    please refer to [SNORT2].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SNORT2: Nick Moore, Snort 2.8.4.1 Ubuntu 9 Installation Guide, June
2009, &lt;a href="http://www.snort.org/assets/113/Snort_2.8.4.1_Ubuntu.pdf"&gt;http://www.snort.org/assets/113/Snort_2.8.4.1_Ubuntu.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ACID: Basic Analysis and Security Engine, Welcome to the Basic Analysis
and Security Engine (BASE) project, 2008,
&lt;a href="http://base.secureideas.net/about.php"&gt;http://base.secureideas.net/about.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenVas1: NA, Backtrack 5- OpenVas Tutorial, NA,
&lt;a href="http://www.ehacking.net/2011/06/backtrack-5-openvas-tutorial.html"&gt;http://www.ehacking.net/2011/06/backtrack-5-openvas-tutorial.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenVas2: BackTrack Linux, Getting started with OpenVas, June 2011,
&lt;a href="http://www.backtrack-linux.org/wiki/index.php/OpenVas"&gt;http://www.backtrack-linux.org/wiki/index.php/OpenVas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SNORT1: kat-amsterdam, SnortIDS, December 2010,
&lt;a href="https://help.ubuntu.com/community/SnortIDS"&gt;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/SnortIDS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] IDS – Intrusion detection system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="DDoS"></category><category term="ids"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="networking"></category><category term="online"></category><category term="openvas"></category><category term="port scan"></category><category term="snort"></category><category term="SYN flood"></category><category term="testing ids"></category><category term="vulnerability scanning"></category></entry><entry><title>Script Kiddie</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2011/10/script-kiddie/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-10-19T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2011-10-19T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2011-10-19:/posts/2011/10/script-kiddie/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;PURPOSE and SCENARIO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this laboratory test is to make effort to attack server and
to deface website. Here is the scenario: your client is worried about
some stuff posted on a blog. They ask You to take care of it. They have
a throwaway “script kiddie”[Script …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;PURPOSE and SCENARIO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this laboratory test is to make effort to attack server and
to deface website. Here is the scenario: your client is worried about
some stuff posted on a blog. They ask You to take care of it. They have
a throwaway “script kiddie”[Script kiddie] in a third world country, who
will mount the attack so You don’t need to worry about hiding the
attackers identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, we need to devise a way to attack wordpress (default
installation) based site to render it unusable (page view times over 60
seconds). Attack resources: one PC with Microsoft Windows XP, a script
kiddie, internet connection of 2Mbit/s. In addition, server has to stay
down for two days and script kiddie has up to 1 day to set up the
attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For scenario above their three different proposals from the fallow
students. Each proposal is described in section Proposals and their
effectiveness, installation process and the evaluation of the efficient
use of available resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, easy solution for limiting the internet connection of 2Mbit/s
by Oracle VirtualBox configuration manager. Secondly, the bandwidth
capacity of the connection and their performance is measured by vnstat1
for graphs to display our utilization. The steps are vivid on section
Methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, providing measurement results with different proposals will
help us to identify the most beneficial proposal for above scenario,
declared in Conclusion section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, after each attack, test the virtual server environment is
restarted, because of the affective situation that server after attack
needs time to recover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;METHODS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of requirements of our scenario we need to limit the internet
connection of 2 Mbit/s and to provide graphs that can help as with the
measurement results to conclude which proposals is more competent.
Therefore, Method 1 is describing the step how we limited the connection
bandwidth and Method 2 providing as solution how to setup that can help
you in measuring the speed and the bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;METHOD 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For limiting the internet traffic of the server we have to do the
following steps in command prompt. The following solution is gathered
from Manual of Oracle Virtualbox, Chapter 8 [User Manual].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Limiting VirtualBox – virtual environment speed of network interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    VBoxManage modifyvm "[name of virtualbox]" --nicspeed2 2048

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where you need to replace name of virtual box with real one, and specie
which network interface adapter you wont to limited. In the above
illustration is only second network adapter affected and then you set
the limitation, in our case is 2 Mbit/s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, to make sure that the result have been effective please use
the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    VBoxManage showvminfo "[name of virtualbox]"

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Results and information important to be aware refer to Appendix 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;METHOD 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are going to install an application that will help us to gather a
visual graphs of traffic manipulation of script kiddie. The application
is vnstat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the server virtual environment in command prompt please type the
following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    sudo apt-get install vnstat&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next step is to select which interface should be monitored and create
graphs. In our case is eth1, which is second network interface. For
furthermore detailed installation process please refer to the following
link:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.4geeksfromnet.com/2009/04/graphical-bandwidth-monitor-for-ubuntu.html"&gt;http://www.4geeksfromnet.com/2009/04/graphical-bandwidth-monitor-for-ubuntu.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To check if the installation process is finished please use your
browser, as shown in illustration 1 and on the address bar type:
http://192.168.56.102/vnstat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration 1: Vnstat PHP interface&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;PROPOSALS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three proposals are following and described in each different
section and their results. The main measure goal which is going to grate
for kiddie script is: easy to use instructions, the most efficient use
of available resources and can the script be up to 1 day attacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the results will be provided with two different graphs in
period of 5 minutes attack and 10 minutes attack. Which would guide us
to compare which kiddie script has performed the attack more in force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;PROPOSAL 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first proposal and the installation process instruction:
Script kiddie uses a little program to connection flood the WordPress
installation! The program uses Apache autobench to take the site down in
seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guide for the scipt Kiddie:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download the program from
    &lt;a href="http://enos.itcollege.ee/~avein/anti2.rar"&gt;http://enos.itcollege.ee/~avein/anti2.rar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unpack and run AntiXakkerv2.0.exe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the address for wordpress site and press the button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above script did no run/work on the VirtualMachine Windows XP.
Therefore, from the same author we have other solution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​1. Download
&lt;a href="http://enos.itcollege.ee/%7Eavein/anti.exe"&gt;http://enos.itcollege.ee/\~avein/anti.exe&lt;/a&gt;,
save it on Desktop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​2. Open Start menu, select run and type “cmd” into the box and press
enter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​3. Drag anti.exe file to the black box (commandline) , select the box
and type the address of your server ( eg. www.delfi.ee ) after the
anti.exe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if the address for your webserver is 192.168.56.101 type
the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    anti.exe 192.168.56.101&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press enter and the site will go down very soon :=) P.S. This is
    lightweight version tat doesnot use much bandwith and is targeted
    against a bug in apache server :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;RESULT 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After running the first proposal we can see that the script kiddie does
attack the server, but the server was reachable after a bit long delay,
but still we could access to the wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some results graphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 minutes attack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration 2: Proposal 1, 5 min, traffic graph&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 minutes attack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration 3: Proposal 1, 10 min, traffic graph&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the one hand the script kiddie did attack the server, but on the
other hand the server was still accessible. I’d like to conclude by
stating that the above script did not meet our needs, and it did not
stop, bring down the response time of the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;PROPOSAL 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second proposal and the installation process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You (Script kiddie) download the file from &lt;a href="http://share.ee/x49176f"&gt;http://share.ee/x49176f&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will get an warning message, but you continue to download anyway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In chrome it looks like this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Execute the file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will get a warning but continue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will look something like this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insert the URL to attack and define how long you want to attack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will look like&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enjoy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The script is basic vbscript that will overwhelm the server by as many
connections that are required to keep the server down for as long as you
define.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above script did not work on the laboratory performance, because it
had an code error. Therefore, for this proposal we are not able to
provide you with the result graphs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;PROPOSAL 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third proposal and the installation process is listed below: There is a
free and very easy Denial of service script written in PHP, called
Keep-Dead (Version 1.14). You can download it from the following link:
&lt;a href="http://www.esrun.co.uk/blog/imp/2011/03/Keep-Dead.zip"&gt;http://www.esrun.co.uk/blog/imp/2011/03/Keep-Dead.zip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is developed for a research purpose, but still we can use it for our
scenario. The good think is primarily meant for use via the terminal;
although it will also work if launched via the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unpack the Keep-Dead.zip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open in notepad or any other text/script editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On line #26 change the
    &lt;code&gt;$target_url = “http://www.example.com/wordpress/?s=%rand%”;&lt;/code&gt; to our
    targeted wordpress blog. We can stop even certain page or post in
    wordpres or use of &lt;code&gt;%rand%&lt;/code&gt; for a random value to be automatically
    generated for each individual request • You can change the maximum
    number of requests to be made on line #32&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changeable is maximum number of requests to be made per connection
    #37, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After setting the setting of our needs save the file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And in terminal you need to run the following script:
    &lt;code&gt;php –e keep-dead.php&lt;/code&gt; or if you run a xamp or other webserver it is
    possible to run the script from your browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can terminate the script by pressing CTRL+C in terminal console
    or stop/close the browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information or video tutorials please refer to the following
link: &lt;a href="http://www.esrun.co.uk/blog/keep-alive-dos-script/"&gt;http://www.esrun.co.uk/blog/keep-alive-dos-script/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we follow the above steps we can perform our scenario 3 to make the
server to stay down for two days or even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There many ways to keep the server down for two days, this script for me
is kind of easy usable. In addition, the author had provide and more
details with following content: In addition of my proposal pls install
the following script:
&lt;a href="http://windows.php.net/downloads/releases/php-5.3.8-nts-Win32-VC9-x86.msi"&gt;http://windows.php.net/downloads/releases/php-5.3.8-nts-Win32-VC9-x86.msi&lt;/a&gt;
in the installation process in the section of Select Web Server you wish
to setup please chose Do not setup a web server -&gt; Next click on the
PHP small narrow down icon and select Entire future will be installed on
local hard drive (second option) -&gt; Next -&gt;Install&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results and graphs of the above proposal are demonstrated in the
next section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the script that actually does the job and it keeps the server
down until the script is down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;RESULT 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test results are following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​1. 5 minutes attack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration 4: Proposal 3, 5 min, traffic graph&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 minutes attack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration 5: Proposal 3, 10 min, traffic graph&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A case in point is that from the above graphs we can see that the server
does get more traffic and it does get attacked by the script kiddie.
Illustration 6, bellow demonstrated that actually the server is down, is
not responding any more to requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration 6: Proposal 3, server down after trying to reach the blog&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three points that we should consider and to see which proposal
was more accurate and it did the job that was required in the scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I would like to start with rating from 1 to 5 each proposal.
Higher score present better results. Which is proving our destination to
hold down the server for longer then one day. The bellow table
demonstrates which proposal has succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;th&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;th align="center"&gt;
Proposal 1

&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;th align="center"&gt;
Proposal 2

&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;th align="right"&gt;
Proposal 3

&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
Easy installation

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
5

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
5

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
4

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
Server down

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
3

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
1

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
5

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
TOTAL

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
8

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
6

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
9

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the scoring rate 3 of server down is means that the server was down,
but after few seconds was retrievable. Where the highest score 5 means
that the server was not retrievable during this proposal test until we
shutdown or cancel the process of script kiddie. In addition, the
Proposal 3 due to a code error was not able to perform attack, that is
why it is graded with server down score of 1. Therefore, our winner for
this laboratory test is Proposal 3 with script kiddie Keep-dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next issue that I would like to focus is to the network speed,
tested with other tool bmon2 which manifests that the speed limit of the
bandwidth did not go over the 2 Mbit/s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the above proposals are nice and good example to have an
view of how and with what tools we should perform script kiddie
techniques. How to shutdown access to a server. On the whole, it show as
how to use tools and methods of measuring the bandwidth of network and
how to limit the transfer in comfortable way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;APPENDIXES&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appendix 1 is connected with the Method 1, which highlighted points are
illustration on what information we should check, to clarify that the
virtual environment has limitation of the network interface. Where
Appendix 2 is for installation process of Ubuntu Server 10.04 LTS and
wordpress, mysql installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;APPENDIX 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    Name: ubuntu-serverGuest OS: UbuntuUUID: fe16451a-f8b1-4ceb-bb90-8650d08c3c0eConfig file: C:\Users\predrag\Documents\Master_CyberSecurity\VirtualBox VMs\ubuntu-server\ubuntu-server.vboxSnapshot folder: C:\Users\predrag\Documents\Master_CyberSecurity\VirtualBox VMs\ubuntu-server\SnapshotsLog folder: C:\Users\predrag\Documents\Master_CyberSecurity\VirtualBox VMs\ubuntu-server\LogsHardware UUID: fe16451a-f8b1-4ceb-bb90-8650d08c3c0eMemory size: 512MBPage Fusion: offVRAM size: 12MBCPU exec cap: 100%HPET: offChipset: piix3Firmware: BIOSNumber of CPUs: 1Synthetic Cpu: offCPUID overrides: NoneBoot menu mode: message and menuBoot Device (1): FloppyBoot Device (2): DVDBoot Device (3): HardDiskBoot Device (4): Not AssignedACPI: onIOAPIC: offPAE: offTime offset: 0 msRTC: UTCHardw. virt.ext: onHardw. virt.ext exclusive: offNested Paging: onLarge Pages: onVT-x VPID: onState: running (since 2011-10-11T11:26:30.089000000)Monitor count: 13D Acceleration: off2D Video Acceleration: offTeleporter Enabled: offTeleporter Port: 0Teleporter Address:Teleporter Password:Storage Controller Name (0): IDE ControllerStorage Controller Type (0): PIIX4Storage Controller Instance Number (0): 0Storage Controller Max Port Count (0): 2Storage Controller Port Count (0): 2Storage Controller Bootable (0): onStorage Controller Name (1): SATA ControllerStorage Controller Type (1): IntelAhciStorage Controller Instance Number (1): 0Storage Controller Max Port Count (1): 30Storage Controller Port Count (1): 1Storage Controller Bootable (1): onSATA Controller (0, 0): C:\Users\predrag\Documents\Master_CyberSecurity\VirtualBox VMs\ubuntu-server\ubuntu-server.vdi (UUID: bf4c167a-ec0a-42fa-915f-2ffbe2fd66fb) NIC 1: MAC: 0800274572ED, Attachment: NAT, Cable connected: on, Trace:off (file: none), Type: 82540EM, &lt;span style="color: #ff0000;"&gt;Reported speed: 2 Mbps&lt;/span&gt;, Boot priority: 0, Promisc Policy: denyNIC 1 Settings: MTU: 0, Socket (send: 64, receive: 64), TCP Window (send:64, receive: 64) NIC 2: MAC: 0800270858EA, Attachment: Host-only Interface 'VirtualBoxHost-Only Ethernet Adapter', Cable connected: on, Trace: off (file: none), Type:82540EM, Reported speed: 2 Mbps , Boot priority: 0, Promisc Policy: denyNIC 3: disabledNIC 4: disabledNIC 5: disabledNIC 6: disabledNIC 7: disabledNIC 8: disabledPointing Device: USB TabletKeyboard Device: PS/2 KeyboardUART 1: disabledUART 2: disabledAudio: enabled (Driver: DSOUND, Controller: AC97)Clipboard Mode: BidirectionalVideo mode: 640x480x0VRDE: disabledUSB: enabledUSB Device Filters: &amp;lt;none&amp;gt;Available remote USB devices: &amp;lt;none&amp;gt;Currently Attached USB Devices: &amp;lt;none&amp;gt;Shared folders: &amp;lt;none&amp;gt;VRDE Connection: not activeClients so far: 0Guest: Configured memory balloon size: 0 MBOS type: UbuntuAdditions run level: 0Guest Facilities: No active facilities.

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;APPENDIX 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation media: Ubuntu 10.04 LTS 32bit iso image;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HW: Virtualbox, 1CPU 32bit, 512MB RAM, 8GB HD (dynamic allocation);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC1 NAT;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC2 host only (for ssh and http access from host);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language used in installation process: English and country Estonia;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyboard Layout English;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hostname: pece&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partition methods: Guided, use entire disk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username: pece&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no http proxy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sudo apt-get install lamp phpmyadmin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wget -c http://wordpress.org/latest.tar.gz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tar xvjf latest.tar.gz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sudo cp wordpress /var/www/wordpress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sudo nano /var/www/wordpress/wp-config.php Change the settings to
    your needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Script kiddie: Wikipedia, Script Kiddie, October 2011,
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Script_kiddie"&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Script_kiddie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User Manual: Oracle Corporation, User Manual, 2004-2011,
&lt;a href="http://www.virtualbox.org/manual/ch08.html"&gt;http://www.virtualbox.org/manual/ch08.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Footnotes:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] vnstat – &lt;a href="http://humdi.net/vnstat/"&gt;http://humdi.net/vnstat/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] Bmon – &lt;a href="http://www.infradead.org/~tgr/bmon/"&gt;http://www.infradead.org/~tgr/bmon/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="attacks"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="DDoS"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="script kiddie"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="server attack"></category><category term="wordpress attack"></category></entry><entry><title>Cost of DDoS, leak of credit card numbers, infected machine and spam</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2011/10/cost-of-ddos-leak-of-credit-card-numbers-infected-machine-and-spam/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-10-12T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2011-10-12T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2011-10-12:/posts/2011/10/cost-of-ddos-leak-of-credit-card-numbers-infected-machine-and-spam/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;PURPOSE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main goal of laboratory report is to identify the costs of nowadays
most known attack  DDOS, leak of credit card numbers, infected machine
and never the less sending spam for 1 000 000 (one million) people.
There are few points that should be presented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where did we discovered …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;PURPOSE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main goal of laboratory report is to identify the costs of nowadays
most known attack  DDOS, leak of credit card numbers, infected machine
and never the less sending spam for 1 000 000 (one million) people.
There are few points that should be presented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where did we discovered the information (links or sources)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What kind of source of communication we used, for instance: instant
    messing, ICQ, IRC, which contact we have gather the information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the prices for the above attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, we must bear in mind that collecting the above information
it is presented to a numerous affected sources ( i.e. Website, news,
forums, IRC chat,etc.). By visiting the source can lead you to a virus,
trojan, malicious code, malware, etc. Which can damage your system.
Therefore, we are going to use virtual environment to find our demands.
In addition, we will use different languages and different search
engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Construction of report is separated by tasks section. Where each section
is presented with the source, communication type and the costs of the
service. In addition, in Appendix 1 we give the configuration of virtual
environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally the conclusion made of all collected data will be concise in
conclusion section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;TASKS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following list is the numeration of the tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DDoS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Credit Card Numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Infected Machines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spam for 1 000 000 people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;TASK 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source where we can find information about the cost of DDoS attacks are
provided in Russian most known [Hackzone] forum. This is the source will
give as more of the answers. But again be careful when you accessing
this site. It is on your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the following link we received an information about DDoS
attacks: [HackzoneDDoS]. With the following translated statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    The average price of service from $ 50 per day. Depends on the complexity of the &lt;em&gt;attacked site. Methods of payment accepted via WebMoney. The network is practically around the clock!Commands:http / https / icmp / post / syn / udp /Price:Day from $ 50Week from $ 350From $ 1200 per month(Prices may change depending of type and timing of orders on the complexity of the attacked site)Demo test for 5-10 minutes.Contact:Icq :20-**-29Inspections completed:hack-world.orgwww.xaker.nameforum.xaknet.ruMost of the DDoS attack service are around per day $ 50, here is an other source and contact details:Contact details Icq:22-**-327Icq:875-**3E-mail:anti**os@jab**r.ru

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above information is from the following link:
&lt;a href="http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/15608/"&gt;http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/15608/&lt;/a&gt;. Other sources that can be
found are with&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the following links: &lt;a href="http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/16067/"&gt;http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/16067/&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/17187/"&gt;http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/17187/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we stated above that the price is from \$50 per day and it goes until
\$350 per month and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;TASK 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of credit cards leaked in the web are numerous amount. The
prices are not that high as people expected. For card that comes from
European country is the highest price and for the other are much
cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here some information from the following link, leak from &lt;a href="http://www.hackzone.ru/memb/view/name/Support_BM/"&gt;Support_BM
Originar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source is in Russian language, so for this report is translated to
English. From the source [CartNumber].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    At the moment there is only us, ca, cvv.Databases are updated every 2-3 days, Walid varies from 75 to 90%.Price:us visa, mc cvv = $ 1.5us amex, diss = $ 1.5us without vbv \ mksk = $ 2us not tied and PayPal = $ 2EU = $ 6-9World = $ 3-6CIS is not and never will.Sorted by: bean = $ 1Sample on any other criterion = +0.5 $Sampling only on the following criteria: bin, judge, state, city, type, zip.WARNING! I do not select “No vbv”, “No attachment to the paypal”, “Give me a map that would be held there now and then.”Terms and conditions of service provision:1. Replacement non valid within 48 hours of purchase.2. I only 04/05/51 Declined, Hold-Call, check only CCN + EXP + CVV3. On messages such as “Here?” “Hi, how are” probably will not answer.4. Money Beg do not.5. Do not change the board, check it before selling.6. I believe only their own way, proven in battle, checker, so your results, another checker,&amp;nbsp;and so do not pay attention.7. Using my service, you automatically agree with everything stated in this post.8. Reserve the right to refuse service to anyone, without explanation.9. I am not responsible for the account balances card-holders.10. I do not give advice on the use of the material.11. Do not keep a bazaar talks about the reductions.12. I do not care where you do not go away if you gave Checker Walid Walid means.Card format:Credit Card Number | CVV2 | ??Exp.date | Name | Address Line | City | State | Zip Code |Country | Phone (Not Always) | Email Address (not always)Attention! Before you knock a replacement non valid, make sure that all the provided maps not valid if none of these cards will be found a valid card and a replacement will be denied.Learn to appreciate their own and other people’s time, get a checker, and live happily ever after.Contact the seller checker can provide for everyone.I accept payment only WMZ and LibertyReserveMy WMID has 70BL, as well as on-demand in icq give links to many reviews.Contact:ICQ: 604000**0JID: ***nager@thes**ure.bizPosted 13.10.2010 13:45:51 (8 days 18 hours 31 minutes 59 seconds)Other source that cross is from Russian banks Alfa debit or others the price from$175. Source is published by contact details: Jabber: v**yt@exp**it.im, ICQ: 25**165,Skype: V**yt_. On the following link:&lt;a href="http://lab-one.net/showthread.php?t=664" target="_blank"&gt; http://lab-one.net/showthread.php?t=664&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;TASK 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays it is not hard to find an infected machine/computer. Because
most of the user PC’s are based with operating system Windows and are
most of them infected. I have try so hard to find infected machine
price, but until today, I did not come up with any good source.
Therefore, I would like if it is possible to add this source and discuss
this source and information with the fellow students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;TASK 4&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spamming for one million people it sounds impossible, but still out
there someone is offering this service. Here is from Kazakhstan source
with the following information, translated in English:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    E-mail newsletter:1 post = 1 m., minimum order 10 000 posts.For large orders – big discounts!At present there is action: 10 000 tenge, we send 20 000 messages. + Action: 50 000 tenge, we send your letter to 360 000 email ardesov in Almaty, send 3 times in one month!The action is over, send a time.E-mail database:In Almaty:60 000 LEGAL Address – Almaty Yuredicheskie email addresses, the entire directory guide “our town” and directory site “Samruk Kazyna”430 000 – private address Almaty residents collected via mail search agent criteria:country, city, gender, age.Throughout Kazakhstan:240 000 – LEGAL person Kazakhstan LLP, Ltd., Inc., Ltd., etc. collected from various references such as “yellow pages” “compass” etc.3.4 million – individuals, all of Kazakhstan. – Collected through the mail search agent criteria: country, city, gender, age.P.S. you can build a base of email addresses to any city in Kazakhstan, or any other city in any other country, can you give us the criteria and we will collect your base, an example of criteria:I try, the city, Age, sex, online, not online.P.S. Legal mailings are engaged for 3 years, dispatching more than 5 years.To Order: +7-701-1**5575, +7 (727) -329-61-**.E-mail: d**z@i**ox.ru

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, for 10 000 KZT = 67.45 USD and the amount of message send are 20
000 spam. Then the price for one million spam is 3.372.5 USD without
discount. The above links is from the following source [Rassilka.kz].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to generalize that from the above information we see that
for any service that we looked for, it has a price. Value that are
different in other countries and currencies. Yet, before you start this
research make sure that you are not using your local machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, I have used an virtual environment to be able to collect all
the above data. Because the sites, forums, links, etc. are infected with
malicious code, or can be easily traceable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, we utter gather as much as possible different sources and
different prices. Most expensive is the spam for one million people,
second is DDoS attacks and never the last is to gain an credit card
numbers from different countries and different price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more info please refer to following source [QuinStreet Inc] why I
have chose Russia as the main source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;APPENDIX&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appendix 1 is configuration of the virtual environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;APPENDIX 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virtual environment: Oracle VirtualBox Version 4.1.2 r73507.
Downloadable from the following link:
https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Downloads&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security Fedora 14 32 bit – Client:
http://spins.fedoraproject.org/security/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Base Memory: 512 MB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acceleration: VT-x/AMD-V, Nested Paging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Display – Video memory: 12 MB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage: SATA Controller, Port 0: 8 GB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adapter 1: Adapter 1: Parvirtualized Network (NAT)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adapter 2: Adapter 2: Inter PRO/1000 MT Desktop (Host-only
    adapter, „VirtualBox Host- Only Enternet Adapter“)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hackzone: HackZone.ru, Forum, 2011, &lt;a href="http://www.hackzone.ru/"&gt;http://www.hackzone.ru/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HackzoneDDoS: Master_DDoS, Качественный DDoS Сервис,
&lt;a href="http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/17387/"&gt;http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/17387/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CartNumber: Support_BM, Качественный US\EU\WORLD картон, 2011,
&lt;a href="http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/14936/"&gt;http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/14936/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rassilka.kz: kamondimon, E-mail рассылки!, 2011,
&lt;a href="http://rassilka.kz/rassilki-rassilka-kz/47-e-mailrassylki.html"&gt;http://rassilka.kz/rassilki-rassilka-kz/47-e-mailrassylki.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QuinStreet Inc: Paul Rubens, Understanding the Russian Hacker
Underground, Aug 13, 2010,
&lt;a href="http://www.enterprisenetworkingplanet.com/netsecur/article.php/3898601/Understanding-the-Russian-Hacker-Underground.htm"&gt;http://www.enterprisenetworkingplanet.com/netsecur/article.php/3898601/Understanding-the-Russian-Hacker-Underground.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="acceleration"></category><category term="optamization"></category><category term="simmulation of attacks and defence"></category><category term="wordpress attacks"></category><category term="credit card numbers"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="DDoS"></category><category term="defence"></category><category term="infected machine"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="malware"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="online"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="spam"></category></entry><entry><title>Future of human communication</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2011/06/future-of-human-communication/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-06-26T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2011-06-26T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2011-06-26:/posts/2011/06/future-of-human-communication/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;On the basis of how the communication possibilities have changed (for) most people during last decades, what’s my idea of the normal human interaction in 10..20…50 years?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand the present we must first understand the past. The
Internet has revolutionized the computer and communications world like …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;On the basis of how the communication possibilities have changed (for) most people during last decades, what’s my idea of the normal human interaction in 10..20…50 years?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand the present we must first understand the past. The
Internet has revolutionized the computer and communications world like
nothing before. The invention of the telegraph, telephone, radio, and
computer set the stage for this unprecedented integration of
capabilities. The Internet is at once a world-wide broadcasting
capability, a mechanism for information dissemination, and a medium for
collaboration and interaction between individuals and their computers
without regard for geographic location.&lt;span id="more-113"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet represents one of the most successful examples of the
benefits of sustained investment and commitment to research and
development of information infrastructure. Beginning with the early
research in packet switching, the government, industry and academia have
been partners in evolving and deploying this exciting new technology
(Barry M. , et al., 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet today is a widespread information infrastructure, the
initial prototype of what is often called the National (or Global or
Galactic) Information Infrastructure. Its history is complex and
involves many aspects – technological, organizational, and community.
And its influence reaches not only to the technical fields of computer
communications but throughout society as we move toward increasing use
of online tools to accomplish electronic commerce, information
acquisition, and community operations(Barry M. , et al., 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likelihood, computers have changed the face of communication to an
extent that we can’t consider our routine life without presence of these
machines. With the availability of technologies like internet, instant
messaging, emailing and others, the computers has fast replaced
conventional means of communicating with each other(Communication Type,
2008).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one writes letter anymore. It’s been said that longhand or cursive is
no longer taught in grade school. No need for it. People don’t write
anymore. As technology defined the late Twentieth Century, we became
both closer together and further apart. People had more time for an
online chat via the fast growing Internet than they did for a day at the
park with a dear friend. That was bad. On the other hand, we connected
to people all over the world that we might not otherwise get to enjoy.
Today, computer technology constantly changes the way we communicate
(Friends of Time, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we look through the history of computer communication from 1968 to
nowadays there are three unique market sectors: Data Communication,
Networking and Internet (Internetworking). Data communication is an
electronic transmission of information that has been encoded digitally
(as for storage and processing by computers). Computer Networking is an
interconnection of various computer systems located at different places.
In computer network two or more computers are linked together with a
medium and data communication devices for the purpose of communicating
data and sharing resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Internet is a network of networks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Millions of computers all over the world are connected through the
Internet. Computer users on the Internet can contact one another
anywhere in the world. If your computer is connected to the Internet,
you can connect to millions of computers. You can gather information and
distribute your data. It is very much similar to the telephone
connection where you can talk with any person anywhere in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As digital media takes flight, the grand slam of computer communication
has arrived. Skype . It’s free, it’s live, and it’s real face time. Not
only can people talk, but they can see each other as they talk. There
are even Skype and “skype-like” apps for Smartphones. To an extent,
communication has a more human feel again. People can see friends and
family a world away and keep very close contact. And leave it to
teenagers to figure out how to make Skype the new bedroom powwow.
Teenagers simply turn it on and hang out. They may not even be talking
to each other, but they know the other person is there (Friends of Time,
2011). With a free access of the Internet though the wireless local area
network (WLAN 1) we can chat and talk with anyone from anywhere, without
the consideration of graphical location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet and computers are offering a wide range of communication
influence. We can communicate to text messages to your friends through
computers and communication tools provided by it. From emails and
newsletters to text chats and instant messaging, micro-blogging,
computers can help you to reach your friends, relatives, business
associates and others in the matter of few seconds. Communication tools
to communicate your voice messages without facing the geographical
restrictions. Voice mails and voice chats, brought revolutionary changes
how have computers changed the way we communicate. Business
communication with the help of audio and video conferencing. The
executives of different branches of a company, located in different
geographical locations, can communicate with each other and distances
can pose no hurdles in establishing these communication systems. Other
influence of computer communication are helping and proving the
education system of offering a distant learning, gaining a degree
without being at the university location, etc. One of the popular
concepts in nowadays communication is online social networking, instance
of communication, joining different online clubs and communicates with
individuals from various parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, imagine a day without computer in your room or on the
office desk. For instance no emails, no chatting, no instant messaging
and no web camera interactions, how we are going to feel? Therefore, we
all can understand how computers have changed the way we communicate.
Life can come to a standstill without computers and similar devices
around us. Consequently, communication through computers is an important
aspect of every individual today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part of communicating through computer and Internet is that you
can practice it from any part of the world. All computer technology is
wonderful and the more access to communication the better. But it will
be a shame if the world becomes so shrouded in technology that good old
fashioned face to face people skills become a rare art instead of an
everyday norm.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, all the above describes how the computers changed the way we
communicate. This is because computers have become great contributors
towards the world of communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Reference&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barry M. , L., Vinton G. , C., David D. , C., Robert E. , K., Leonard ,
K., Daniel C. , L., et al. (2011). A Brief History of the Internet.
Retrieved from Internet Society (ISOC):
&lt;a href="http://www.isoc.org/internet/history/brief.shtml"&gt;http://www.isoc.org/internet/history/brief.shtml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication Type. (2008, October 29). Computers and Communication –
Technology Giving Way to Technology. Retrieved from Communication Type:
&lt;a href="http://www.communication-type.com/computers-and-communication-%E2%80%93-technology-giving-way-to-technology/"&gt;http://www.communication-type.com/computers-and-communication-%E2%80%93-technology-giving-way-to-technology/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friends of Time. (2011). Computer Technology Constantly Changes the Way
We Communicate. Retrieved from Friends of Time:
&lt;a href="http://friendsoftime.org/computer-technology-constantly-changes-the-way-we-communicate.html"&gt;http://friendsoftime.org/computer-technology-constantly-changes-the-way-we-communicate.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Footnote:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] WLAN: a local area network that uses high frequency radio signals to
transmit and receive data over distances of a few hundred feet; uses
Ethernet protocol&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="communication"></category><category term="future of human communication"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="networking"></category><category term="online"></category></entry><entry><title>Digital divide or not?</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2011/06/digital-divide-or-not/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-06-19T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2011-06-19T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2011-06-19:/posts/2011/06/digital-divide-or-not/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Digital divide or not?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there a psychological “digital divide”? Are people who often use the
Internet psychologically different from those who do not and in what
ways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet is changing the average citizens as much as did other
technologies, for instance: telephone, TV, computers, mobile phones etc.
The …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Digital divide or not?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there a psychological “digital divide”? Are people who often use the
Internet psychologically different from those who do not and in what
ways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet is changing the average citizens as much as did other
technologies, for instance: telephone, TV, computers, mobile phones etc.
The mainly province was to help the science, engineering, and business.
Many scholars, technologists, and social critics believe that these
changes and the Internet, in particular, are transforming economic and
social life (Robert , Micheal, Vicki, Sara, Tridas , &amp;amp; William , 1998).
In the past few years, the scholars have done many researches to make a
conclusion of difference in psychological and social tend of the
Internet to the citizens. Therefore, the term “digital divide” is the
gap that exists between those who have access to electronic and
Information Technology – Internet and those who do not (University of
Minnesota Duluth, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People use home computers and the Internet in many different ways and
for many purposes, including entertainment, education, information
retrieval, and communication. If people use the Internet mainly for
communication with others through e-mail, distribution lists, multiuser
dungeons, chats, and many other instant or voice messenger applications,
they might do so to augment traditional technologies of social contact,
expanding their number of friends and reducing the difficulty of
coordinating interaction with them. On the other hand, these
applications disproportionately reduce the costs of communication with
geographically distant acquaintances and strangers; as a result, a
smaller proportion of people’s total social contacts might be with
family and close friends. Yet other applications on the Internet,
particularly the World Wide Web, provide asocial entertainment that
could compete with social contact as a way for people to spend their
time (Robert et al., 1998).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, since the primary use of the Internet is communication,
some people might speculate that the Internet will have positive social
consequences in people’s everyday lives because it increases the
frequency and quality of interpersonal communications among people.
People with easy access to others would feel better connected and more
strongly supported by others, leading to happiness and engagement in
families, organizations, communities, and society more generally
(Nikolovska, 2007).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, on the other hand, the ease of electronic communication may lead to
weaker social ties, because people have less reason to leave their homes
and actually interact face to face with other people. The Internet
allows people to more easily work from their home, to form and sustain
friendships and even romantic attachments from their home, to bank from
their home, to vote and engage in political and social issue based
discussions with others (from home) (Nikolovska, 2007).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with watching television and using a home computer and the Internet
generally imply physical inactivity and limited face-to-face social
interaction. Some studies, including our own, have indicated that using
a home computer and the Internet can lead to increased skills and
confidence with computers (Lundmark, Kiesler, Kraut, Scherlis, &amp;amp;
Mukhopadhyay, 1998). However, when people use these technologies
intensively for learning new software, playing computer games, or
retrieving electronic information, they consume time and may spend more
time alone (Vitalari, Venkatesh, &amp;amp; Gronhaug, 1985). Some cross-sectional
research suggests that home computing may be displacing television
watching itself (Danko, W. D. &amp;amp; MacLachlan, J. M, 1983), (Kohut, 1994)
as well as reducing leisure time with the family (Vitalari et al.,
1985).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this variety of ways, Internet communications can potentially
displace face-to-face communications. This point is important because
psychologists in many researches have described and proved such face to
face and telephone connections as being of higher quality, when viewed
in terms of their contribution to satisfaction and
well-being(Nikolovska, 2007).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Question that rise is while our culture heralds the Internet as a
technological wonder; there are suggestions that Internet use has a
negative influence on individuals and their social skills. A recent
study conducted by Carnegie Mellon University concludes that Internet
use leads to small but statistically significant increases in misery and
loneliness and a decline in overall psychological
well-being(Association, American Psychological, 1998). The appropriately
named HomeNetproject studied a sample of 169 people in Pittsburg during
their first year or two online. Data showed that as people in this
sample used the Internet more, they reported keeping up with fewer
friends. They also reported spending less time talking with their
families, experiencing more daily stress, and feeling more lonely and
depressed. These results occurred even though interpersonal
communication was their most important reason for using the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Katz and Aspden’s national survey (1997) is one of the few empirical
studies that have compared the social participation of Internet users
with nonusers. Controlling statistically for education, race, and other
demographic variables, these researchers found no differences between
Internet users’ and nonusers’ memberships in religious, leisure, and
community organizations or in the amount of time users and nonusers
reported spending communicating with family and friends. From these
data, Katz and Aspden concluded that “[f]ar from creating a nation of
strangers, the Internet is creating a nation richer in friendships and
social relationships” (p. 86)(Robert et al., 1998).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the percentage of usage of the technology nowadays
drastically enhanced. Such as the state/country statistics of
information society reports during pass few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parallel between two countries with a similarity of population number:
Estonia and Macedonia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estonia since 2000 had 366,600 connected citizens though Internet.
However, in 2010 the statistic report’s the rapidly changes with the
number of 969,700 connections (Miniwatts Marketing Group., 2010). Yet
the statistic in Macedonia shows since 2000 the users that were
connected are 30,000, where in 2010 the number swiftly has change,
1,057,400 users in the country were connected though Internet. Thus, the
statistic shows that 75,1% of citizens in Estonia has access to
Internet, analogous to Macedonia 51% of population of the country in
final report of 2010 (Miniwatts Marketing Group, 2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, from the statistic we can see that, most of the population
nowadays has a computer, laptop, or device in their pocket that can
connect on Internet. Despite the alarm, research indicates most children
are doing fine. Computers are certainly intriguing and captivating, and
the Internet is most assuredly alluring with its research and
communicative capacities. But overall, technology can be considered a
positive enhancement to growth(Affonso, 1999). This feature is
eloquently affirmed by author Don Tapscott (Tapscott, 1999):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“… when kids are online, they’re reading, thinking, analyzing,
criticizing and authenticating – composing their thoughts. Kids use
computers for activities that go hand-in-hand with our understanding of
what constitutes a traditional childhood. They use the technology to
play, learn, communicate and form relationships as children always have.
Development is enhanced in an interactive world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the above the influence of the Internet has caused a change in the
way we communicate, study, shop, etc. The most famous for the ability to
spread information, to communicate from a distance with a web camera,
etc. it is the Internet. But this communication revolution changed the
pure nature of interpersonal and group processes. We should be able to
see the difference between the qualities of face-to-face communication
that influence the impact of communication on people and their social
interaction. Moreover, should we be able to predict the probable
influence of any new communication technology. Nevertheless, the
researchers show that people sooner or later convert their cyber
contacts into more traditional face-to-face, as most of us do. People
use the Internet, in other words to help them achieve their real-life
goals. And rather than technology’s changing people’s social and
psychological reality, in other words, people change their use of
technology to facilitate their creation of a desired social reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Reference&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Affonso, B. (1999, December). Is the Internet Affecting the Social
Skills of Our Children? Retrieved from Sierra Source Web Design:
&lt;a href="http://www.sierrasource.com/cep612/internet.html"&gt;http://www.sierrasource.com/cep612/internet.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Association, American Psychological. (1998). Internet paradox — a social
technology that reduces social involvement and psychological well-being?
American Psychologist,53, 1017-1031.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Danko, W. D., &amp;amp; MacLachlan, J. M. (1983). Research to accelerate the
diffusion of a new invention. Journal of Advertising Research,
23(3),39-43.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kohut, A. (1994). The role of technology in American life. Los Angeles:
Times Mirror Center for the People and the Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lundmark, V., Kiesler, S., Kraut, R., Scherlis, W., &amp;amp; Mukhopadhyay, T.
(1998). How the strong survive: Patterns and significance of competence.
Unpublished manuscript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miniwatts Marketing Group. (2010). Macedonia Internet Usage and
Telecommunications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retrieved from Internet Usage and Telecommunications:
&lt;a href="http://www.internetworldstats.com/eu/mk.htm"&gt;http://www.internetworldstats.com/eu/mk.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miniwatts Marketing Group. (2010). Internet Usage Stats and Market
Report – Estonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retrieved from Internet World Statistic:
&lt;a href="http://www.internetworldstats.com/eu/ee.htm"&gt;http://www.internetworldstats.com/eu/ee.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nikolovska, M. (2007, April). The Influence Of The Internet On People’s
Social And Psychological Realities. Retrieved from EzineArticles.com:
&lt;a href="http://ezinearticles.com/?The-Influence-Of-The-Internet-On-Peoples-Social-And-Psychological-Realities&amp;amp;id=524319"&gt;http://ezinearticles.com/?The-Influence-Of-The-Internet-On-Peoples-Social-And-Psychological-Realities&amp;amp;id=524319&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robert , K., Micheal, P., Vicki, L., Sara, K., Tridas , M., &amp;amp; William ,
S. (1998). Internet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paradox. Washington, DC: American Psychological Association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tapscott, D. (1999). The kids are alright: technology doesn’t make them
‘little criminals’. Retrieved from Victoria Point Multimedia:
&lt;a href="http://www.victoriapoint.com/child_technology.htm"&gt;http://www.victoriapoint.com/child_technology.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;University of Minnesota Duluth. (2011, 04 04). Web Design References:
Glossary. Retrieved from Information Technology Systems &amp;amp; Services:
&lt;a href="http://www.d.umn.edu/itss/support/Training/Online/webdesign/glossary/d.html"&gt;http://www.d.umn.edu/itss/support/Training/Online/webdesign/glossary/d.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitalari, N., Venkatesh, A., &amp;amp; Gronhaug, K. (1985). Computing in the
home: Shifts in the time allocation patterns of households.
Communications of the ACM, 28(5), 512-522.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="digital divide"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="net generation"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="network generation"></category><category term="online"></category><category term="online generations"></category><category term="psychological"></category></entry><entry><title>Internet and collectivistic cultures</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2011/06/internet-and-collectivistic-cultures/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-06-06T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2011-06-06T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2011-06-06:/posts/2011/06/internet-and-collectivistic-cultures/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Internet and collectivistic cultures. How the Internet affects the psyche of the people from collectivistic cultures?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays everyone has a computer at home, work and even a carrying
device, example: laptop, notebook, mobile phones, IPod etc. All the
devices that are making our life easy in everyday tasks are able …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Internet and collectivistic cultures. How the Internet affects the psyche of the people from collectivistic cultures?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays everyone has a computer at home, work and even a carrying
device, example: laptop, notebook, mobile phones, IPod etc. All the
devices that are making our life easy in everyday tasks are able to
connect though the Internet. Which affects our psyche and people around.
It not only influences the thoughts, behavior and personality of
individual but it has lobby to the group of people that we socialize.
Thus, in other words the collectivistic culture beside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cultures by the membership are typically divided into two categories:
collectivist and individualist. Individualistic cultures, people are
expected to develop and display their individual personalities and to
choose their own affiliations, where in collectivist cultures, people
are defined and act mostly as members of a long-term group, such as the
family, a religious group, an age cohort, a town, or a profession, among
others (Deb, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, individualism pertains to societies in which ties are loose:
people are expected to look after themselves and their immediate family.
In addition, collectivism pertains to societies in which people are
integrated into strong, cohesive groups from birth onwards, protecting
them in exchange for unquestioned loyalty (Hall, Menno, &amp;amp; Steehouder,
2004). Cross-cultural studies have provided empirical evidence that the
individualism-collectivism dimension is the most important dimension for
pinpointing differences between cultures (Ting-Toomey &amp;amp; Gao, 1998).
Furthermore, both collectivist and individualist cultures have their
failings. People in individualist cultures are susceptible to
loneliness, and people in collectivist cultures can have a strong fear
of rejection (Psychology Wiki, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically the emphasize of groups in family and work goals in
collectivist cultures, such as those of East Asia, parts of Latin
America and some countries from Europe, like: Greece and Portugal
(Psychology Wiki, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To illustrate the traits of collectivism is that each person is
encouraged to conform to society, to do what is best for the group and
do not openly express opinions or beliefs that go against it; group,
family or rights for the common good seen as more important than the
rights of individuals; where rules promote stability, order, obedience;
fitting in or conforming to group or society is required; where
distinctions made between in-group and out-group and working with others
and cooperating is the norm. Refusal to cooperate and wanting to be
independent or stand out is seen as shameful. Everyone must rely on
others for support. Therefore, stereotype of a ‘good person’ in
collectivist cultures is trustworthy, honest, generous, and sensitive,
all characteristics that are helpful to people working in groups
(Psychology Wiki, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the present day, users of the online social networks are more
collectivistic, because of the apparent benefits to networked
interaction. Given this rise in popularity, a significant amount of
prior work has examined the social behavior and attitudes of the users
that engage in Internet network. Proponents argue that community
building technology is useful because it improves knowledge interaction
among users, enhancing interpersonal relationships. Specifically as
weblogs, playing online or through Internet network games, wikis such as
Wikipedia, social networking such as Facebook, Myspace, Hi5, etc. and
micro blogging tools such as Twitter, in particular, have attracted
attention ( Dayne, Sigi, &amp;amp; Hart, 2009).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, I do not know all of my friends in my social networks
Facebook, last.fm, twitter, myspace, etc. Yet I do like to build a
community where I can share my other activities, such as sharing my new
photography that I have taken in Estonia or somewhere else, share the
event when I am going to perform a music show in clubs in Tartu or
Tallinn. Sharing links of my new blog posts or my site update.
Therefore, still I have seen this people face to face, or at least I
have had a face to face conversation with most of them. I do rely on
their support to show in events that I am performing, or get a feedback
on the photography that I have posted recently. All the above, creates
my own society group network though Internet my own virtual world
family, where relationship permits classification in the in-group, which
relied on collectivistic culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, when collectivists meet another person, the first
thought they are likely to have is, “What is my relationship with that
person?” If the relationship permits classification in the in-group,
they are likely to behave very positively – cooperating, supporting,
going out of their way to help. In contrast, if the other person is
classified as an out-group member, they are likely to be indifferent or
even hostile. Such sharp differentiation of in-group and out-group is
not found among individualists. Collectivists use action verbs, rather
than state verbs, because they prefer to use context in their
communications. Sometime even show a generosity rule when exchanging
with in-group members, where their acceptance of paternalism and to
emphasize the importance of the nurturance of the leader. And for
further more information see (Individualism and Collectivism, 2001, p.
35).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the Internet drastically changes the psyche in-group and
out-group communication, relationship, supporting, cooperation, etc. in
human culture. Nevertheless, Internet has influence on psyche in
collectivist culture behaviors but affects the individualist. Nowadays
people are communicating through the many sources available on Internet
and develop new relationships, groups and community where they can share
and feel positive, classified, into larger groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Reference&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dayne, F., Sigi, G., &amp;amp; Hart, D. (2009, November 9). Individualist and
collectivist factors affecting online repurchase intentions. Retrieved
from School of Accounting and Business Information Systems, The
Australian: www.emeraldinsight.com/1066-2243.htm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deb. (2011, March 27). Geert Hofstede. Retrieved from wikimedia.org:
https://secure.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/wiki/Geert_Hofstede&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hall, M., Menno, d., &amp;amp; Steehouder, M. (2004, November 1). Cultural
differences and usability evaluation: individualistic and collectivistic
participants compared. Retrieved fromHighBeam Research:
http://www.highbeam.com/doc/1G1-126157549.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psychology Wiki. (2011). Collectivist and individualist cultures.
Retrieved from Collectivist and individualist cultures – Psychology
Wiki:
http://psychology.wikia.com/wiki/Collectivist_and_individualist_cultures#Traits_of_Collectivism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ting-Toomey, S., &amp;amp; Gao, G. (1998). Communicating Effectively with the
Chinese. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage Publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TRIANDIS, H. C. (2001). Individualism and Collectivism. In D. Matsumoto,
The Handbook of CULTURE &amp;amp; PSYCHOLOGY (p. 35). Oxford: Oxfrod University
Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="collectivistic"></category><category term="cultures"></category><category term="informatics"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="online people"></category><category term="psyche"></category><category term="social"></category></entry><entry><title>Major changes in warfare from antiquity to modern</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2011/04/major-changes-in-warfare-from-antiquity-to-modern/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-04-20T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2011-04-20T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2011-04-20:/posts/2011/04/major-changes-in-warfare-from-antiquity-to-modern/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Analyse the major changes in warfare from antiquity to modern days. What are the most significant changes? What has remained unchanged?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we start the discussion about the major changes in warfare from
antiquity to present day we will precede with definition of War and its
significant and remained unchanged …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Analyse the major changes in warfare from antiquity to modern days. What are the most significant changes? What has remained unchanged?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we start the discussion about the major changes in warfare from
antiquity to present day we will precede with definition of War and its
significant and remained unchanged changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WAR in its literal meaning is fighting, for fighting alone is the
efficient principle in the manifold activity which, in a wide sense, is
called war. But fighting is a trial of strength of the moral and
physical forces by means of the latter. That the moral cannot be omitted
is evident of itself, for the condition of the mind has always the most
decisive influence on the forces employed in war (Graham, 2002).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humanity has wedged war since antiquity through nowadays for million
causes, national and religious freedom, hatred, grudge, human rights,
liberating the enslaved etc. But one principle in war has always been
present from the depths of history till today, that is, wars are fought
for one purpose only, conquest of new territory from which economic
benefit is to be acquired for the soul use of the conqueror. Nowhere is
this more obvious than in the armed clashes of the beginning of the XXI
century, when under the pretext of human rights countries are being
robed from their natural resources and air-raids are killing those whom
should protect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we met with the theory of war and moral principles, it is time to
consider changes that have occurred between the ancient and modern
times. The military of ancient Egypt had introduced the new technologies
of metal, where they used bronze in the Middle Kingdom as main weapons
source, after it changed to iron in the New Kingdom and all during the
Late Dynastic Period. The Old Kingdom soldiers were equipped with a
great variety of weapons: shields, spears, cudgels, maces, daggers, bows
and arrows. The New Kingdom carried spears, battle axes, sickleswords
(MdC transliteration: xpS – khepesh or khopesh) and daggers. After the
bowmen, either on foot or on chariots, had softened up the enemy forces
with a shower of arrows (Dollinger, Dynasties XVIII to XX, 2004), the
infantry would rush in, breaking their ranks with hand weapons, maces
with wooden handles and stone – later metal – heads, battle axes,
hatchets, clubs, swords, sickleswords and daggers (Dollinger, Weapons,
2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Persian Army had only three wars, started from 490 BC until 478BC, the
army was very multicultural, were organizes in a decimal basis,
regiments, units and corps were grouped in tens, hundreds and thousands
(Drury, 2006). Officers were being responsible for ten men, another for
one hundred, one thousand and ten thousand. Heavily equipped with
weapons, which are: Thrusting Spear, palta, Akinakes , Xiphos, kopis,
bow etc (Wildfiregames, 2004).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greece war, first nine years of the war consisted of both war in Troy
and war against the neighbouring regions, where destroyed Trojan
economy, allowed Greeks to getter a large amount of resources. The
Greeks won most of the battles, but they still could not break the walls
of Troy. The weapons that were used in those battles were bows and
arrows. As for strategies the famous Trojan horse, when Odysseus had a
perfect idea to build a big wooden horse where inside will be field with
the soldiers, which bring and invasion of Troy from the Greeks (Rita,
2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Army of Macedonia was the army of ancient Kingdom of Macedonia. It
considers a grate military force where there were reforms constructed
from the suggestion of King Philip II of Macedon and then his son
Alexander the Great. The introduction was in innovation of weapons and
new tactics, along with unique elements combination of military
elements, which bring a great intercontinental empire (Ellis, 1979).
Philip II had implemented in Macedonian phalanx army separation which
one group were on a mission to conquer a city and the other to conquer
castles. Each phalangite carried as his primary weapon a sarissa, but
the phalangite were not the focal point for the battle, they have used
other forces like: skirmishers, range troops, reserves of allied
hoplites, and artillery (Hellenica, 2005).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rome in the wars had adapted weapons, armour and tactics of many enemies
they fought. Main weapons of Rome soldiers were Spanish sword – gladius,
it had two throwing spears, a large shield, body armour and a helmet.
They have also operated with the fire supported weapons, scorpios,
carroballistas, onagers. For a fest moves they started to build bridges,
so that the soldiers and the army can move faster. The army can march up
to 30 km a day. They were very evil, trained to stab a 5 cm deep wound,
after breaking the enemy, Romans tended to kill as many enemies as
possible and their cavalry pursued fleeing enemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Rome the medieval Europe warfare followed, which was the war
of legal and acceptable justification, nobility (knights) and the main
force on the battlefield was a heavy cavalry, where the law of the armed
conflict was born. The second largest empire in human history was the
Mongol empire. Mongols army had the capacity to move up to 150 km a day.
The weapons of the army consisted of massive fire (bow) speed and
manoeuvres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wars of the XVI Century were mostly protracted and indecisive. There was
insistency on building a fortress that was very difficult to conquer.
The most important improvement is the side of the weapons with adoption
of light guns and gunpowder. Gustavus Adolphus had guns in his army, he
had 1 gun per 83, but his enemies had 1 gun per 2000 men. The main thing
was to build and modify the fortresses for safety and hard to conquer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;World War I, sometimes described as ‘the war to end all wars’ (Creveld,
2000, p. 162), the strategies were based on first manoeuvre, and then
attrition. Forces and armaments were infantry, cavalry artillery, and
surface navy (initially); later – tanks, planes, submarines, chemical
weapons. The tactics were manoeuvre, frontal assaults, fortified
defence, artillery concentration (initially); the theoretical thinking:
seeking the way out of dead end, but not finding the means and ways. The
first known bombardment from the sky, using airplanes was by Bulgarian
army on the 16 of October 1912 at battle of Adrianople, where they were
captivated by the Turkish army. From the German newspaper “Geschichte
des Luftkriegs”, Militarverlag der DDR, Berlin, 1975, though the 1912
United Kingdom had 23 air planes, Russian – 99, German – 46, Italian –
22, Japan – 10 and USA – 3 air planes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second World War, where the technology and the concept of the war were
getting bigger, developed into a prolonged and extremely deadly struggle
of attrition. The Germans invented the rockets (vau1 and vau2).
Hiroshima and Nagasaki are the first and only events of deployments of
nuclear weapons in the world.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second half of the 20th century, after the valuable technical point, the
arms forward for an outbreak of terrorism. That means that wars are no
longer big and global; the enemy is no longer in uniforman in force. And
size is no longer as great as it was the enemy can attack from anywhere.
Therefore, no longer wars head-do met the two armies, but running by
partisan / guerillas. Terrorism is an unconventional war de facto, i.e.
anti-insurgent operation, i.e. counter insurgency. Which create the kind
of combat actions that are performed nowadays in Afghanistan and Iraq.
In the 20th century, has one goal, redistribution of resources, i.e. to
get to justify the need to test before the war for democracy and human
rights. Macedonia is the country that is inclined towards terrorism, the
early 20th century, April 28 1903rd in Thessaloniki, the boatmen of
Thessaloniki have committed terrorist actions against the capital of
Western Europe and Turkey, i.e. have planted bombs in the Ottoman Bank
in Thessaloniki, the main post office, and planted a bomb in a ship
(Sotros, 2004 December).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As can read above the changes are very drastic. Humanity is fighting for
the different purpose; starting from the antiquity to nowadays, not only
in weapons that were used and presented, but in the strategies in a
tactics and theoretical thinking. Therefore, there are no more battles
wars, people are grouping and they can embattle from anywhere, which
gives a content of the terroristic activities of the wars. Today the
humanity and the scholars should getter together to work around of the
problems and solutions for the future, possibilities of internet (social
networks, VOIP, IM etc.), net generations1, thus today it is the main
source of grouping the population for massive protests or any other
actions, which can end-up to a war or scandal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently the technology and science are rising, the possibilities
and the changes in an aspect of wars will change. For instant is Russian
– Georgian conflict in 2008 as a result of territorial attack and in
sequence with it there was an cyber-attack in progress2; or powerful
internet worm repeatedly targeted five nuclear industrial facilities in
Iran and many others3. Therefore, nowadays this actions and concept of
warfare is different, no more uniforms, battles etc. Warfare’s are
getting new aspect and new ways to approach through the technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Reference&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creveld, M. V. (2000). THE INTERWAR PERIOD. In M. v. Creveld, The Art of
War – War and Military Thought. London: Cassell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dollinger, A. (2004, November). Dynasties XVIII to XX. Retrieved from
Ancient Egyptian history:
&lt;a href="http://www.reshafim.org.il/ad/egypt/history18-20.htm#merneptah"&gt;http://www.reshafim.org.il/ad/egypt/history18-20.htm#merneptah&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dollinger, A. (2010, March). Weapons. Retrieved from Pharaonic Egypt:
&lt;a href="http://www.reshafim.org.il/ad/egypt/weapons/index.html#rem4"&gt;http://www.reshafim.org.il/ad/egypt/weapons/index.html#rem4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drury, M. (2006, February). Battles of the Achaemenid Empire . Retrieved
from A History Resource by Mark Drury:
&lt;a href="http://members.ozemail.com.au/~ancientpersia/batt_frm.html"&gt;http://members.ozemail.com.au/~ancientpersia/batt_frm.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ellis, J. R. (1979). Philip II and Macedonian Imperialism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graham, C. J. (2002). On The Theory Of War, Section: Branches of the Art
of War. Retrieved 2011, from Clausewitz, ON WAR:
&lt;a href="http://www.clausewitz.com/readings/OnWar1873/BK2ch01.html"&gt;http://www.clausewitz.com/readings/OnWar1873/BK2ch01.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hellenica. (2005, 04). Macedonian phalanx. Retrieved from Hellenica:
&lt;a href="http://www.mlahanas.de/Greeks/LX/MacedonianPhalanx.html"&gt;http://www.mlahanas.de/Greeks/LX/MacedonianPhalanx.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rita. (2010). The Trojan War. Retrieved from Stanford University:
&lt;a href="/http://www.stanford.edu/~plomio/history.html#anchor202941"&gt;http://www.stanford.edu/\~plomio/history.html#anchor202941&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sotros, J. (2004 December). The Greek Speaking Anarchist and
Revolutionary Movement (1830–1940) Writings for a History. No God-No
Masters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wildfiregames. (2004, September). Persia: Arms of the Shah-an-Shah –
Persian Arms an. Retrieved from 0 A.D. :: Wildfire Games:
&lt;a href="http://wildfiregames.com/0ad/page.php?p=1581"&gt;http://wildfiregames.com/0ad/page.php?p=1581&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] The Net Generation Brain by Don Tapscott (2009)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="http://zdnet.com/blog"&gt;ZDnet.com/blog&lt;/a&gt; – Coordinated Russia vs
Georgia cyber attack in progress  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3] &lt;a href="http://bbc.co.uk/technology"&gt;BBC.co.uk/technology&lt;/a&gt; – Stuxnet virus
targets and spread revealed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="antiquity"></category><category term="art of war"></category><category term="changes warfare"></category><category term="cyber"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="cyber warfare"></category><category term="history"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="modern"></category><category term="networking"></category><category term="new war"></category><category term="nework crime"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="war"></category><category term="war strategy"></category></entry><entry><title>Human Computer Interaction in 2020</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2011/03/human-computer-interaction-in-2020/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2011-03-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2011-03-17:/posts/2011/03/human-computer-interaction-in-2020/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In March 2007, Microsoft Research organised the “HCI 2020” meeting at
the El Bulli Hacienda Hotel near Seville, Spain. The event’s title
expressed its key question: what will Human-Computer Interaction (HCI)
be like in the year 2020? (Harper, Tom, Yvonne, &amp;amp; Abigail, 2008, p. 8)
The report that I have …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In March 2007, Microsoft Research organised the “HCI 2020” meeting at
the El Bulli Hacienda Hotel near Seville, Spain. The event’s title
expressed its key question: what will Human-Computer Interaction (HCI)
be like in the year 2020? (Harper, Tom, Yvonne, &amp;amp; Abigail, 2008, p. 8)
The report that I have read it is divided in a four parts; Part 1 it is
look back over the past 20 years or so; Part 2 it gives an outline how
does changes are transforming the nature of our interaction with
computers and the key questions that need to be addressed in the next 15
years as a result; Part 3 is concerned with HCI as a field of research
and as a community of practitioners and designers; Part 4,
recommendations, outlines specific suggestions for HCI in terms of how
the field needs to be change. Therefore, the research report it talks
about the future aspects and the future plans with an recommendations
that has to be concern in an aspect of HCI, I have chosen to write about
the part 4 where they give a good outline of the recommendations that
has to be encounter for the new actions in the future of HCI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research report came with very good seventh future directions. Each
direction will be described in an educationally signification for me,
what I have learned and what should be the next future actions in
consideration. Matter of course, no one will know in what kind of
aspects and future plans the HCI will change, but still this research
report gives vaulting and most important future recommendations that
need to be considered, and there will be more and more recommendations
and future directions as the technology and the HCI changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we start to talk about the recommendations in a field of HCI,
let’s see what HCI is. It is a term used to refer to the understanding
and designing of different relationships between people and computers.
In the late 1970’s the main concern was usability. Since then, HCI has
established and designed, developed and apply all manners to ensure that
the technologies are easy to learn and easy to use. (Harper, Tom,
Yvonne, &amp;amp; Abigail, 2008, p. 84)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting familiar with the terms and the practice of HCI let as
look though the main seventh future recommendations that were considered
by the scholars and people involved in this forum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation 1: Revisit research and design methods in HCI: it is
    a distinct research area, methods and techniques have been used have
    altered over the years. Computer system and technologies are still
    in a way of changes, thus are the approaches for 2020 that needs to
    be considered:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore new ways of understanding users. Over the last decade there
    have been techniques and design-based practices involving cultural
    probes. Usage of existing techniques of understanding that have
    emerged from scientific and engineering traditions, designs, views
    of diverse disciplines and cultural traditions; usage of conceptual
    analysis in the first stage of new HCI, where can comes from
    techniques of analytic philosophy and clarifying the systems of
    meaning and value of actions that are involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore new ways of designing and making. Designing and making it
    takes a very important influence in a way of HCI. It is very
    important to comprehend for what, which and why the system is going
    to be used, what kind of users. In the future lightweight and
    prototypes should fit the designing and engineering solutions
    together. Should be developed new technological, prototype tool for
    the future development, and consider a test of hardware and software
    within every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reconsider how to evaluate digital technologies. Create a purpose of
    usage of the system, towards the, is it going to be used in everyday
    life in houses, working spaces or other environment. For what kind
    of usability the system is going to be used. For all should be made
    evaluation tools to reconsider the criteria and techniques.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation 2: Be explicit about the remit of HCI. How far or
    whether the HCI as a research area should continue extend itself, or
    should be involved with interaction between people and digital
    technology, and should with concern itself more than in the past?
    Does are the question that should be raised. It should develop new
    design possibilities, future altering and crafting the landscape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation 3: Develop disciplinary techniques that allow HCI to
    collaborate with other research communities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disciplinary exchange. Requirement for HCI researchers to know how
    to converse with disciplines with very different traditions, they
    need to understand what philosophers can do and why philosophy is
    important. Example: economists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beyond interdisciplinary boundaries. HCI should ask what might be
    the appropriate models for allowing interdisciplinary investigations
    to happen and it is an area where investment in research theories
    and approaches, in the elements of HCI competence and skill, and in
    the foundations of the philosophy of science are required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation 4: Teach HCI to the young. Children should be
    introduced to the ‘properties and possibilities of computing’ it is
    the only way that they develop sufficient understanding of computing
    to enable them to be fully computer-literate when they are adults,
    and help them to shape the world in relation to technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation 5: More advanced training for future HCI researchers.
    HCI professionals need to move outside of the scientific community
    they have lived within and find ways to engage with society as a
    whole.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation 6: Engage with government, policy and society. More
    better technical and economical approach, where there will be wide
    range of implementing HCI in a government, but in policy and
    society. HCI should have a strong links with the society, it needs
    to interact more, not only like for policy in a trust and security
    in computer systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation 7: Offer an inclusive future in 2020. By 2020, HCI
    will need to be able to design for and support differences in human
    value, irrespective of the economic means of those seeking those
    values. In this way, the future can be different and diverse because
    people want it to be. (Harper, Tom, Yvonne, &amp;amp; Abigail, 2008, pp.
    78-83)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this article very interesting, not only in an aspect of human
interaction with computers but with the actions that were taken and the
propositions that were sum. I love to make a summer of the entire
research paper, but because of the short time period I could not make
it. Still I gained my knowledge what should be expected and where are
burrows in HCI field. It gives me a perfect view for the future
implementation of projects, aspects and techniques that can be used.
Hope that this few years since the 2007, the implementation and
recommendation directories have been successfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Reference&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harper, R., Tom, R., Yvonne, R., &amp;amp; Abigail, S. (2008). Being Human,
Human-Computer Interaction in the year 2020. Cambridge, CB3 0FB,
England: Microsoft Research Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="2020"></category><category term="future of human communication"></category><category term="HCI"></category><category term="HCI 2020"></category><category term="human computer interaction"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="networking"></category><category term="online"></category><category term="online generations"></category><category term="social informatics"></category></entry></feed>