<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece - Macedonia</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/feeds/macedonia.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://predragtasevski.com/</id><updated>2017-01-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Cyber Security overview of 2016 and 2017 predictions (Macedonian language)</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2017/01/IT-security-2017-predictions/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-01-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2017-01-02:/posts/2017/01/IT-security-2017-predictions/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Interview in Macedonian IT news portal only available in Macedonian language, link: &lt;a href="https://www.it.mk/it-bezbednost/" target="_blank" title="ИТ безбедност: 2016-та беше хорор година, очекувањата се дека 2017-та ќе биде полоша"&gt;https://www.it.mk/it-bezbednost/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Predrag Tasevski" src="https://www.it.mk/wp-content/themes/it2015/images/2017/it-bezbednost-predrag-tasevski-cybersecurity.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Interview in Macedonian IT news portal only available in Macedonian language, link: &lt;a href="https://www.it.mk/it-bezbednost/" target="_blank" title="ИТ безбедност: 2016-та беше хорор година, очекувањата се дека 2017-та ќе биде полоша"&gt;https://www.it.mk/it-bezbednost/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Predrag Tasevski" src="https://www.it.mk/wp-content/themes/it2015/images/2017/it-bezbednost-predrag-tasevski-cybersecurity.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Macedonia"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="IT security"></category><category term="prediction"></category><category term="interview"></category><category term="ransomware"></category><category term="data breaches"></category><category term="botnet"></category><category term="awareness"></category><category term="privacy"></category><category term="encryption"></category></entry><entry><title>Balkans capacity towards cyber defense</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2015/09/yata-comments-of-the-week/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-27T13:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-09-27T13:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2015-09-27:/posts/2015/09/yata-comments-of-the-week/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following texts is captured interview for YATA Comments of the week video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LAfOPIBoj8Q" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Predrag Tasevski and I’m an independent cyber security researcher from Macedonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we talk about Balkan region it is actually neither one step further nor one step backwards regarding cyber threats and cyber security …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following texts is captured interview for YATA Comments of the week video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LAfOPIBoj8Q" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Predrag Tasevski and I’m an independent cyber security researcher from Macedonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we talk about Balkan region it is actually neither one step further nor one step backwards regarding cyber threats and cyber security. And at the same time progression of ICT is improving the  connectivity and its utilities from the rest of the world. For this reason discussing about cyber defense and security capacity in the region is in fact crucial and important topic.
However before we continue we have to understand the difference between IT security and cyber security. IT security is to protect business and individual assets, whereas cyber security it involved IT security as well as national, state security and security of Critical Information Infrastructure point of view.
To be able to have safer cyber space, we need to take an actions. Such as, ratifying conventions for instance Budapest Convention, moreover, adapting legal framework with international and of course social society needs. Than pursue establishment of National Bodies that will deal with occurrence and the frequency of cyberspace attacks and threats. And last but not least, develop national cyber security strategy. Among the mentioned actions, also important is to take into consideration the general approaches, as multi stakeholders and multi-level approach.
Cyberspace could not be 100% secured, therefore each country should introduce national cyber security culture and at the same time raising the awareness level to the weakest link in cyber security - that is the human behaviors.
Moreover, when we discuss about the cyber security and defense another important questions should be raised, by providing of course and answers:
Who? determines the target of who you are planning to secure.
What? determines the content of what to secure.
How? is the means by how you are going to secure it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turning back to Balkan vision toward cyber defense and security, we might say that several countries a much further progressing, such as Slovenia, Croatia, Albania, Montenegro and Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina, in contrast to slowly progressing countries: Macedonia, Serbia and etc.
Nevertheless, the region has taken under the umbrella and understood the importance of such topics and for this reason are taking hence actions. Such actions are as we mentioned previously making their legal framework compliance with the international perspectives. And establishing national bodies to react and countermeasure the incident occurred in cyberspace. And finally establishing national cyber security strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the end I would like to provide recommendation actions that could help other countries in pursuing and capacity building towards cyber defense and security.
Such as:
1. Understand cyber defense from a global perspective, don't feel nervous and foolish when it comes to the word “Cyber”. Use common and simple language that everyone could understand it.
2. Define and implement a national cyber security/defence strategy, followed by cyber security frameworks by supporting it initiatives and international cooperation.
3. Develop public awareness, cyber security culture and education that will touch entire population needs.
4. Improve resilience against cyber terrorism, cyber espionage, hybrid war and cyber warfare by sharing knowledge, documents, continues education and training, military and non-military capabilities.
5. Enforcing ICT infrastructures security in order to obtain confidence and security in the use of ICT. By investing in research and development.
6. And finally, continuance of public meetings and networking are in fact needed and essential on yearly basis for secure cyber space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The first step toward encouraging security and defence is awareness, followed by the implementation, acceptance and so forth”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="balkan"></category><category term="awareness"></category><category term="cyber defense"></category><category term="YATA"></category><category term="video"></category><category term="interview"></category><category term="Macedonia"></category><category term="ICT"></category><category term="strategy"></category></entry><entry><title>Research Paper: Macedonian Path Towards Cybersecurity</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2015/09/macedonian-cyber-security/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-15T19:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-09-15T19:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2015-09-15:/posts/2015/09/macedonian-cyber-security/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information and communication technologies in Macedonia have experienced a phenomenal growth throughout the last decades, which has had a tremendous impact on governmental services’ presence in the Internet, as well as on everyday life. Against this background, technologies-based growth introduces new risks and threats to the cyber domain in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information and communication technologies in Macedonia have experienced a phenomenal growth throughout the last decades, which has had a tremendous impact on governmental services’ presence in the Internet, as well as on everyday life. Against this background, technologies-based growth introduces new risks and threats to the cyber domain in the country. To respond to those challenges the Macedonian government is pursing the establishment of a national authority to react to cyber attacks that occur, or a Computer Incident Response Team – MKD-CIRT, and the adoption of a National Cybersecurity Strategy. However, it should be
taken into account that such tasks are neither easy nor simple. There are several issues that should be considered, for instance: the improvement of the measures for protection of information systems and of the critical infrastructure; the legal and policy framework; the international approach; and the formation of a cybersecurity culture, to name but a few. Simultaneously, considering that Macedonia is a candidate for accession to the EU and NATO, it has to comply with their standards when performing the reforms in the cybersecurity field. The current article briefly introduces the country’s steps towards cybersecurity, provides an analysis of the legal, policy and institutional progress achieved, and suggests recommendations that should be considered to ensure safer, secure, trustworthy and resilient cyber space
in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link for full paper (download): &lt;a href="http://procon.bg/article/macedonian-path-towards-cybersecurity" target="_blank"&gt;Procon LTD, In Information &amp;amp; Security: An International Journal. Vol. 32., In Press&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keywords&lt;/em&gt;: Macedonia, cyber, establishment, MKD-CIRT, strategy, security,
national security&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Macedonia"></category><category term="cyber"></category><category term="establishment"></category><category term="MKD-CIRT"></category><category term="strategy"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="national security"></category></entry><entry><title>Interview: Snowden helped the mass awakening of awareness by Nova Makedonija</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2014/04/interview-snowden-helped-the-mass-awakening-of-awareness-by-nova-makedonija/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-04-29T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-04-29T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2014-04-29:/posts/2014/04/interview-snowden-helped-the-mass-awakening-of-awareness-by-nova-makedonija/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Source: Nova Makedonija, Interview by Predrag Tasevski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First Macedonian daily newspaper have asked me for interview before the
holidays. The topic was concentrating on security, coupled the national
security and IT security. However, the interview is posted in
&lt;a href="http://www.novamakedonija.com.mk/NewsDetal.asp?vest=4291475063&amp;amp;amp;id=51&amp;amp;amp;prilog=0&amp;amp;amp;setIzdanie=23162"&gt;Macedonian
language&lt;/a&gt;,
but also you could use &lt;a href="http://translate.google.com/translate?sl=mk&amp;amp;amp;tl=en&amp;amp;amp;js=y&amp;amp;amp;prev=_t&amp;amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.novamakedonija.com.mk%2FNewsDetal.asp%3Fvest%3D4291475063%26id%3D51%26prilog%3D0%26setIzdanie%3D23162&amp;amp;amp;edit-text="&gt;English
translation&lt;/a&gt;
with Google translator …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Source: Nova Makedonija, Interview by Predrag Tasevski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First Macedonian daily newspaper have asked me for interview before the
holidays. The topic was concentrating on security, coupled the national
security and IT security. However, the interview is posted in
&lt;a href="http://www.novamakedonija.com.mk/NewsDetal.asp?vest=4291475063&amp;amp;amp;id=51&amp;amp;amp;prilog=0&amp;amp;amp;setIzdanie=23162"&gt;Macedonian
language&lt;/a&gt;,
but also you could use &lt;a href="http://translate.google.com/translate?sl=mk&amp;amp;amp;tl=en&amp;amp;amp;js=y&amp;amp;amp;prev=_t&amp;amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.novamakedonija.com.mk%2FNewsDetal.asp%3Fvest%3D4291475063%26id%3D51%26prilog%3D0%26setIzdanie%3D23162&amp;amp;amp;edit-text="&gt;English
translation&lt;/a&gt;
with Google translator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any comments and want to discuss something feel free to drop
me a comments below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Holidays!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="interview"></category><category term="nova makedonija"></category><category term="newspaper"></category><category term="snowden"></category><category term="awareness"></category><category term="macedonia"></category><category term="cyber security"></category></entry><entry><title>I can hack your FB, can you catch me...</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/05/i-can-hack-your-fb-can-you-catch-me/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-05-26T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2013-05-26T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2013-05-26:/posts/2013/05/i-can-hack-your-fb-can-you-catch-me/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of &lt;a href="http://surfajbezbedno.mk/" title="Surfaj Bezbedno"&gt;Surf
Safe&lt;/a&gt; campaign in Macedonia
to raise awareness about the mind, responsible and safe use of the
Internet, and close acquaintance with threats and ways of prevention and
detection.
&lt;a href="http://www.finki.ukim.mk/en/home" title="Faculty of Computer Science and Engineering - Skopje"&gt;FINKI&lt;/a&gt;
in cooperation with the &lt;a href="http://moi.gov.mk/" title="Ministry of Interior Macedonia"&gt;Ministry of Interior in
Macedonia&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://www.cybersecurity.mk/" title="CyberSecurity.mk"&gt;CyberSecurity.mk&lt;/a&gt;
organized hour practical …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of &lt;a href="http://surfajbezbedno.mk/" title="Surfaj Bezbedno"&gt;Surf
Safe&lt;/a&gt; campaign in Macedonia
to raise awareness about the mind, responsible and safe use of the
Internet, and close acquaintance with threats and ways of prevention and
detection.
&lt;a href="http://www.finki.ukim.mk/en/home" title="Faculty of Computer Science and Engineering - Skopje"&gt;FINKI&lt;/a&gt;
in cooperation with the &lt;a href="http://moi.gov.mk/" title="Ministry of Interior Macedonia"&gt;Ministry of Interior in
Macedonia&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://www.cybersecurity.mk/" title="CyberSecurity.mk"&gt;CyberSecurity.mk&lt;/a&gt;
organized hour practical training on topic “I can hack your Facebook,
can You catch me…”, aimed at introducing the possibilities of hacking
social networks sites, how you can find and discover burglar and how to
protect yourself in the future. The training was held on May 10 at 13:30
pm in the amphitheater of TMF. The training was free and open to all
interested. Trainers of this training were: &lt;a href="http://predragtasevski.com/" title="Predrag Tasevski"&gt;Predrag
Tasevski&lt;/a&gt; founder
&lt;a href="http://www.cybersecurity.mk/" title="CyberSecurity.mk"&gt;CyberSecurity.mk&lt;/a&gt; and
Katerina Jovanovska head of Department of Information and criminal
investigations in the area of criminal technique in Ministry of
Interiors in Macedonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, during the presentation I have introduce the participant how
easy and simple is to pass the second verification of Trusted contacts
in Facebook. For more information please refer to the next paragraph the
presentation. Due to the copyrights and leaking of information I’m
unable to share the presentation of Department of information and
criminal investigation in Macedonia. Thank you for your understanding.
Also many thanks to the Deputy Minister of Information Society and
Administration, Marta Arsovska Tomovska for wonderful introduction and
being present to the training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also the purpose of this training was to boost the awareness and of
course interest to the students for future training that will be
provided by
&lt;a href="http://www.cybersecurity.mk/" title="CyberSecurity.mk"&gt;CyberSecurity.mk&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://www.finki.ukim.mk/en/home" title="Faculty of Computer Science and Engineering - Skopje"&gt;FINKI&lt;/a&gt;
university to their students and also to the government and private
agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Presentation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/file/d/0B1472nuKPMN5dTI2dlFSV0ZVWkk/preview" width="640" height="480"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Pictures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="375"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648703591830%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648703591830%2F&amp;set_id=72157648703591830&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648703591830%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648703591830%2F&amp;set_id=72157648703591830&amp;jump_to=" width="500" height="375"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="facebook"></category><category term="fb"></category><category term="hack"></category><category term="mvr"></category><category term="macedonia"></category><category term="course"></category><category term="teaching"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="surfaj bezbedno"></category></entry><entry><title>Cyber Security Group in South Eastern Europe</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/01/cyber-security-group-in-south-eastern-europe/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-01-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-01-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2013-01-03:/posts/2013/01/cyber-security-group-in-south-eastern-europe/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently we have heard and read about the importance of cybersecurity
around the
&lt;a href="http://www.csmonitor.com/USA/Politics/2013/0213/Why-Obama-s-executive-order-on-cybersecurity-doesn-t-satisfy-most-experts"&gt;US&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a href="http://ec.europa.eu/digital-agenda/en/news/eu-cybersecurity-plan-protect-open-internet-and-online-freedom-and-opportunity-cyber-security"&gt;EU&lt;/a&gt;.
Firstly Obama administration get order intended to bolster
cybersecurity, where the move comes after the White House tried, and
indeed failed to get tough cybersecurity legislation through Congresses
last year. Secondly, EU released the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently we have heard and read about the importance of cybersecurity
around the
&lt;a href="http://www.csmonitor.com/USA/Politics/2013/0213/Why-Obama-s-executive-order-on-cybersecurity-doesn-t-satisfy-most-experts"&gt;US&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a href="http://ec.europa.eu/digital-agenda/en/news/eu-cybersecurity-plan-protect-open-internet-and-online-freedom-and-opportunity-cyber-security"&gt;EU&lt;/a&gt;.
Firstly Obama administration get order intended to bolster
cybersecurity, where the move comes after the White House tried, and
indeed failed to get tough cybersecurity legislation through Congresses
last year. Secondly, EU released the cybersecurity plan to protect open
Internet and online freedom and opportunity – Cyber Security strategy
and Proposal for a Directive. Frankly, where are the countries of South
Eastern Europe (SEE) in here, such as the ones that are not in EU, for
instance: Macedonia, Serbia, Montenegro, Bosnia, Albania and Kosovo?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, my plan, as a founder of
&lt;a href="http://cybersecurity.mk"&gt;Cybersecurity.mk&lt;/a&gt; would like to make a
proposal of creating and teaming a group which will meet once a month to
talk over another the importance of such as beneficial and in fact
essential cybersecurity issues, as well as to exchange knowledge.
Sharing is caring. Additionally, in every meeting we will merge and
invite important people either over the remote or in the place speakers
to give, share and offer us a knowledge what we should do in a near
future. How we could fix and raise not only the awareness, but also the
importance of cybersecurity in South Eastern Europe (Macedonia, Serbia,
Montenegro, Bosnia, Albania, Kosovo, Croatia, Slovenia, Bulgaria,
Romania and Greece).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this proposal to be success we would need a help from NGO’s, NPO’s
and any other institutes from the region and elsewhere. In addition I
would like to ask hackers, crackers, ethical and non-ethical, designers,
freelancers and many other to help us with the following problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Name of the group. I will be more than happy if you could give as
proposals on the comment section for the name of the group. Let us
contribute together in this matter and we will be all God Fathers for
the group which will help us in improving and boosting awareness level
in cyber and IT security in our region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logo. We would like to hear from any of you to design the logo of
South Eastern Europe – Cyber Security Group. Please feel free to give us
a link of the design in the comment section (below) and then we will
select together the best proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sponsorship for the speakers to invite them to meet with us in face to
face, either is NGO, NPO, financial, telecommunication, insurance
institutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proposal of speakers, list for the next meetings and place, indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further great ideas or proposals please do not hesitate
to share them with us. We would be more than happy to take them in
consideration. Nevertheless, I really hope that forming the group, such
as Google Developer Group etc. will help on one hand. And on the other
hand, will aid to meet one another, to discuss and share our knowledge.
To learn from the best people and scholars in cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, more frequently in SEE region we have seen targets to attackers
on the Internet. How do we handle this matter of facts and how we deal
against? How we protect our online space? And indeed why we should take
actions? Those are just a start-up questions that everyone of us should
be able to answer them. Therefore, we hope that you all will contributes
in the above problem that we face and will HELP us in creating this
group in SEE region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="NGO"></category><category term="group"></category><category term="south eastern europe"></category><category term="macedonia"></category><category term="balkan"></category></entry><entry><title>Company Brochure and Founder Notes, Cybersecurity.mk</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2012/09/company-brochure-and-founder-notes-cybersecuritymk/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-09-20T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2012-09-20T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2012-09-20:/posts/2012/09/company-brochure-and-founder-notes-cybersecuritymk/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;COMPANY BROCHURE: Cybersecurity.mk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your IT infrastructure could be taken under the shoulder of
professionals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;September 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founder Notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, Macedonian government has announced to open a CERT agency.
This news was not only shock to us, but to everyone else, indeed.
However, we are supporting this initiative and hope …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;COMPANY BROCHURE: Cybersecurity.mk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your IT infrastructure could be taken under the shoulder of
professionals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;September 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founder Notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, Macedonian government has announced to open a CERT agency.
This news was not only shock to us, but to everyone else, indeed.
However, we are supporting this initiative and hope that will be able to
elaborate and corporate within organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Macedonian situation in a field of information and cyber security is not
on very surprising or signification level. Therefore our main goal is to
increase and merge the collaboration with neighbour countries as well as
with international organizations and agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, our belief lies that we will be able to bring better
understanding of very important issues that concern information and
cyber security, and to lead to better national awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this matter, our company will continue to expend the partnership as
well as international collaboration. We will constantly checking for
updates for existing solutions, also to search for new solutions to
update our offerings and services. And further development of our
projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this brochure we would like to introduce you with our company
profile, such as, our services, partners, clients, projects and our blog
posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link to PDF version of the brochure is on the following link:
&lt;a href="http://cybersecurity.mk/about.html"&gt;http://cybersecurity.mk/about.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="cert"></category><category term="CIRT"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="cybersecurity"></category><category term="cybersecurity.mk"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="macedonia"></category><category term="mkd"></category><category term="online"></category><category term="security"></category></entry><entry><title>Ministry of Interior – Macedonia, website defacement: http://mvr.gov.mk</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2012/06/ministry-of-interior-macedonia-website-defacement-httpmvrgovmk/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-06-25T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2012-06-25T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2012-06-25:/posts/2012/06/ministry-of-interior-macedonia-website-defacement-httpmvrgovmk/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Purpose&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the 25 of June 2012, the Macedonian website of Ministry of
Interior (MVR) was defaced by Kosovo Network Security (KNS) group, below
figure. However, after we have noticed and some of the social networking
sites have informed me, I was concern to find out what just have
happened …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Purpose&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the 25 of June 2012, the Macedonian website of Ministry of
Interior (MVR) was defaced by Kosovo Network Security (KNS) group, below
figure. However, after we have noticed and some of the social networking
sites have informed me, I was concern to find out what just have
happened and how did happen, and of course how they have done it. So for
this purpose, I have done some digging into details, about the previous
defacement activities of this very important government site. But before
we continue with more details, let just talk about the situation of
yesterday and what did the authorities take protective measures steps
and actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, 25 June 2012 at 19:38, one friend have updated his status in
one of the social networking sites, as follows: “Хакован
&lt;a href="http://mvr.gov.mk/"&gt;http://mvr.gov.mk/&lt;/a&gt;” (Hacked &lt;a href="http://mvr.gov.mk/"&gt;http://mvr.gov.mk/&lt;/a&gt;). And it made me
extremely intrigue to see what actually have just happened. The below
figure, displays the message spread from the KNS group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Screenshot from the mvr.gov.mk defaced version&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, what makes the situation even more interesting is that after
the report that the site was defaced the authorities have taken a
measures steps to fix the issue, by either shutting down the server or
restoring the content of the site from the backup. Then after one or two
minutes the site was defaced again. I did not want to lose the time and
the nervous to check every five or ten minutes to see when it will be
back again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, after 15 hours, or one stressful – hard core night for the
administrators of the site, the usability and functionalities where back
as normal, let just see how long will stay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, in the current post the idea is to give and overview, of what
actually is going on when it comes to case of cyber space, cyber
security issues in Macedonia. The structure of this post is introduces
first with the issue, or the problem that actuality made me to write
this post. Followed by the background investigation about the previous
defacement activities on the Ministry of Interior website in Macedonia.
Then with the background investigation about the KNS group, moreover,
with the self pen-testing site with different attacking methodologies.
And finally, closing by with a conclusion and action plan that should be
taken, for hence actions. This post does not only involves the public
sector, but even and the private sector too. Those agencies,
organizations are too much careless and do not take any actions of
securing their IT assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ministry of Interior in Macedonia site offers different online services.
The site primary idea is to inform the inhabitance about the news,
actions, useful information, public relations, analysis and statistics;
international cooperation and legislation; and finally the services. And
secondly is to give and opportunities to the population scheduling of
service, if their document is issued, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one short sentence, this site, for some people, it may be very useful
or not. However, I need to empathize that the site is only available in
Macedonian language, nor Albania, nor English version. So, in simple
conclusion this site is only useful for Macedonian speakers, and not for
foreigners, yet still represents one of very important public service,
government agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, in the next section we will discuses the previous
defacement and hacking attacks of this site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Background&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The service of this site, or the domain first was registered in 22
October 2003, and unfortunate I do not remember when was first time
available and published. However, in the pass years I have heard many
times that this site was defaced and hacked, but still no actions or
results were shown. Therefore, it made me very interesting to find out,
if this defacement activities where notified and when and how many
where. For this purpose I have use a site service that I know few years
ago, the &lt;a href="http://www.zone-h.org/"&gt;Zone-H&lt;/a&gt;. Moreover,
&lt;a href="http://www.zone-h.org/"&gt;Zone-H&lt;/a&gt; is neither responsible for the reported
computer crimes nor it is directly or indirectly involved with them, it
is just and simple site where collects the cybercrime activities
notified anonymously. The bellow figure provides a details of previous
reported/notified cybercrime activities of MVR site in Macedonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In details, total notifications are 4 of which 2 are single IP and 2 are
mass defacements. The first mass defacement was done in 29 July 2009,
when the site use a OS: Windows 2000, then in 2011 it was the
re-defacement and the server operating system is Windows 2008. Followed
by the other massive defacement in this year 2012 in March 18, and same
year, few days before the current attack, 22 of June it was
re-defacement. And the attack, defacement that we write for it was not
notified or reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From these data, and schedule, we can come to a conclusion that the site
was defaced just 3 days before the mass defacement attack, so it might
be a simple warning, to taken an action before something goes really
wrong. But most probably, non of those administrators, or authorities
did not taken any serious actions, until the case yesterday appears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Details&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be able to do an analysis of what actually have happened, we need to
take some actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we have done a simple web sniffer, to find out what kind of
system, and services the site, server is using. If we request the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_HTTP_header_fields"&gt;HTTP
Request Header&lt;/a&gt;
we will receive an HTTP Response Header with a following data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    Status: HTTP/1.1 200 OKCache-Control: privateContent-Type: text/html; charset=utf-8Server: Microsoft-IIS/7.0Set-Cookie: ASP.NET_SessionId=3lti3gep3usg4255ggf34tjn; path=/; HttpOnlyX-AspNet-Version: 2.0.50727X-Powered-By: ASP.NETDate: Tue, 26 Jun 2012 08:18:34 GMTConnection: closeContent-Length: 103773

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above data, is useful in a sense that provides as an information
about the Server and the ASP.Net Version. Then, if we want to find more
details about the open and close ports and operating system we can use
the &lt;a href="http://nmap.org/"&gt;nmap&lt;/a&gt; tool with the following command line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;nmap -O -v IP-Address&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the results will be as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    PORT STATE SERVICE21/tcp open ftp80/tcp open httpRunning (JUST GUESSING) : Microsoft Windows Vista|2008|7 (89%)

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the web sniffing and from the OS version scanning we can assume
that the server is running Microsoft Windows 2008. The current
vulnerabilities and possible exploitations are visible on the &lt;a href="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/security/bulletin/"&gt;Microsoft
Security
Bulletins&lt;/a&gt;
website. By knowing the vulnerabilities it is very easy task to find out
a way either to commit DoS attack or remote server access. However, in
this post we will not go into details and exploitation descriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the KNS, we assume the domain is followed:
&lt;a href="http://kns-team.com/"&gt;http://kns-team.com&lt;/a&gt;. However, the site is down,
therefore, we will have to understand who is behind this domain
registration. Therefore, we will use the whois database to understand
more, or even we can use another site that have been defaced by this
group to find out more. So there is the list presented the members in
the groups and their archive of notified defaced sites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.zone-h.org/archive/notifier=cracker-besi"&gt;rAcKeR-BeSi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.zone-h.org/archive/notifier=L0wHacker"&gt;L0wHacker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sLizer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X-r00t&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SpyHackz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Facebook fan page is:
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Kosova-Network-Security/176195849098989"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/pages/Kosova-Network-Security/176195849098989&lt;/a&gt;.
For more info I was short of time to do more digging, but I hope that
someone will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Action&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After understanding the details about the MVR site, operating system and
their server services, and information about the KNS, it is time to take
an action of trying to see how vulnerable is MVR site, and to see if
these lads had very difficult time of defacing the content of the site,
or even gaining access to the server-side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before, we carry on, I want to stress out that this section is not
to give you an idea how, or knowledge to exploit or use any
vulnerabilities to deface or gain access to the site. We will just
demonstrate you a very simple
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-site_scripting"&gt;XSS&lt;/a&gt; exploit of MVR
site that we have found a vulnerability, figure below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example of exploitation by XSS vulnerability, mvr.gov.mk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is therefore, from this very simple and easy exploitation of XSS
vulnerability of the MVS site we will be able to run more advance and
complicated shell scripts to gain access and maintain access of the
server. Our initial idea is not to show you how to do it, but to expose
to the audience that actually hence actions is need it. And we hope that
the administrators, developers and the authorities will take an action
of mitigating the risk, and further vulnerabilities of the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Macedonia, cyber space, cyber crime, cyber security, cyber warefare,
cyber terrorism are actually unknown words, terminology. They are not
even specified or added into the Macedonian dictionary, nor in IT
dictionary. However, this is not the first or least defacement, attack
that has happened in Macedonia, nor the first attack that has been done,
implemented by neighbor countries, or someone else. I just don’t
understand why people in this country are so careless about how to
protect their IT assets, and everything else, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it is not an issue that we do not have specialists to
conduct a pen-testing to the sites and services that not only the
government agencies are offering but even the banks and private sectors
as well. We even have a cyber crime unit in Ministry of Interior, and
one of very successful information security research and development
laboratory in Macedonia: &lt;a href="http://www.zeroscience.mk/en/"&gt;Zero Science
Lab&lt;/a&gt;. Also, the &lt;a href="http://cybersecurity.mk/icsap/"&gt;ICSAP – Interactive
Cyber Security Awareness Program&lt;/a&gt;,
Macedonia project, developed by myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, in final conclusion, I would like to recommend the
authorities to take actions about the above described activities done by
KNS and hope that the security awareness will boost up, and the further
actions will be considered of securing cyber space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Attacks"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="information warfare"></category><category term="legal aspects of cyber security"></category><category term="log mining"></category><category term="DDoS"></category><category term="exploitation"></category><category term="kns"></category><category term="macedonia"></category><category term="mvr"></category><category term="online"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="vulnerability"></category><category term="expolit"></category></entry><entry><title>Hate Speech on Internet, 01 Dec. 2012</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2012/04/hate-speech-on-internet-01-dec-2012/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-04-11T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2012-04-11T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2012-04-11:/posts/2012/04/hate-speech-on-internet-01-dec-2012/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Discussing in one of the highest mountains in Macedonia, around 1250m
above sea level, in theme to Hate Speech on Internet is always a great
idea.&lt;span id="more-503"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the event was performed from 30 of November until 3rd of
December by non-governmental, non-profit youth voluntary organization,
&lt;a href="http://www.cid.mk/index.php"&gt;The Centre for Intercultural Dialogue …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Discussing in one of the highest mountains in Macedonia, around 1250m
above sea level, in theme to Hate Speech on Internet is always a great
idea.&lt;span id="more-503"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the event was performed from 30 of November until 3rd of
December by non-governmental, non-profit youth voluntary organization,
&lt;a href="http://www.cid.mk/index.php"&gt;The Centre for Intercultural Dialogue
(CID)&lt;/a&gt;. In the request to the organization
I was invited to deliver training-speech as an expert in the cyber
security to the above topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get an idea of what was the content of training I have provided you
with the slides below, as well as the pictures taken during training.
Unfortunately, the presentation slides are only in Macedonian language.
If anyone needs the content on the slides in English please fell free to
contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, I would like to thank the organizers for the invitation, as
well as, for a great organized event and kindly words from the trainees.
The group to the panel discussion was very enthusiasts, knowledgeable
and experience to share and to give an interesting ideas for the hence
actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conclusion from the discussion was made. As well as, that this is
just a step to bring the topic into Macedonia, and for the organizations
and groups to become more familiar and aware about the Hate Speech on
Internet as extremely important topic to be taken into consideration. In
additions, to emphases that in Macedonia is widespread in different
categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Slides:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/file/d/0B1472nuKPMN5WmtHNW56OEU2V1k/preview" width="640" height="480"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="hate speech"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="macedonia"></category><category term="sapka"></category><category term="cid"></category></entry></feed>