<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece - nato</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/feeds/nato.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://predragtasevski.com/</id><updated>2013-12-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Camp in Plav – Montenegro with Young, Smart and Enthusiast people – REACT 2013 Montenegro</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/12/camp-in-plav-montenegro-with-young-smart-and-enthusiast-people-react-2013-montenegro/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-12-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-12-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2013-12-09:/posts/2013/12/camp-in-plav-montenegro-with-young-smart-and-enthusiast-people-react-2013-montenegro/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m always in big favor when it comes to share, discuss and to spend six
days in camp with young, smart, enthusiast, academical, non-academical,
scholars, military, history critics and politicians in a venue in wild
beauty of Montenegro, near the Plavsko lake in Plav. The location of the
camp …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m always in big favor when it comes to share, discuss and to spend six
days in camp with young, smart, enthusiast, academical, non-academical,
scholars, military, history critics and politicians in a venue in wild
beauty of Montenegro, near the Plavsko lake in Plav. The location of the
camp was in a such a beautiful area. My eyes could not stop looking for
something, such as either it was the top of the mountain, or the Plavsko
lake, or even the green hills and valleys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, let me return to the main point here. Firstly I will like to
share a couple of history background of &lt;a href="http://www.reactmontenegro.me/"&gt;Regional Euro Atlantic Camp
REACT&lt;/a&gt;, organized by &lt;a href="http://www.alfacentar.org/"&gt;ALFA Center
Montenegro&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First REACT camp took place in 2008, since then it takes place every
year, until now six years. The best and intriguing part of this camp is
that each year the venue of the event is in different place, therefore
the participants have a change to meet the beauty of Montenegro. The
idea in behalf of the organizers is very good, and I do support them in
this matter. Sometimes Montenegro routs could be a very heavy for the
drivers, however still this beauty should be exposed to the rest of the
world. Additionally, each year the number of participants varies
depending on the applications. However, this year there where
participants from 25 different countries, which make is in total 75
participants from elsewhere, such as, Balkans countries, Ex-Soviet Union
countries, Hungary, Slovakia, Czech Republic and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning to the
&lt;a href="http://www.reactmontenegro.me/agenda/agenda.html"&gt;agenda&lt;/a&gt; of REACT
2013, it was quite densely deployed, with lectures, panel discussions,
etc. Although it was heavy still the best side was the picnic adventures
and cultural evenings. Please feel free to see the pictures below of the
post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I would like to take a time to concentrate more on the issue
of cyber security. During the event the
&lt;a href="http://www.reactmontenegro.me/agenda/list-of-speakers.html"&gt;speakers&lt;/a&gt;
where representative of governments from sixteen countries, as well as
NGOs, media, students, researchers, among the others. Mostly, the topics
where concentrating on intention to see the pros and cons of join to
NATO, where indeed the countries from this region have in mind. However,
when it comes to the goals of NATO, and new threats, such as cyber
threats, cyber crime coupled with strategies, framework and so on, only
one speaker it emphasized the importance of cyber security as one of the
greatest risk now a day and in future, of course. I will not delay too
much, as you might all unravel it was the USA Deputy Chief of Mission in
Montenegro, Mr. Jones. Mr. Jones was very precise in his speech,
moreover he mentioned the importance of infrastructure as well as the
stability and security in Balkan region. I would like to cite one of the
lectures, Mr. Petric he said “Together we are stronger!”. How the days
go by, I was just wondering and always trying to ask questions about the
cyber security, and the importance of this issue, however, most of the
speakers where no that specialized or somehow not interested of in fact
important unit of integration requirements in NATO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I was a moderator to a topic Kosovo open or close? The
question was which topics, fields are close or open, regarding the
Kosovo as a new country in the region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short summary, please feel free to see the pictures below and I hope
that in future to REACT Camp we will have much more discussions and
panels and topics about the new threats that we are facing. Likewise, I
always say, no matter how much we pour money in infrastructure and
security, still the weakest chain will be the human factor, because it
is not a aware of the importance of cyber security. Consequently, we
will have to keep in mind that this issue and importance of cyber
security is in benefits to wide security, economy and political aspects,
by process of joining and integrating the region to the path of NATO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Pictures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="375"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705121698%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705121698%2F&amp;set_id=72157648705121698&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705121698%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705121698%2F&amp;set_id=72157648705121698&amp;jump_to=" width="500" height="375"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="camp"></category><category term="react"></category><category term="nato"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="montenegro"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="cyberwar"></category><category term="cyber"></category><category term="plav"></category></entry><entry><title>Collective Cyber Defence – The Role of Newer Members and Opportunities for Specialization of Bulgaria in the Alliance Questions and answers</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/03/collective-cyber-defence-the-role-of-newer-members-and-opportunities-for-specialization-of-bulgaria-in-the-alliance-questions-and-answers/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2013-03-12:/posts/2013/03/collective-cyber-defence-the-role-of-newer-members-and-opportunities-for-specialization-of-bulgaria-in-the-alliance-questions-and-answers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;November is a month of &lt;a href="http://www.paneuropa.bg/en/news/38/PanEuropa-Bulgaria-organizes-international-conference-with-the-special-support-of-NATO" title="PanEuropa Bulgaria organizes international conference with the special support of NATO"&gt;Smart Defense and Open – Door Policy – New
Synergies for Euro –Atlantic
Security&lt;/a&gt;.
Not only in Europe, but also in South-East European region as well. The
following international event was organized
by &lt;a href="http://www.paneuropa.bg/" title="PanEuropa Bulgaria"&gt;PanEuropa Bulgaria&lt;/a&gt; and
it was supported by NATO. Furthermore, I was invited to take …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;November is a month of &lt;a href="http://www.paneuropa.bg/en/news/38/PanEuropa-Bulgaria-organizes-international-conference-with-the-special-support-of-NATO" title="PanEuropa Bulgaria organizes international conference with the special support of NATO"&gt;Smart Defense and Open – Door Policy – New
Synergies for Euro –Atlantic
Security&lt;/a&gt;.
Not only in Europe, but also in South-East European region as well. The
following international event was organized
by &lt;a href="http://www.paneuropa.bg/" title="PanEuropa Bulgaria"&gt;PanEuropa Bulgaria&lt;/a&gt; and
it was supported by NATO. Furthermore, I was invited to take a
participation as a speaker on the panel discussion Collective Cyber
Defence – The Role of Newer Members and Opportunities for Specialization
of Bulgaria in the Alliance Questions and answers. In details, the event
main points ware to highlight the need for specialization of each member
state in terms of the principles of Smart Defense and the joint
participation in future military operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the event had splendid video addressing in the opening session
of Neelie Kroes, the Vice – President of European Commission.
Emphasizing the current online spying crisis as well as the importance
of cyber security strategy. In additional, she highlighted the
importance of new legal threats, information norms coupled to boost the
trust among the Europe. As well as, that the weakest link in the chain
should be able to raise and boost the awareness, coupled with the future
investments in research and innovations, and projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding the collective cyber defense panel discussion, I was delighted
to be speaker with such strong extensive and experienced experts from
different fields. Such as private, public, academy and business sectors.
Speaking of which, the moderator of the panel was Prof. Veselin Tselkov,
D. Sc., Member of the Board, Commission for Personal Data Protection in
Bulgaria. The lectures where: unfortunately Col. Associate Prof. Dr.
Stoyan Balabanov, Director, Institute for Defense, Ministry of Defense
Bulgaria, was not able to attend the panel, however we had
representative from MoD. Also from Bulgaria was Zlatogor Minchev from
Institute of Information and Communication Technologies, Bulgaria. From
Macedonian was Dr. Metodi Hadji-Janev (LtC), Assistant Prof., Military
Academy ” General Mihailo Apostolski”, Skopje, Macedonia. From business
prospective I was the presenter of
&lt;a href="http://cybersecurity.mk" title="CyberSecurity.mk"&gt;CyberSecurity.mk&lt;/a&gt; copmany,
based in Macedonia. In addition, Mr. Robert Griffin, Director Business
Development – Security Systems, RSA. From all the above, we also had
video addressing from Mr. Detlef Puhl, Senior Advisor at the Emerging
Security Challenges Division, NATO Headquarters, and Mr. Philippe
Roggeband, Security Sales Business Development Manager, EBG EMEAR, Cisco
Systems. However, due to the security measures in the building where the
event was held the video addressing was interrupted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, here is my short presentation notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyberspace has become one of the most essential and distinguished
bridge between government and their inhabitants. Thus, the people are
able to get access to government services 24/7, as well as their life
becomes more easier. However, all in this has led to advance of
producing cyberspace to be vulnerable, coupled with information’s that
should not be available to others. For this reason I would like to
share three important points that are fundamental to emphasis when we
discuss about the Cyber defense in general. First, we have to
understand and highlight the difference between Cyber Security vs IT
Security. Second, it is the important to boost the awareness level
tailored to national level, social society, private sector and indeed
multistakeholder cooperation in the region. Last but not least, we
have to brake the lack of communications between the neighboring
countries and to create a trusted, same level, and collaboration of
cyber security. Where national agencies and parties should work
together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, first the main goal of IT security is to protect
information from a wide range of threats in order to ensure business
continuity, reduce business damages and maximize return on investments
and business opportunity. Likewise the cyber security is protecting
Information and Communication Technologies (ICT) systems and Critical
Infrastructure (CI). However the most important protection element in
IT security is to reduce business risk to accepted levels and the
protection of entire information and information systems essential to
the organizations. Alternatively, cyber security aims at assuring
critical IT service for CI and CII on accepted levels, in addition to
the protection of critical information. In other words the security
objective determiner in information security is an organization’s
business process, while in cyber security it is for the entire state.
Emphasizing that states may have different or complementary interests
compared to an organization’s business interests. On one hand,
handling cyber security problems is considered to be both a nationally
and internationally coordinated activity to protect national CII.
Similarly, to information security goals: confidentiality,
availability and integrity, in cyber security the additional goals are
non-repudiation, authentication, information systems importance and
criticality from the standpoint of state CII/CI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning to awareness, I would like to share my recent research that
have been published as book, title: Interactive Cyber Security
Awareness Program. It is highlighting the method, approach and the
importance of current awareness level in Western Balkans. Coupled how
to boost the awareness on the national level. I would not like to go
in details, however, just want to mention that the positive results
were presented, and that the awareness level among the end users are
varied. Moreover, in particular we have to create and recognize the
importance of establishing cyber security awareness strategy, coupled
with influence of the weakest link in cyber security, which is the
human factor, or in other words, social-technical aspects. In spite of
our investment in technologies and in the applications, still the
weakest link in cyber defense and security will the human behavior.
Therefore, we will have to conceive an awareness/education to raise
the awareness on the national behalf, such as, from the young to the
oldest generation, tailored through social society, private sector and
multistakeholder cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, in recent years we are witnesses of acts that have taken into
place between neighboring countries in the region. Such acts were
followed by different motivations of attacks. Where mostly they were
done through defacement’s or denial-of-service attacks. Thus,
motivations where divers. Nevertheless, in this last point is I would
like to stress the importance of merging the best practices learned
from past event occurrence as well as to improve the role of newer
members and opportunities into the collective roles of cyber defence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, I am keen that after this discussion/panel will lead into
further actions. And also thanks to the organizers for the invitation
and done a good job in organizing such an important event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Pictures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="375"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157646785203333%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157646785203333%2F&amp;set_id=72157646785203333&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157646785203333%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157646785203333%2F&amp;set_id=72157646785203333&amp;jump_to=" width="500" height="375"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="cyber defence"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="bulgaria"></category><category term="balkan"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="nato"></category></entry></feed>