<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece - attacks</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/feeds/tag/attacks.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://predragtasevski.com/</id><updated>2015-12-12T18:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Workshop: Cyber Security and Privacy</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/posts/2015/12/workshop-cs-privacy/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-12T18:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-12-12T18:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2015-12-12:/posts/2015/12/workshop-cs-privacy/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dark Moto Studio hosted me to deliver a two days workshop in the field of &lt;strong&gt;Cyber Security and Privacy&lt;/strong&gt;, between 12 - 13 of December 2015 in Verona, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="verona Workshop: Cyber Security and Privacy" src="https://scontent-vie1-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpl1/t31.0-8/12371120_456362121218149_5044654840342295836_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 1:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is cyber security and how the hackers think (4 hours)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to cyber security and privacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attacking phases …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dark Moto Studio hosted me to deliver a two days workshop in the field of &lt;strong&gt;Cyber Security and Privacy&lt;/strong&gt;, between 12 - 13 of December 2015 in Verona, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="verona Workshop: Cyber Security and Privacy" src="https://scontent-vie1-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpl1/t31.0-8/12371120_456362121218149_5044654840342295836_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 1:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is cyber security and how the hackers think (4 hours)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to cyber security and privacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attacking phases:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reconnaissance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scanning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaining Access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintaining/Expending Access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Covering Tracks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most common types of attacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is attack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is vulnerability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is exploit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demo of DoS/DDoS attack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 2:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to secure yourself using open source tools (4 hours)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Engineering and Social Networking manipulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secure browsing and firewalls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;E-mail and Instant Messaging – Chat security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up Security Wireless connection and network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secure your smart phones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/740993119377989/"&gt;FB Event link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Photos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Demo: network scanning" src="https://scontent-vie1-1.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-xpf1/t31.0-8/12487296_464598787061149_1198574937328096575_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pages"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="privacy"></category><category term="Italy"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="attacks"></category><category term="awareness"></category></entry><entry><title>What is network security?</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/posts/2012/10/what-is-network-security/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-26T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2012-10-26T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2012-10-26:/posts/2012/10/what-is-network-security/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A computer network, or in other words simply a network, is a collection
of computers and other hardware components interconnected by
communication channels that allow sharing of data, resources and
information [1]. Adopt for both_ private or public needs, which are
used in everyday tasks to conduct transactions and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A computer network, or in other words simply a network, is a collection
of computers and other hardware components interconnected by
communication channels that allow sharing of data, resources and
information [1]. Adopt for both_ private or public needs, which are
used in everyday tasks to conduct transactions and communications among
individuals, business, government agencies, etc. The network consists of
nodes, which are individual user computers (client terminals), and one
or more servers and/or host computers. Which are linked by communication
systems, some of might be private, for example company, and other which
might be open to public access. Obvious example of a network system that
is open to public access is the Internet, where indeed, many private
networks utilize publicly accessible communications, as well. Nowadays
for instance, company host computers can be accessed by their employees
whether in their offices over a private communications network, or from
their homes, or while there on the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is therefore, network security involves all activities that
individuals, organizations, enterprises and institutions are undertaking
to protect their value and on-going employment of assets and the
integrity and continuity of operations. For that reason this article
will introduce the readers and end users with the history of network
security. Furthermore, with an introduction of effective network
security strategy requires and most common network attacks methods.
Please bear in mind that in fact, this article is not going to discuss
over the depth details, rather than is going to deliver you introductory
knowledge and suggestions for further perusal. And finally, we will
finalize the article within conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;History&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Securing information over a network had its roots in the late 1960s when
networks only existed in the sense of huge mainframes and multiple
networked terminals. Hundreds of thousands and millions of dumb
terminals were connected via hubs and concentrators to the huge central
processing units, spinning tapes, and rotating drives in some distant
air-conditioned, properly humidifier windowless room [2]. Without the
presence of client-server network models, sharing or multi-user,
multi-tasking processors, network security was not yet a real concern.
Network security, however, has evolved over the years due to the
increasing reliance on public networks not to disclose personal,
financial, and other restricted information [3]. Such as, there are
numerous instances Kevin Mitnick [4] and Vladimir Levin [5] cases that
prompted organizations across all industries to re-think the way they
handle information, including its transmission and disclosure. The
popularity of the Internet was one of the most important developments
that prompted an intensified effort in data security [3].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A growing number of people are using their personal computers to gain
access to the resources that the Internet has to offer. From electronic
email, commerce transactions and research interests, the Internet has
taken place as one of the most important development of 20th century.
However, the Internet Protocol (IP) in early stage was not designed to
be secure. There were no approved securities standards build into the
Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) and IP communication stack, which
allowing it open to potentially malicious users and processes across the
network. Where modern developments have made Internet communication more
secure, yet there are still incidents that gain eminent attention and
alert us to the fact that nothing is completely safe and secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where in early 2000 a different type of attacks were unleashed on
several of the most heavily trafficked site on the Internet, such as,
yahoo.com, cnn.com, amazon.com and many others. Furthermore, in 2007, a
data breach exploiting the widely known weaknesses of the Wired
Equivalent Privacy (WEP) wireless encryption protocol resulted [6].
Indefinitely all those incidents have granted billion of records and
money to end up in the behalf of the thief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, these results enforce the reality that computer and network
security has become a quantifiable and justifiable expense for IT
budgets. Organizations that require data integrity and high availability
elicit the skills of system administrators, developers, and engineers to
ensure 24×7 reliability of their systems, services, and information.
Falling victim to malicious users, processes, or coordinated attacks is
a direct threat to the success of the organization, as well as
individual [3].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Network Security&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;System and network technology is in fact a key technology for a wide
variety of applications. Security is crucial factor to networks and
applications. Although, network security is a critical requirement in
emerging networks, there is a significant lack of security methods that
can be easily implemented [7].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an existing communication gap between the developers of
security technology and developers of networks. When considering network
security, it must be emphasized that the while network is secured.
Moreover, network security does not only concern the security in the
computers at each end of communication sequence. Also when transmitting
data the communication channel should not be vulnerable to attack. A
hacker could target the communication channel, and could obtain the
data, and decrypt it and re-insert a false value. In fact, securing the
network is just as important as securing the computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result when developing a secure network, the following need to be
considered [8]:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Access – authorized users are provided the means to communicate to and
from a particular network&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confidentiality – Information in the network remains private&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authentication – Ensure the users of the network are who they say they
are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrity – Ensure the message has not been modified in transit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non‐repudiation – Ensure the user does not refute that he used the
network&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, an effective network security plan is developed with the
understanding of security issues, potential attackers and attacking
methods, needed level of security, and factors that make a network
vulnerable to attack. The different attacking methods are followed
throughout this article endeavour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Common Network Attacks Methods&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whiteout implemented security measures and controls in place, your
network and data might be subjected to an attack. Some attacks for
instance could be passive, meaning that information is monitored; other
could be active, meaning the information is varying within intent to
destroy or corrupt the data or the network itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likelihood your networks and data are vulnerable to any of the following
types of attacks if you do not have a security plan in place [9]:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eavesdropping – Interception of communications by an unauthorized
    party&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Modification – Data altering, reading from unauthorized party&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identity Spoofing (IP Address Spoofing) – IP address to be falsely
    assumed— identity spoofing and the attacker can modify, reroute, or
    delete your data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password-Based Attacks – By gaining your access rights to a computer
    and network resources are determined by who you are, that is, your
    user name and your password&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Denial-of-Service Attack – Prevents normal use of your computer or
    network by valid users, and it could be used for sending invalid
    data to application, to flood the computer, block traffic, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Man-in-the-Middle Attack – Is when someone between you and the
    person with whom you are communicating is actively monitoring,
    capturing, and controlling your communication transparently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application-Layer Attack – It targets application servers by
    deliberately causing a fault in a server’s operating system or
    applications and the attacker gaining the ability to bypass normal
    access controls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anyhow, this is just a most commonly known network attacks methods,
    and indeed there plenty of more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why network security is an important field that is increasingly
gaining attention as the Internet usage increases. The security threats
and Internet protocols were analysed to determine the necessary security
technology. However, the current development in network security is not
very impressive and significant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, researchers and scholars are rapidly evolving in developing
and investigating the threats further in a future. And with this
information in mind, the process can be formalized and the path becomes
clearer as you delve deeper into the specifics of the security process,
as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] Computer network definition, Retrieved from
http://www.atis.org/glossary/definition.aspx?id=6555&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] Stallings, William, Internet Security Handbook, IDG Books Worldwide,
Inc., 1995.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3] RedHat, Inc, Chapter 1. Security Overview. Retrieved from
https://access.redhat.com/knowledge/docs/en-US/Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux/6/html/Security_Guide/chap-Security_Guide-Security_Overview.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4] Kevin Mitnick Case: 1999 – No Bail, No Computer, Hacker Pleads
Guilty. Retrieved from
http://law.jrank.org/pages/3791/Kevin-Mitnick-Case-1999.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[5] Vladimir Levin. Retrieved from
http://www.livinginternet.com/i/ia_hackers_levin.htm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[6] Dan Goodin, May 2007. Lax security led to TJX breach. Retrieved from
http://www.theregister.co.uk/2007/05/04/txj_nonfeasance/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[7] Bhavya Daya, Network Security: History, Importance, and Future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[8] Dowd, P.W.; McHenry, J.T., “Network security: it’s time to take it
seriously,” Computer, vol.31, no.9, pp.24‐28, Sep 1998&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[9] Common Types of Network Attacks. Retrieved from:
http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/cc959354.aspx&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pages"></category><category term="network security"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="access"></category><category term="confidentiality"></category><category term="authentication"></category><category term="non-repudation"></category><category term="DDoS"></category><category term="Man-in-the-middle"></category><category term="attacks"></category><category term="address spoofing"></category><category term="eavesdropping"></category></entry><entry><title>Ministry of Interior – Macedonia, website defacement: http://mvr.gov.mk</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/posts/2012/06/ministry-of-interior-macedonia-website-defacement-httpmvrgovmk/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-06-25T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2012-06-25T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2012-06-25:/posts/2012/06/ministry-of-interior-macedonia-website-defacement-httpmvrgovmk/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Purpose&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the 25 of June 2012, the Macedonian website of Ministry of
Interior (MVR) was defaced by Kosovo Network Security (KNS) group, below
figure. However, after we have noticed and some of the social networking
sites have informed me, I was concern to find out what just have
happened …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Purpose&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the 25 of June 2012, the Macedonian website of Ministry of
Interior (MVR) was defaced by Kosovo Network Security (KNS) group, below
figure. However, after we have noticed and some of the social networking
sites have informed me, I was concern to find out what just have
happened and how did happen, and of course how they have done it. So for
this purpose, I have done some digging into details, about the previous
defacement activities of this very important government site. But before
we continue with more details, let just talk about the situation of
yesterday and what did the authorities take protective measures steps
and actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, 25 June 2012 at 19:38, one friend have updated his status in
one of the social networking sites, as follows: “Хакован
&lt;a href="http://mvr.gov.mk/"&gt;http://mvr.gov.mk/&lt;/a&gt;” (Hacked &lt;a href="http://mvr.gov.mk/"&gt;http://mvr.gov.mk/&lt;/a&gt;). And it made me
extremely intrigue to see what actually have just happened. The below
figure, displays the message spread from the KNS group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Screenshot from the mvr.gov.mk defaced version&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, what makes the situation even more interesting is that after
the report that the site was defaced the authorities have taken a
measures steps to fix the issue, by either shutting down the server or
restoring the content of the site from the backup. Then after one or two
minutes the site was defaced again. I did not want to lose the time and
the nervous to check every five or ten minutes to see when it will be
back again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, after 15 hours, or one stressful – hard core night for the
administrators of the site, the usability and functionalities where back
as normal, let just see how long will stay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, in the current post the idea is to give and overview, of what
actually is going on when it comes to case of cyber space, cyber
security issues in Macedonia. The structure of this post is introduces
first with the issue, or the problem that actuality made me to write
this post. Followed by the background investigation about the previous
defacement activities on the Ministry of Interior website in Macedonia.
Then with the background investigation about the KNS group, moreover,
with the self pen-testing site with different attacking methodologies.
And finally, closing by with a conclusion and action plan that should be
taken, for hence actions. This post does not only involves the public
sector, but even and the private sector too. Those agencies,
organizations are too much careless and do not take any actions of
securing their IT assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ministry of Interior in Macedonia site offers different online services.
The site primary idea is to inform the inhabitance about the news,
actions, useful information, public relations, analysis and statistics;
international cooperation and legislation; and finally the services. And
secondly is to give and opportunities to the population scheduling of
service, if their document is issued, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one short sentence, this site, for some people, it may be very useful
or not. However, I need to empathize that the site is only available in
Macedonian language, nor Albania, nor English version. So, in simple
conclusion this site is only useful for Macedonian speakers, and not for
foreigners, yet still represents one of very important public service,
government agency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, in the next section we will discuses the previous
defacement and hacking attacks of this site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Background&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The service of this site, or the domain first was registered in 22
October 2003, and unfortunate I do not remember when was first time
available and published. However, in the pass years I have heard many
times that this site was defaced and hacked, but still no actions or
results were shown. Therefore, it made me very interesting to find out,
if this defacement activities where notified and when and how many
where. For this purpose I have use a site service that I know few years
ago, the &lt;a href="http://www.zone-h.org/"&gt;Zone-H&lt;/a&gt;. Moreover,
&lt;a href="http://www.zone-h.org/"&gt;Zone-H&lt;/a&gt; is neither responsible for the reported
computer crimes nor it is directly or indirectly involved with them, it
is just and simple site where collects the cybercrime activities
notified anonymously. The bellow figure provides a details of previous
reported/notified cybercrime activities of MVR site in Macedonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In details, total notifications are 4 of which 2 are single IP and 2 are
mass defacements. The first mass defacement was done in 29 July 2009,
when the site use a OS: Windows 2000, then in 2011 it was the
re-defacement and the server operating system is Windows 2008. Followed
by the other massive defacement in this year 2012 in March 18, and same
year, few days before the current attack, 22 of June it was
re-defacement. And the attack, defacement that we write for it was not
notified or reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From these data, and schedule, we can come to a conclusion that the site
was defaced just 3 days before the mass defacement attack, so it might
be a simple warning, to taken an action before something goes really
wrong. But most probably, non of those administrators, or authorities
did not taken any serious actions, until the case yesterday appears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Details&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be able to do an analysis of what actually have happened, we need to
take some actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we have done a simple web sniffer, to find out what kind of
system, and services the site, server is using. If we request the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_HTTP_header_fields"&gt;HTTP
Request Header&lt;/a&gt;
we will receive an HTTP Response Header with a following data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    Status: HTTP/1.1 200 OKCache-Control: privateContent-Type: text/html; charset=utf-8Server: Microsoft-IIS/7.0Set-Cookie: ASP.NET_SessionId=3lti3gep3usg4255ggf34tjn; path=/; HttpOnlyX-AspNet-Version: 2.0.50727X-Powered-By: ASP.NETDate: Tue, 26 Jun 2012 08:18:34 GMTConnection: closeContent-Length: 103773

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above data, is useful in a sense that provides as an information
about the Server and the ASP.Net Version. Then, if we want to find more
details about the open and close ports and operating system we can use
the &lt;a href="http://nmap.org/"&gt;nmap&lt;/a&gt; tool with the following command line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;nmap -O -v IP-Address&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the results will be as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    PORT STATE SERVICE21/tcp open ftp80/tcp open httpRunning (JUST GUESSING) : Microsoft Windows Vista|2008|7 (89%)

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the web sniffing and from the OS version scanning we can assume
that the server is running Microsoft Windows 2008. The current
vulnerabilities and possible exploitations are visible on the &lt;a href="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/security/bulletin/"&gt;Microsoft
Security
Bulletins&lt;/a&gt;
website. By knowing the vulnerabilities it is very easy task to find out
a way either to commit DoS attack or remote server access. However, in
this post we will not go into details and exploitation descriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the KNS, we assume the domain is followed:
&lt;a href="http://kns-team.com/"&gt;http://kns-team.com&lt;/a&gt;. However, the site is down,
therefore, we will have to understand who is behind this domain
registration. Therefore, we will use the whois database to understand
more, or even we can use another site that have been defaced by this
group to find out more. So there is the list presented the members in
the groups and their archive of notified defaced sites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.zone-h.org/archive/notifier=cracker-besi"&gt;rAcKeR-BeSi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.zone-h.org/archive/notifier=L0wHacker"&gt;L0wHacker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sLizer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X-r00t&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SpyHackz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Facebook fan page is:
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Kosova-Network-Security/176195849098989"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/pages/Kosova-Network-Security/176195849098989&lt;/a&gt;.
For more info I was short of time to do more digging, but I hope that
someone will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Action&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After understanding the details about the MVR site, operating system and
their server services, and information about the KNS, it is time to take
an action of trying to see how vulnerable is MVR site, and to see if
these lads had very difficult time of defacing the content of the site,
or even gaining access to the server-side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before, we carry on, I want to stress out that this section is not
to give you an idea how, or knowledge to exploit or use any
vulnerabilities to deface or gain access to the site. We will just
demonstrate you a very simple
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-site_scripting"&gt;XSS&lt;/a&gt; exploit of MVR
site that we have found a vulnerability, figure below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example of exploitation by XSS vulnerability, mvr.gov.mk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is therefore, from this very simple and easy exploitation of XSS
vulnerability of the MVS site we will be able to run more advance and
complicated shell scripts to gain access and maintain access of the
server. Our initial idea is not to show you how to do it, but to expose
to the audience that actually hence actions is need it. And we hope that
the administrators, developers and the authorities will take an action
of mitigating the risk, and further vulnerabilities of the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Macedonia, cyber space, cyber crime, cyber security, cyber warefare,
cyber terrorism are actually unknown words, terminology. They are not
even specified or added into the Macedonian dictionary, nor in IT
dictionary. However, this is not the first or least defacement, attack
that has happened in Macedonia, nor the first attack that has been done,
implemented by neighbor countries, or someone else. I just don’t
understand why people in this country are so careless about how to
protect their IT assets, and everything else, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it is not an issue that we do not have specialists to
conduct a pen-testing to the sites and services that not only the
government agencies are offering but even the banks and private sectors
as well. We even have a cyber crime unit in Ministry of Interior, and
one of very successful information security research and development
laboratory in Macedonia: &lt;a href="http://www.zeroscience.mk/en/"&gt;Zero Science
Lab&lt;/a&gt;. Also, the &lt;a href="http://cybersecurity.mk/icsap/"&gt;ICSAP – Interactive
Cyber Security Awareness Program&lt;/a&gt;,
Macedonia project, developed by myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, in final conclusion, I would like to recommend the
authorities to take actions about the above described activities done by
KNS and hope that the security awareness will boost up, and the further
actions will be considered of securing cyber space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pages"></category><category term="Attacks"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="information warfare"></category><category term="legal aspects of cyber security"></category><category term="log mining"></category><category term="DDoS"></category><category term="exploitation"></category><category term="kns"></category><category term="macedonia"></category><category term="mvr"></category><category term="online"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="vulnerability"></category><category term="expolit"></category></entry><entry><title>Clever solution by making site more resilient by optimization</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/posts/2012/03/clever-solution-by-making-site-more-resilient-by-optimization/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-03-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-03-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2012-03-23:/posts/2012/03/clever-solution-by-making-site-more-resilient-by-optimization/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;PURPOSE &amp;amp; SCENARIO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective of this laboratory test, scenario is to make explore
alternative “clever” solutions (as opposed to making the site more
resilient by optimizing it) to protect your site against attacks.
Moreover, DDoS [1] attacks, malicious code, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, we need to develop countermeasures for the &lt;strong&gt;working&lt;/strong&gt;
attacks …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;PURPOSE &amp;amp; SCENARIO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective of this laboratory test, scenario is to make explore
alternative “clever” solutions (as opposed to making the site more
resilient by optimizing it) to protect your site against attacks.
Moreover, DDoS [1] attacks, malicious code, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, we need to develop countermeasures for the &lt;strong&gt;working&lt;/strong&gt;
attacks simulated with a standard DoS attack from a single IP address
(performed with AB [2] or Jmeter). Limitations for this scenarios is
highlighted:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No additional hardware can be used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The wordpress installation can not be optimized: no caching plugins,
    no reverse-proxy (varnish, squid etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No reactive measures that automatically block incoming traffic: the
    site must respond to at least some of the requests coming from the
    attacker at all times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The countermeasures must not have negative effects on “normal usage
    pattern”. Normal usage pattern is defined as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bursts of 10 connections per IP address in 1 second&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Page load times not over 10 seconds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
-   Normal usage must be possible from the same IP address that the
attack originated from after a 20 second delay maximum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, we have to make much of the rules for the scenario. Rules
as follow: Fresh installation of the latest version of Ubuntu Server and
the most recent WordPress as of 20.10.2011. First priority: No normal
usage pattern connections can be dropped! Second priority: service speed
of normal connections. Defined by number of connections / second (easy
to measure). Third priority: How fast after the attack is stopped, the
site can be accessed from the attacking IP again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each test and measured results will be exposed in to Test section.
Whereas, the process of installation of clever solution and attacking
scripts will be provided in to Appendixes section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the measurement results will be compared with the first state
without attack and any security solutions applied. Alternatively,
providing measurement results with one solution and attack will help us
to identify the most beneficial security solution. Therefore, in
Conclusion section comparison results will be highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;TESTS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of requirements of our scenario we need to display the results
before security solution is applied and attacker performance. For this
purpose we are going to use an AB script to display the response time of
the server:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ab -t 10 -n 10 -c 10 http://192.168.56.102/wordpress/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above script provides detail information, yet only important is
Request per second. Thus, with an fresh installation and without any
security solution, it provided with result of 3.95 [#/sec]. With other
word, 3.95 number of request per second. After applying different
security solution and performing an attack to the server, results will
be divers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, test were done by two different virtual environment
machines. One is for testing results and the other one is to perform
attack with the following script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ab -n 100 -c 10 http://192.168.56.102/wordpress/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;TEST 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First test is to install libapache2-mod-evasive
[libapache2-mod-evasive]. Where, mod_evasive is an evasive maneuvers
module for Apache is to provide some protection in the event of an HTTP
DoS or DDoS attack or brute force attack. It is also designed to be a
detection tool, and can be easily configured to talk to ipchains,
firewalls, routers, and etcetera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process of installation and configuration refer to the Appendix 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After completed the installation and configuration process it is time to
test the security solution and to highlight the results. Before
performing the attack the results were somehow, lower then, before
installing the mod-evasive, 2.06 number request per second. When we
start the attack and in same time analysis the server responded with
timeout. The conclusion is that mod-evasive it is not enough solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;TEST 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From previous test we can see that the solution was not enough clever
for our needs. The server somehow was dead. However, we are going to
install now &lt;code&gt;mod_security&lt;/code&gt; module for apache, with side of previous
test. For more detail information of installation process and
configuration refer to Appendix 2 or to the following source
[mod_security].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three points that we should consider and to see which proposal
was more accurate and it did the job that was required in the scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the above proposals are nice and good example to have an
view of how and with what tools we should perform script kiddie
techniques. How to shutdown access to a server. On the whole, it show as
how to use tools and methods of measuring the bandwidth of network and
how to limit the transfer in comfortable way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;APPENDIXES&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appendix 1 is connected with the Method 1, which highlighted points are
illustration on what information we should check, to clarify that the
virtual environment has limitation of the network interface. Where
Appendix 2 is for installation process of Ubuntu Server 10.04 LTS and
wordpress, mysql installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;APPENDIX 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install libapache2-mod-evasive&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configuration process is followed and gather from the following source
[Evasive Module], for addition proposal please refer to[Blacklist]:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    sudo mkdir /var/log/apache2/mod_evasivesudo chown www-data /var/log/apache2/mod_evasive

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, create its configuration file with a default content, with
the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    sudo nano /etc/apache2/apache2.conf IfModule mod_evasive20.c;DOSHashTableSize 3097DOSPageCount 2DOSSiteCount 50DOSPageInterval 1DOSSiteInterval 1DOSBlockingPeriod 10DOSLogDir /var/log/apache2/mod_evasiveDOSEmailNotify root@localhostDOSWhitelist 127.0.0.1DOSSystemCommand &amp;amp;quot;/sbin/iptables -I INPUT -p tcp --dport 80 -s %s -j DROP/IfModule;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above changes to take effect please restart the apache service by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo service apache2 restart&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can test whether it works using a script included in the deb
package:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;perl /usr/share/doc/libapache2-mod-evasive/examples/test.pl&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;APPENDIX 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation and configuration of mod_security:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install libapache2-modsecurity /etc/init.d/apache2 force-reload&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation media: Ubuntu 11.10 32bit iso image;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HW: Virtualbox, 1CPU 32bit, 512MB RAM, 8GB HD (dynamic allocation);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC1 NAT;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC2 host only (for ssh and http access from host);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language used in installation process: English and country Estonia;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyboard Layout English;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no http proxy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install lamp phpmyadmin&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;wget -c http://wordpress.org/latest.tar.gz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;tar xvjf latest.tar.gz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo cp wordpress /var/www/wordpress&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nano /var/www/wordpress/wp-config.php&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the settings to your needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[libapache2-mod-evasive] Canonical Ltd., Package: libapache2-mod-evasive
(1.10.1-1), 2011,
&lt;a href="http://packages.ubuntu.com/hardy/libapache2-mod-evasive"&gt;http://packages.ubuntu.com/hardy/libapache2-mod-evasive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[modsecurity] How to Forge, Secure Your Apache With mod_security, 2006,
&lt;a href="http://www.howtoforge.com/apache_mod_security"&gt;http://www.howtoforge.com/apache_mod_security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Evasive Module] Deep Logic, Inc., Apache Evasive Maneuvers Module,
2005,
&lt;a href="http://fossies.org/unix/www/apache_httpd_modules/mod_evasive_1.10.1.tar.gz:t/mod_evasive/README"&gt;http://fossies.org/unix/www/apache_httpd_modules/mod_evasive_1.10.1.tar.gz:t/mod_evasive/README&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Blacklist] Jeff Starr, Eight Ways to Blacklist with Apache’s
mod_rewrite, Feb 2009,
&lt;a href="http://perishablepress.com/press/2009/02/03/eight-ways-to-blacklist-with-apaches-mod_rewrite/"&gt;http://perishablepress.com/press/2009/02/03/eight-ways-to-blacklist-with-apaches-mod_rewrite/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] DDoS – Denial-of-service attack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] AB - &lt;a href="http://httpd.apache.org/docs/2.0/programs/ab.html"&gt;http://httpd.apache.org/docs/2.0/programs/ab.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pages"></category><category term="ab"></category><category term="attacks"></category><category term="clever solution"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="DDoS"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="jmeter"></category><category term="malicious code"></category><category term="wordpress"></category></entry><entry><title>Script Kiddie</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/posts/2011/10/script-kiddie/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-10-19T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2011-10-19T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2011-10-19:/posts/2011/10/script-kiddie/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;PURPOSE and SCENARIO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this laboratory test is to make effort to attack server and
to deface website. Here is the scenario: your client is worried about
some stuff posted on a blog. They ask You to take care of it. They have
a throwaway “script kiddie”[Script …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;PURPOSE and SCENARIO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this laboratory test is to make effort to attack server and
to deface website. Here is the scenario: your client is worried about
some stuff posted on a blog. They ask You to take care of it. They have
a throwaway “script kiddie”[Script kiddie] in a third world country, who
will mount the attack so You don’t need to worry about hiding the
attackers identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, we need to devise a way to attack wordpress (default
installation) based site to render it unusable (page view times over 60
seconds). Attack resources: one PC with Microsoft Windows XP, a script
kiddie, internet connection of 2Mbit/s. In addition, server has to stay
down for two days and script kiddie has up to 1 day to set up the
attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For scenario above their three different proposals from the fallow
students. Each proposal is described in section Proposals and their
effectiveness, installation process and the evaluation of the efficient
use of available resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, easy solution for limiting the internet connection of 2Mbit/s
by Oracle VirtualBox configuration manager. Secondly, the bandwidth
capacity of the connection and their performance is measured by vnstat1
for graphs to display our utilization. The steps are vivid on section
Methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, providing measurement results with different proposals will
help us to identify the most beneficial proposal for above scenario,
declared in Conclusion section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, after each attack, test the virtual server environment is
restarted, because of the affective situation that server after attack
needs time to recover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;METHODS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of requirements of our scenario we need to limit the internet
connection of 2 Mbit/s and to provide graphs that can help as with the
measurement results to conclude which proposals is more competent.
Therefore, Method 1 is describing the step how we limited the connection
bandwidth and Method 2 providing as solution how to setup that can help
you in measuring the speed and the bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;METHOD 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For limiting the internet traffic of the server we have to do the
following steps in command prompt. The following solution is gathered
from Manual of Oracle Virtualbox, Chapter 8 [User Manual].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Limiting VirtualBox – virtual environment speed of network interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    VBoxManage modifyvm "[name of virtualbox]" --nicspeed2 2048

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where you need to replace name of virtual box with real one, and specie
which network interface adapter you wont to limited. In the above
illustration is only second network adapter affected and then you set
the limitation, in our case is 2 Mbit/s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, to make sure that the result have been effective please use
the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    VBoxManage showvminfo "[name of virtualbox]"

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Results and information important to be aware refer to Appendix 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;METHOD 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are going to install an application that will help us to gather a
visual graphs of traffic manipulation of script kiddie. The application
is vnstat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the server virtual environment in command prompt please type the
following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    sudo apt-get install vnstat&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next step is to select which interface should be monitored and create
graphs. In our case is eth1, which is second network interface. For
furthermore detailed installation process please refer to the following
link:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.4geeksfromnet.com/2009/04/graphical-bandwidth-monitor-for-ubuntu.html"&gt;http://www.4geeksfromnet.com/2009/04/graphical-bandwidth-monitor-for-ubuntu.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To check if the installation process is finished please use your
browser, as shown in illustration 1 and on the address bar type:
http://192.168.56.102/vnstat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration 1: Vnstat PHP interface&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;PROPOSALS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three proposals are following and described in each different
section and their results. The main measure goal which is going to grate
for kiddie script is: easy to use instructions, the most efficient use
of available resources and can the script be up to 1 day attacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the results will be provided with two different graphs in
period of 5 minutes attack and 10 minutes attack. Which would guide us
to compare which kiddie script has performed the attack more in force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;PROPOSAL 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first proposal and the installation process instruction:
Script kiddie uses a little program to connection flood the WordPress
installation! The program uses Apache autobench to take the site down in
seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guide for the scipt Kiddie:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download the program from
    &lt;a href="http://enos.itcollege.ee/~avein/anti2.rar"&gt;http://enos.itcollege.ee/~avein/anti2.rar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unpack and run AntiXakkerv2.0.exe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the address for wordpress site and press the button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above script did no run/work on the VirtualMachine Windows XP.
Therefore, from the same author we have other solution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​1. Download
&lt;a href="http://enos.itcollege.ee/%7Eavein/anti.exe"&gt;http://enos.itcollege.ee/\~avein/anti.exe&lt;/a&gt;,
save it on Desktop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​2. Open Start menu, select run and type “cmd” into the box and press
enter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​3. Drag anti.exe file to the black box (commandline) , select the box
and type the address of your server ( eg. www.delfi.ee ) after the
anti.exe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if the address for your webserver is 192.168.56.101 type
the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    anti.exe 192.168.56.101&lt;br&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press enter and the site will go down very soon :=) P.S. This is
    lightweight version tat doesnot use much bandwith and is targeted
    against a bug in apache server :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;RESULT 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After running the first proposal we can see that the script kiddie does
attack the server, but the server was reachable after a bit long delay,
but still we could access to the wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some results graphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 minutes attack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration 2: Proposal 1, 5 min, traffic graph&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 minutes attack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration 3: Proposal 1, 10 min, traffic graph&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the one hand the script kiddie did attack the server, but on the
other hand the server was still accessible. I’d like to conclude by
stating that the above script did not meet our needs, and it did not
stop, bring down the response time of the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;PROPOSAL 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second proposal and the installation process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You (Script kiddie) download the file from &lt;a href="http://share.ee/x49176f"&gt;http://share.ee/x49176f&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will get an warning message, but you continue to download anyway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In chrome it looks like this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Execute the file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will get a warning but continue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will look something like this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insert the URL to attack and define how long you want to attack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will look like&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enjoy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The script is basic vbscript that will overwhelm the server by as many
connections that are required to keep the server down for as long as you
define.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above script did not work on the laboratory performance, because it
had an code error. Therefore, for this proposal we are not able to
provide you with the result graphs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;PROPOSAL 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third proposal and the installation process is listed below: There is a
free and very easy Denial of service script written in PHP, called
Keep-Dead (Version 1.14). You can download it from the following link:
&lt;a href="http://www.esrun.co.uk/blog/imp/2011/03/Keep-Dead.zip"&gt;http://www.esrun.co.uk/blog/imp/2011/03/Keep-Dead.zip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is developed for a research purpose, but still we can use it for our
scenario. The good think is primarily meant for use via the terminal;
although it will also work if launched via the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unpack the Keep-Dead.zip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open in notepad or any other text/script editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On line #26 change the
    &lt;code&gt;$target_url = “http://www.example.com/wordpress/?s=%rand%”;&lt;/code&gt; to our
    targeted wordpress blog. We can stop even certain page or post in
    wordpres or use of &lt;code&gt;%rand%&lt;/code&gt; for a random value to be automatically
    generated for each individual request • You can change the maximum
    number of requests to be made on line #32&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changeable is maximum number of requests to be made per connection
    #37, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After setting the setting of our needs save the file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And in terminal you need to run the following script:
    &lt;code&gt;php –e keep-dead.php&lt;/code&gt; or if you run a xamp or other webserver it is
    possible to run the script from your browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can terminate the script by pressing CTRL+C in terminal console
    or stop/close the browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information or video tutorials please refer to the following
link: &lt;a href="http://www.esrun.co.uk/blog/keep-alive-dos-script/"&gt;http://www.esrun.co.uk/blog/keep-alive-dos-script/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we follow the above steps we can perform our scenario 3 to make the
server to stay down for two days or even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There many ways to keep the server down for two days, this script for me
is kind of easy usable. In addition, the author had provide and more
details with following content: In addition of my proposal pls install
the following script:
&lt;a href="http://windows.php.net/downloads/releases/php-5.3.8-nts-Win32-VC9-x86.msi"&gt;http://windows.php.net/downloads/releases/php-5.3.8-nts-Win32-VC9-x86.msi&lt;/a&gt;
in the installation process in the section of Select Web Server you wish
to setup please chose Do not setup a web server -&gt; Next click on the
PHP small narrow down icon and select Entire future will be installed on
local hard drive (second option) -&gt; Next -&gt;Install&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results and graphs of the above proposal are demonstrated in the
next section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the script that actually does the job and it keeps the server
down until the script is down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;RESULT 3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test results are following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​1. 5 minutes attack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration 4: Proposal 3, 5 min, traffic graph&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 minutes attack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration 5: Proposal 3, 10 min, traffic graph&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A case in point is that from the above graphs we can see that the server
does get more traffic and it does get attacked by the script kiddie.
Illustration 6, bellow demonstrated that actually the server is down, is
not responding any more to requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration 6: Proposal 3, server down after trying to reach the blog&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three points that we should consider and to see which proposal
was more accurate and it did the job that was required in the scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I would like to start with rating from 1 to 5 each proposal.
Higher score present better results. Which is proving our destination to
hold down the server for longer then one day. The bellow table
demonstrates which proposal has succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;th&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;th align="center"&gt;
Proposal 1

&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;th align="center"&gt;
Proposal 2

&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;th align="right"&gt;
Proposal 3

&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
Easy installation

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
5

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
5

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
4

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
Server down

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
3

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
1

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
5

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
TOTAL

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
8

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="center"&gt;
6

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
9

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the scoring rate 3 of server down is means that the server was down,
but after few seconds was retrievable. Where the highest score 5 means
that the server was not retrievable during this proposal test until we
shutdown or cancel the process of script kiddie. In addition, the
Proposal 3 due to a code error was not able to perform attack, that is
why it is graded with server down score of 1. Therefore, our winner for
this laboratory test is Proposal 3 with script kiddie Keep-dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next issue that I would like to focus is to the network speed,
tested with other tool bmon2 which manifests that the speed limit of the
bandwidth did not go over the 2 Mbit/s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the above proposals are nice and good example to have an
view of how and with what tools we should perform script kiddie
techniques. How to shutdown access to a server. On the whole, it show as
how to use tools and methods of measuring the bandwidth of network and
how to limit the transfer in comfortable way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;APPENDIXES&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appendix 1 is connected with the Method 1, which highlighted points are
illustration on what information we should check, to clarify that the
virtual environment has limitation of the network interface. Where
Appendix 2 is for installation process of Ubuntu Server 10.04 LTS and
wordpress, mysql installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;APPENDIX 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    Name: ubuntu-serverGuest OS: UbuntuUUID: fe16451a-f8b1-4ceb-bb90-8650d08c3c0eConfig file: C:\Users\predrag\Documents\Master_CyberSecurity\VirtualBox VMs\ubuntu-server\ubuntu-server.vboxSnapshot folder: C:\Users\predrag\Documents\Master_CyberSecurity\VirtualBox VMs\ubuntu-server\SnapshotsLog folder: C:\Users\predrag\Documents\Master_CyberSecurity\VirtualBox VMs\ubuntu-server\LogsHardware UUID: fe16451a-f8b1-4ceb-bb90-8650d08c3c0eMemory size: 512MBPage Fusion: offVRAM size: 12MBCPU exec cap: 100%HPET: offChipset: piix3Firmware: BIOSNumber of CPUs: 1Synthetic Cpu: offCPUID overrides: NoneBoot menu mode: message and menuBoot Device (1): FloppyBoot Device (2): DVDBoot Device (3): HardDiskBoot Device (4): Not AssignedACPI: onIOAPIC: offPAE: offTime offset: 0 msRTC: UTCHardw. virt.ext: onHardw. virt.ext exclusive: offNested Paging: onLarge Pages: onVT-x VPID: onState: running (since 2011-10-11T11:26:30.089000000)Monitor count: 13D Acceleration: off2D Video Acceleration: offTeleporter Enabled: offTeleporter Port: 0Teleporter Address:Teleporter Password:Storage Controller Name (0): IDE ControllerStorage Controller Type (0): PIIX4Storage Controller Instance Number (0): 0Storage Controller Max Port Count (0): 2Storage Controller Port Count (0): 2Storage Controller Bootable (0): onStorage Controller Name (1): SATA ControllerStorage Controller Type (1): IntelAhciStorage Controller Instance Number (1): 0Storage Controller Max Port Count (1): 30Storage Controller Port Count (1): 1Storage Controller Bootable (1): onSATA Controller (0, 0): C:\Users\predrag\Documents\Master_CyberSecurity\VirtualBox VMs\ubuntu-server\ubuntu-server.vdi (UUID: bf4c167a-ec0a-42fa-915f-2ffbe2fd66fb) NIC 1: MAC: 0800274572ED, Attachment: NAT, Cable connected: on, Trace:off (file: none), Type: 82540EM, &lt;span style="color: #ff0000;"&gt;Reported speed: 2 Mbps&lt;/span&gt;, Boot priority: 0, Promisc Policy: denyNIC 1 Settings: MTU: 0, Socket (send: 64, receive: 64), TCP Window (send:64, receive: 64) NIC 2: MAC: 0800270858EA, Attachment: Host-only Interface 'VirtualBoxHost-Only Ethernet Adapter', Cable connected: on, Trace: off (file: none), Type:82540EM, Reported speed: 2 Mbps , Boot priority: 0, Promisc Policy: denyNIC 3: disabledNIC 4: disabledNIC 5: disabledNIC 6: disabledNIC 7: disabledNIC 8: disabledPointing Device: USB TabletKeyboard Device: PS/2 KeyboardUART 1: disabledUART 2: disabledAudio: enabled (Driver: DSOUND, Controller: AC97)Clipboard Mode: BidirectionalVideo mode: 640x480x0VRDE: disabledUSB: enabledUSB Device Filters: &amp;lt;none&amp;gt;Available remote USB devices: &amp;lt;none&amp;gt;Currently Attached USB Devices: &amp;lt;none&amp;gt;Shared folders: &amp;lt;none&amp;gt;VRDE Connection: not activeClients so far: 0Guest: Configured memory balloon size: 0 MBOS type: UbuntuAdditions run level: 0Guest Facilities: No active facilities.

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;APPENDIX 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation media: Ubuntu 10.04 LTS 32bit iso image;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HW: Virtualbox, 1CPU 32bit, 512MB RAM, 8GB HD (dynamic allocation);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC1 NAT;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIC2 host only (for ssh and http access from host);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language used in installation process: English and country Estonia;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyboard Layout English;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hostname: pece&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partition methods: Guided, use entire disk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username: pece&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no http proxy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sudo apt-get install lamp phpmyadmin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wget -c http://wordpress.org/latest.tar.gz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tar xvjf latest.tar.gz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sudo cp wordpress /var/www/wordpress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sudo nano /var/www/wordpress/wp-config.php Change the settings to
    your needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Script kiddie: Wikipedia, Script Kiddie, October 2011,
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Script_kiddie"&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Script_kiddie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User Manual: Oracle Corporation, User Manual, 2004-2011,
&lt;a href="http://www.virtualbox.org/manual/ch08.html"&gt;http://www.virtualbox.org/manual/ch08.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Footnotes:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] vnstat – &lt;a href="http://humdi.net/vnstat/"&gt;http://humdi.net/vnstat/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] Bmon – &lt;a href="http://www.infradead.org/~tgr/bmon/"&gt;http://www.infradead.org/~tgr/bmon/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pages"></category><category term="attacks"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="DDoS"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="script kiddie"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="server attack"></category><category term="wordpress attack"></category></entry><entry><title>IP Responsibility and abuse reporting procedure</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/posts/2011/03/ip-responsibility-and-abuse-reporting-procedure/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2011-03-11:/posts/2011/03/ip-responsibility-and-abuse-reporting-procedure/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;PURPOSE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main goal of laboratory report is to identify the responsibilities
for the IP addresses below and how we can make connection to them. IP
addresses are randomly chosen by the lecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IP addresses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​1. 69.163.171.238&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​2. 31.44.184.101&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​3. 188.72.228.69 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;PURPOSE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main goal of laboratory report is to identify the responsibilities
for the IP addresses below and how we can make connection to them. IP
addresses are randomly chosen by the lecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IP addresses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​1. 69.163.171.238&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​2. 31.44.184.101&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​3. 188.72.228.69&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;External IP that is used for purpose of this test is following:
193.40.244.0/255 1. The ISP that provides this network is EENet2.
Organization that is behind is Tallinn Technical University, Estonia.
City location is Tallinn and the region is Harjumaa. The phone number of
my ISP is: +372 73&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;*&lt;/em&gt;. The e-mail we should report abuse are: first
persons that is in charge: Viktor Borisevitch (e-mail:&lt;/strong&gt;tor at cc.ttu.ee
and phone number: +372-2-&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;*46) and Andres Lepp (e-mail: l&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at
cc.ttu.ee and phone number: +372 6 &lt;strong&gt;*&lt;/strong&gt;55). In addition, if we wont to
submit an abuse we should use both persons of network administration and
then we can submit and security incident on the following ISP e-mail:
turvas@eeenet.ee [RIPE NCC].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, Method 1 and Appendix 1 describes the website, tools and
application that are used to conduct this laboratory report. In
addition, Method 2 and Appendix 2 will introduce website tools and
databases where we can check if following IP’s have been reported before
as abuse and security risk. Both methods are represented with answer and
consequences confront in the result section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally the conclusion made of all collected data will be concise in
conclusion section of this report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;METHODS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First method describes and demonstrates web tools that have been used to
collect the needed information from the stated IP’s addresses. Second
method is pointing out website tools and databases that can be applied
if the IP has been reported previously as a abuse, spam or security
threat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;METHOD 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we need to collect as much as we can details about the IP
address. In Appendix 1 is showing the wholly information of the IP’s,
contact details, organization name, address, location, state, country,
technicians contact, abuse phone number, abuse e-mail, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on the location of IP we should make sure that not only we
know the ISP or abuse contact details, but we should know national CERT
3 agency that is in charge too. Therefore, to collect the information we
have used different web sites, agencies: [RIPENCC, LACNIC, AfriNIC,
APNIC, ARIN]. The above reference are agencies collected from IANA4.
Authority responsible for global coordination of the Internet Protocol
addressing systems [IANA].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, to have more details about the route of the IP’s we are using
command prompt in Windows 7 with the following command, where the
results are presented in Appendix 2 section:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    tracert [0.0.0.0]To illustrate, the details information are presented in Result 1 section.

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;METHOD 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we have collected the wholly information about the concrete IP
proposals, we should check if in addition those IP’s previously have
been reported as abused, spam or security threat. To complete the
following method we need to check concrete database system that is
offering following service. First that crossed on web is [MalwareURL]
which is dedicated to fighting malware, trojans and a multitude of other
web-related threats. In addition, we can check if the IP addresses are
listed in anti-spam databases. With other words blacklist check
[MyIPAddress].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;RESULTS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Results from Method 1 are presented in Result 1, further Method 2 is
presented in Result 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;RESULT 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each IP are presented only the most important data details that we
need to collect for our goal. In addition, full description and details
are presented in Appendix 1. The tables bellow are illustrating the most
important information that we should look-for. In addition, the
highlighted lines are indicating the abuse e-mail box that should be
send mail too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    69.163.171.238OrgName: New Dream Network, LLCAddress: 417 Associated Rd.Address: PMB #257City: BreaStateProv: CAPostalCode: 92821Country: US#technician in chargeOrgTechName: Nagel, MarkOrgTechPhone: +1-714-706-4182OrgTechEmail: mna47-arin at dreamhost.com#abuse in chargeOrgAbuseName: DreamHost Abuse TeamOrgAbusePhone: +1-714-706-4182OrgAbuseEmail: abuse&amp;nbsp; at dreamhost.comTable 131.44.184.101person: Chris Burnsaddress: Building 4&gt;address: City West Office Parkaddress: Gelderd Roadaddress: Leeds LS12 6LXaddress: Englandphone: +44-208-901-2332#abuse e-mail: abuse-mailbox: abuse at laveconetworks.co.ukTable 288.72.228.69role: Mannesmann Arcor Network Operation Centeraddress: Arcor AG &amp;amp; Co. KGaddress: Department TBSaddress: Otto-Volger-Str. 19address: D-65843 Sulzbach/Ts.address: Germanyphone: +49 6196 523 0864#abuse e-mailabuse-mailbox: abuse at arcor-ip.deTable 3

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, now that we know the abuse e-mail, phone number and contact
person details, still is this information enough for us. If we look in
details all of the IP’s are from different countries. Therefore we need
to find what is the national CERT agency contact details. First table is
based in USA, therefore we need to use their reporting system, which is
locate in the following link: &lt;a href="http://www.us-cert.gov/"&gt;http://www.us-cert.gov/&lt;/a&gt; . Second table
is UK, the national CERT agency link:
&lt;a href="http://www.ukcert.org.uk/"&gt;www.ukcert.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. Third table is based in
Germany, the CERT agency link: &lt;a href="http://www.cert-verbund.de/"&gt;http://www.cert-verbund.de/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the routing trace we can conclude that the first IP and the third
respond and it did not miss route trace, where in the second IP,
31.44.184.101 there is miss route trace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why we will run this IP address to Method 2. Despite the fact,
still we will run the rest of IP’s in the Method 2, to be trusted that
are not in the abuse list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;RESULT 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next step is to attempt to search the IP address to check if they have
been previously report as a abuse, trojan, malware, security threat,
etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To check and verify the security status we are using the service
available [MalwareURL]. Where results for 69.163.171.238 and
88.72.228.69 are with status that have not been previously reported as
abuse. On the other hand, 31.44.184.101 IP address is detected as an
security threat before. More details are presented in Appendix 3. Where
is demonstrating that the
&lt;code&gt;/404.php?type=stats&amp;amp;amp;affid=531&amp;amp;amp;subid=03&amp;amp;amp;iruns&lt;/code&gt; has been
reported as malicious URL and it is in a blacklist of Google, MyWOT,
etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only that it is listed in the malware database list, but also if we
double check on service [MyIPAddress] that the 31.44.184.101 IP address
is listed in few blacklist which is assess by DNSBL5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I would like to reiterate that the concrete IP’s that we
analysis in this report are demonstrating the process and methods that
should be done in future to detect, report abuse, malware, threat,
trojan, security risk, etc. Where we should gather the detail
information, and to whom to turn the abuse. To be precise that are not
in blacklist, spam list, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In spite of following IP’s: 69.163.171.238 and 88.72.228.69, from
performing methods and delivering results are safe and secure, still
think can be exploited in easy manners. The opposite, IP address
31.44.184.101 it has been already report infected as malicious code from
few blacklist providers. When checking the DNS, host name is linking to
UK company that deals with IP Transit. For further information please
check the following link: &lt;a href="http://www.laveconetworks.co.uk/"&gt;http://www.laveconetworks.co.uk/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, hope that laboratory report and the analyse will help to
anyone else to guide them for future use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;APPENDIXES&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appendix 1 is list of details collected from service. Appendix 2 is
trace route details. Where Appendix 3 is the result collected from the
black list database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of large content please download
[&lt;a href="http://predragtasevski.com/pdf/Predrag_Tasevski_Lab3_Report_IP_responsibility.pdf"&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RIPE NCC: RIPE NCC, Data &amp;amp; Tools, 2011,
&lt;a href="https://www.ripe.net/data-tools"&gt;https://www.ripe.net/data-tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LACNIC: Internet Address Registry for Latin America and the Caribbean,
REGISTRATION SERVICES , &lt;a href="http://lacnic.net/cgi-bin/lacnic/whois?lg=EN"&gt;http://lacnic.net/cgi-bin/lacnic/whois?lg=EN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AfriNIC: AfriNIC LTD, Query the AfriNIC Whois Database, 2011,
href="http://www.afrinic.net/cgi-bin/whois"
target="_blank"&gt;http://www.afrinic.net/cgi-bin/whois&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APNIC: APNIC, APNIC – Query the APNIC Whois Database, 2011,
&lt;a href="http://wq.apnic.net/apnic-bin/whois.pl"&gt;http://wq.apnic.net/apnic-bin/whois.pl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ARIN: ARIN, WHOIS-RWS, 2011,
&lt;a href="http://whois.arin.net/"&gt;http://whois.arin.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IANA: IANA, Number Resources, 2011, &lt;a href="http://www.iana.org/numbers/"&gt;http://www.iana.org/numbers/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MalwareURL: The MalwareURL Team, The MalwareURL Team, 2011,
&lt;a href="http://www.malwareurl.com/"&gt;http://www.malwareurl.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MyIPAddress: What Is My IP Address, Blacklist Check, 2011,
&lt;a href="http://whatismyipaddress.com/blacklist-check"&gt;http://whatismyipaddress.com/blacklist-check&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Footnotes:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] I will not show my own IP address&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] EENet – &lt;a href="http://www.eenet.ee/EENet/"&gt;http://www.eenet.ee/EENet/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3] CERT – Computer Emergency Response Team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4] IANA – Internet Assigned Numbers Authority – &lt;a href="http://www.iana.org/"&gt;http://www.iana.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[5] DNSBL – Domain Name System Blacklist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed on purpose, not to disclose the exposure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pages"></category><category term="attacks"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="DDoS"></category><category term="external IP"></category><category term="Internet Protocol addressing systems"></category><category term="IP addresses"></category><category term="malware"></category><category term="online"></category><category term="report abuse"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="security risk"></category></entry></feed>