<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/feeds/tag/awareness.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://predragtasevski.com/</id><updated>2015-09-27T13:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Balkans capacity towards cyber defense</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2015/09/yata-comments-of-the-week/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-09-27T13:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2015-09-27:posts/2015/09/yata-comments-of-the-week/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following texts is captured interview for YATA Comments of the week video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LAfOPIBoj8Q" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Predrag Tasevski and I’m an independent cyber security researcher from Macedonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we talk about Balkan region it is actually neither one step further nor one step backwards regarding cyber threats and cyber security. And at the same time progression of ICT is improving the  connectivity and its utilities from the rest of the world. For this reason discussing about cyber defense and security capacity in the region is in fact crucial and important topic.
However before we continue we have to understand the difference between IT security and cyber security. IT security is to protect business and individual assets, whereas cyber security it involved IT security as well as national, state security and security of Critical Information Infrastructure point of view.
To be able to have safer cyber space, we need to take an actions. Such as, ratifying conventions for instance Budapest Convention, moreover, adapting legal framework with international and of course social society needs. Than pursue establishment of National Bodies that will deal with occurrence and the frequency of cyberspace attacks and threats. And last but not least, develop national cyber security strategy. Among the mentioned actions, also important is to take into consideration the general approaches, as multi stakeholders and multi-level approach.
Cyberspace could not be 100% secured, therefore each country should introduce national cyber security culture and at the same time raising the awareness level to the weakest link in cyber security - that is the human behaviors.
Moreover, when we discuss about the cyber security and defense another important questions should be raised, by providing of course and answers:
Who? determines the target of who you are planning to secure.
What? determines the content of what to secure.
How? is the means by how you are going to secure it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turning back to Balkan vision toward cyber defense and security, we might say that several countries a much further progressing, such as Slovenia, Croatia, Albania, Montenegro and Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina, in contrast to slowly progressing countries: Macedonia, Serbia and etc.
Nevertheless, the region has taken under the umbrella and understood the importance of such topics and for this reason are taking hence actions. Such actions are as we mentioned previously making their legal framework compliance with the international perspectives. And establishing national bodies to react and countermeasure the incident occurred in cyberspace. And finally establishing national cyber security strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the end I would like to provide recommendation actions that could help other countries in pursuing and capacity building towards cyber defense and security.
Such as:
1. Understand cyber defense from a global perspective, don't feel nervous and foolish when it comes to the word “Cyber”. Use common and simple language that everyone could understand it.
2. Define and implement a national cyber security/defence strategy, followed by cyber security frameworks by supporting it initiatives and international cooperation.
3. Develop public awareness, cyber security culture and education that will touch entire population needs.
4. Improve resilience against cyber terrorism, cyber espionage, hybrid war and cyber warfare by sharing knowledge, documents, continues education and training, military and non-military capabilities.
5. Enforcing ICT infrastructures security in order to obtain confidence and security in the use of ICT. By investing in research and development.
6. And finally, continuance of public meetings and networking are in fact needed and essential on yearly basis for secure cyber space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The first step toward encouraging security and defence is awareness, followed by the implementation, acceptance and so forth”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="balkan"></category><category term="awareness"></category><category term="cyber defense"></category><category term="YATA"></category><category term="video"></category><category term="interview"></category><category term="Macedonia"></category><category term="ICT"></category><category term="strategy"></category></entry><entry><title>Interview: Snowden helped the mass awakening of awareness by Nova Makedonija</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2014/04/interview-snowden-helped-the-mass-awakening-of-awareness-by-nova-makedonija/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-04-29T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2014-04-29:posts/2014/04/interview-snowden-helped-the-mass-awakening-of-awareness-by-nova-makedonija/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Source: Nova Makedonija, Interview by Predrag Tasevski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First Macedonian daily newspaper have asked me for interview before the
holidays. The topic was concentrating on security, coupled the national
security and IT security. However, the interview is posted in
&lt;a href="http://www.novamakedonija.com.mk/NewsDetal.asp?vest=4291475063&amp;amp;amp;id=51&amp;amp;amp;prilog=0&amp;amp;amp;setIzdanie=23162"&gt;Macedonian
language&lt;/a&gt;,
but also you could use &lt;a href="http://translate.google.com/translate?sl=mk&amp;amp;amp;tl=en&amp;amp;amp;js=y&amp;amp;amp;prev=_t&amp;amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.novamakedonija.com.mk%2FNewsDetal.asp%3Fvest%3D4291475063%26id%3D51%26prilog%3D0%26setIzdanie%3D23162&amp;amp;amp;edit-text="&gt;English
translation&lt;/a&gt;
with Google translator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any comments and want to discuss something feel free to drop
me a comments below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Holidays!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="interview"></category><category term="nova makedonija"></category><category term="newspaper"></category><category term="snowden"></category><category term="awareness"></category><category term="macedonia"></category><category term="cyber security"></category></entry><entry><title>ICSAP – Interactive Cyber Security Awareness Program</title><link href="http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2012/12/icsap-interactive-cyber-security-awareness-program/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2012-12-06:posts/2012/12/icsap-interactive-cyber-security-awareness-program/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, humans coupled with the socio-technical aspect can be either
the strongest or the weakest link in any information security system,
and the key in security lies in delivering awareness training through
short and effective online videos, whereby the participator can gain
knowledge on security. Our aim, therefore, is to develop innovative
solutions to deliver an interactive cyber security awareness program,
where the main goal is to enhance information on security awareness and
knowledge in organizations, schools, nations, homes etc. The syllabus
consists of a systematic approach divided into three sections. The
introduction is a basic level course (BASIC), with the aim of delivering
an elementary curriculum in physical security, computer and mobile;
network and Internet security to everyone. It is made up of several
units with interactive training videos that last less than 10 minutes
each. The second course (ADVANCE) is the advanced program which
demonstrates the attacking phases, different attacking methods and the
countermeasures that highlight the anatomy of Advance Persistence
Threats (APT). This curriculum is intended for administrators, help desk
personnel, information technology professionals among others. The last
course (MANAGEMENT) is intended for managers, where we annotate two
decision-making processes with their cycle loop. Moreover, after each
unit there is a questionnaire, which measures the knowledge of each
participant, and compares it to the base-line survey carried out during
the registration process. As a result, it represents the participant’s
awareness level and knowledge, and will assist in further actions if
necessary. By implementing this program in private and public
organizations, governments, schools and universities will lead to the
improvement of security in the everyday use of computers, mobile phones,
online banking, social networking_ both at home and in the workplace.
The present study addresses and implements the IT security issue. We
will apply the results by carrying out the syllabus, with the latest
improvements, in universities and private organizations. Consequently by
applying these further improvements to the syllabus, it will meet the
needs of the cyber security field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords:&lt;/strong&gt; cyber security, human factor, socio-technical, awareness,
program&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Presentation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/file/d/0B1472nuKPMN5ZHlocUFFc2o2UWM/preview" width="640" height="480"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</summary><category term="awareness"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="human factor"></category><category term="program"></category><category term="socio-technical"></category><category term="training"></category></entry></feed>