<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece - digital divide</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/feeds/tag/digital-divide.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://predragtasevski.com/</id><updated>2013-04-04T23:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Bullying of digital divide or not?</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/04/bullying-of-digital-divide-or-not/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-04-04T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2013-04-04T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2013-04-04:/posts/2013/04/bullying-of-digital-divide-or-not/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet is changing the average citizens as much as did other
technologies, for instance: telephone, TV, computers, mobile phones,
etc. The main province was to help the science, engineering, and
business. Many scholars, technologists, and social critics believe that
these changes and the Internet, in particular, are transforming …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet is changing the average citizens as much as did other
technologies, for instance: telephone, TV, computers, mobile phones,
etc. The main province was to help the science, engineering, and
business. Many scholars, technologists, and social critics believe that
these changes and the Internet, in particular, are transforming economic
and social life [1]. In the past few years, the scholars have done many
researches to make a conclusion of difference in psychological and
social tend of the Internet to the citizens. Therefore, the term
“digital divide” is the gap that exists between those who have access to
electronic and Information Technology – Internet and those who do not
[2]. Whereby the Anti-Counterfeiting Trade Agreement (ACTA) set up could
result in an order of restricting the universal access to the Internet.
And representing a barrier to European development as an information,
knowledge and technology society. In other words, could lead to the
censorship of online content and control-restriction to the Internet’s
freedom, by intimidation the growth of electronic business, cultural
exchange, as well as digital creativity. In order to safe the Internet
and to provide shelter to digital divide culture we will have to take
actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enormous continuing and boosting usage of information and communication
technologies in an economic inequality between groups, broadly
construed, in terms of access and knowledge has created the term digital
divide. Additionally, divide inside countries also could refer to
individuals, households, business and geographical areas at different
socioeconomic and other demographic levels. On one hand the Internet is
changing the average citizens. As much as on the other hand the other
technologies, such as: telephone, TV, mobile phones, etc. The main idea
and purpose was to aid to and benefit the science, engineering, and
business. However, many scholars, technologists, and social critics
believe that these changes and the Internet, in particular, are
transforming economic and social life [1]. In the past, the scholars
have done many researches to make a conclusion of difference in
psychological and social tend of the Internet to the citizens.
Therefore, the term “digital divide” is the gap that exists between
those who have access to electronic and Information Technology –
Internet and those who do not [2]. Moreover, interesting is to point out
that to break the gap between the digital divide the scholars and
societies have created a new approach and technology for delivering
laptop per child. The project name is one laptop per Child and
significant fact is that as of 2011 there were over about 2.4 million XO
laptops delivered elsewhere [4]. Whereby the Anti-Counterfeiting Trade
Agreement (ACTA) could result in an order of restricting the universal
access to the Internet. And representing a barrier to European
development as an information, knowledge and technology society. In
other words, could lead to the censorship of online content and
control-restriction to the Internet’s freedom, by intimidation the
growth of electronic business, cultural exchange, as well as digital
creativity. Therefore, in this article we have introduced the readers
within the basic concept of digital divide. In addition we illustrate to
the readers a map of digital divide and example countries that have
stress out the digital divide. In contrast to digital divide we would
emphasis on the secret negotiations of ACTA agreement. Moreover, why we
should care about it, as well as in order to safe the Internet what kind
of actions we should take into consideration. At least we deliver to the
readers a conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Digital divide&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned previously it is a term to determine the gap that exists
between those who have access to electronic and Information Technology –
Internet and those who do not [1]. Thereby in the next subsection we
introduce the readers within the concept and basic approach of
determining and criteria to define the digital divide. Least we also
provide the example country of digital divide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Concept&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main concept and criteria of digital divide is shown below [3]:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​1. Subjects of connectivity, or who connects: individuals,
organizations, enterprises, schools, hospitals, countries, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​2. Characteristics of connectivity, or which attributes: demographic
and socio-economic variables, such as income, education, age, geographic
location, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​3. Means of connectivity, or connectivity to what: fixed or mobile,
Internet or telephony, digital TV, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​4. Intensity of connectivity, or how sophisticated the usage: mere
access, retrieval, interactivity, innovative contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​5. Purpose of connectivity, or why individuals and their cohorts are
(not) connecting: reasons individuals are and are not online and uses of
the Internet and ICTs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best example of digital divide is a North Korea. The
broadband infrastructure is with optical fiber links up to 2.5Gbits/s
[5]. Additionally the Internet in North Korea is more or less is
recalled as “Intranet”, because of implementation of the Kwangmyong
network, in English “walled garden” [6]. The most significant fact was
the news have spread information that one of the most known torrent
sites has been moved to and relocated in North Korea, March 4 2013.
However this information was no correct. For more details please refer
to the following source [7]. Nevertheless the above are just simple
examples and in the Figure 1 we have illustrated you with the map of
digital divide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;ACTA: Anti-Counterfeiting Trade Agreement&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anti-Counterfeiting Trade Agreement has been negotiated from 2007
through 2010 by the United states, the European Union, Switzerland,
Canada, Australia, New Zealand, Mexico, Singapore, Morocco, Japan and
South Korea. And it has been signed 8 of 11 agreements in October 2011.
Moreover, in October 2012 it was ratifies by Japan as well [8]. In
addition in Figure 2 we have illustrated you the map of ACTA countries
involved in drafting the convention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Why should you care?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we look over the both maps we can come to conclusion that the
strongest countries that has less digital divide is the ones who has
drafted the convention of ACTA. So we should care, because of the
process how it was negotiated, indeed in secret. And the first text was
officially released in 2010. It has been roundup within eight
closed-doors negotiations. As well as the provisions, where the new IP
enforcement measures that raise potential concerns for users free
speech, privacy, ability to innovate and due process rights. And
finally, the enforcement it creates a new ad-hoc institution, an “ACTA
Committee”, constituting non-elected members to oversee ACTA
implementation and interpretation with no legal obligation to the
transparent in their proceedings [8].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Digital divide vs ACTA&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, when we compare digital divide versus ACTA agreement we can see
that they overlap into one opposite directions. Such as explained in the
below table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;th align="right"&gt;
Digital divide

&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;th align="left"&gt;
ACTA

&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
Access to ICT – Internet

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;
Restriction to Internet

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
Freedom of speech

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;
Censorship and control-restriction to freedom

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
Economy growth

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;
Privacy

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
Culture exchange

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;
N/A

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
Demoralizing: the economy, culture exchange, digital creativity

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="right"&gt;
Digital creativity

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;td align="left"&gt;
N/A

&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short summary is we have introduced the reader with the terminology
of what is digital divide coupled with examples. As well as the linked
connection between the two topics, digital divide versus ACTA agreement.
Therefore, we come to the conclusion is that indeed the ACTA convention
is bullying the digital divide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Presentation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/file/d/0B1472nuKPMN5dW96RllUWWhoblE/preview" width="640" height="480"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: Robert , K., Micheal, P., Vicki, L., Sara, K., Tridas , M., &amp;amp;
William , S., Internet Paradox, 1998 "Robert"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: University of Minnesota Duluth, Web Design References: Glossary,
2011, http://www.victoriapoint.com/child_technology.htm "Duluth"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3]: Martin Hilbert, The end justifies the definition: the manifold
outlooks on the digital divide and their practical usefulness for
policy-making, 2011 "Martin"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4]: Worldwide | One Laptop per Child, 2013, http://laptop.org/map
"OLPC"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[5]: Jungbae An, Asia Internet History Projects, Sep 26, 2012,
https://sites.google.com/site/internethistoryasia/country-region-information/north-korea-korea-democratic-peoples-republic-of
"Jungbae"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[6]: Andrew Jacobs, Google Chief UrgesNorth Korea to Embrace Web,
January 10, 2013 "Andrew"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[7]: Will, The Pirate Bay – North Korean hosting? No, it’s fake. (P2),
05. March 2013, ttps://rdns.im/the-pirate
-bay-north-korean-hosting-no-its-fake-p2 "Will"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
[8]: Carolina Rossini, Maira Sutton, Gwen Hinze, Anti-Counterfeiting
Trade Agreement, https://www.eff.org/issues/acta "Carolina"

Video
=====

&lt;object id="flash-object" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" data="http://f.vimeocdn.com/p/flash/moogaloop/6.0.21/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=62281130&amp;amp;z=1415229799455" width="100%" height="100%"&gt;&lt;param name="flashvars" value="clip_id=62281130&amp;amp;embed_location=http://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/04/bullying-of-digital-divide-or-not/&amp;amp;js_getConfig=getConfig&amp;amp;js_setConfig=setConfig&amp;amp;js_onLoad=onMoogaloopLoaded&amp;amp;api=1&amp;amp;moogaloop_type=moogaloop"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://f.vimeocdn.com/p/flash/moogaloop/6.0.21/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=62281130&amp;amp;z=1415229799455"&gt;&lt;param name="allowfullscreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"&gt;&lt;param name="bgcolor" value="#000000"&gt;&lt;param name="wmode" value="opaque"&gt;&lt;param name="quality" value="high"&gt;&lt;param name="scalemode" value="noscale"&gt;&lt;/object&gt;</content><category term="pages"></category><category term="hactivism"></category><category term="bullying"></category><category term="digital divide"></category></entry><entry><title>Digital divide or not?</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/posts/2011/06/digital-divide-or-not/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-06-19T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2011-06-19T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2011-06-19:/posts/2011/06/digital-divide-or-not/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Digital divide or not?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there a psychological “digital divide”? Are people who often use the
Internet psychologically different from those who do not and in what
ways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet is changing the average citizens as much as did other
technologies, for instance: telephone, TV, computers, mobile phones etc.
The …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Digital divide or not?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there a psychological “digital divide”? Are people who often use the
Internet psychologically different from those who do not and in what
ways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet is changing the average citizens as much as did other
technologies, for instance: telephone, TV, computers, mobile phones etc.
The mainly province was to help the science, engineering, and business.
Many scholars, technologists, and social critics believe that these
changes and the Internet, in particular, are transforming economic and
social life (Robert , Micheal, Vicki, Sara, Tridas , &amp;amp; William , 1998).
In the past few years, the scholars have done many researches to make a
conclusion of difference in psychological and social tend of the
Internet to the citizens. Therefore, the term “digital divide” is the
gap that exists between those who have access to electronic and
Information Technology – Internet and those who do not (University of
Minnesota Duluth, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People use home computers and the Internet in many different ways and
for many purposes, including entertainment, education, information
retrieval, and communication. If people use the Internet mainly for
communication with others through e-mail, distribution lists, multiuser
dungeons, chats, and many other instant or voice messenger applications,
they might do so to augment traditional technologies of social contact,
expanding their number of friends and reducing the difficulty of
coordinating interaction with them. On the other hand, these
applications disproportionately reduce the costs of communication with
geographically distant acquaintances and strangers; as a result, a
smaller proportion of people’s total social contacts might be with
family and close friends. Yet other applications on the Internet,
particularly the World Wide Web, provide asocial entertainment that
could compete with social contact as a way for people to spend their
time (Robert et al., 1998).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, since the primary use of the Internet is communication,
some people might speculate that the Internet will have positive social
consequences in people’s everyday lives because it increases the
frequency and quality of interpersonal communications among people.
People with easy access to others would feel better connected and more
strongly supported by others, leading to happiness and engagement in
families, organizations, communities, and society more generally
(Nikolovska, 2007).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, on the other hand, the ease of electronic communication may lead to
weaker social ties, because people have less reason to leave their homes
and actually interact face to face with other people. The Internet
allows people to more easily work from their home, to form and sustain
friendships and even romantic attachments from their home, to bank from
their home, to vote and engage in political and social issue based
discussions with others (from home) (Nikolovska, 2007).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with watching television and using a home computer and the Internet
generally imply physical inactivity and limited face-to-face social
interaction. Some studies, including our own, have indicated that using
a home computer and the Internet can lead to increased skills and
confidence with computers (Lundmark, Kiesler, Kraut, Scherlis, &amp;amp;
Mukhopadhyay, 1998). However, when people use these technologies
intensively for learning new software, playing computer games, or
retrieving electronic information, they consume time and may spend more
time alone (Vitalari, Venkatesh, &amp;amp; Gronhaug, 1985). Some cross-sectional
research suggests that home computing may be displacing television
watching itself (Danko, W. D. &amp;amp; MacLachlan, J. M, 1983), (Kohut, 1994)
as well as reducing leisure time with the family (Vitalari et al.,
1985).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this variety of ways, Internet communications can potentially
displace face-to-face communications. This point is important because
psychologists in many researches have described and proved such face to
face and telephone connections as being of higher quality, when viewed
in terms of their contribution to satisfaction and
well-being(Nikolovska, 2007).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Question that rise is while our culture heralds the Internet as a
technological wonder; there are suggestions that Internet use has a
negative influence on individuals and their social skills. A recent
study conducted by Carnegie Mellon University concludes that Internet
use leads to small but statistically significant increases in misery and
loneliness and a decline in overall psychological
well-being(Association, American Psychological, 1998). The appropriately
named HomeNetproject studied a sample of 169 people in Pittsburg during
their first year or two online. Data showed that as people in this
sample used the Internet more, they reported keeping up with fewer
friends. They also reported spending less time talking with their
families, experiencing more daily stress, and feeling more lonely and
depressed. These results occurred even though interpersonal
communication was their most important reason for using the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Katz and Aspden’s national survey (1997) is one of the few empirical
studies that have compared the social participation of Internet users
with nonusers. Controlling statistically for education, race, and other
demographic variables, these researchers found no differences between
Internet users’ and nonusers’ memberships in religious, leisure, and
community organizations or in the amount of time users and nonusers
reported spending communicating with family and friends. From these
data, Katz and Aspden concluded that “[f]ar from creating a nation of
strangers, the Internet is creating a nation richer in friendships and
social relationships” (p. 86)(Robert et al., 1998).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the percentage of usage of the technology nowadays
drastically enhanced. Such as the state/country statistics of
information society reports during pass few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parallel between two countries with a similarity of population number:
Estonia and Macedonia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estonia since 2000 had 366,600 connected citizens though Internet.
However, in 2010 the statistic report’s the rapidly changes with the
number of 969,700 connections (Miniwatts Marketing Group., 2010). Yet
the statistic in Macedonia shows since 2000 the users that were
connected are 30,000, where in 2010 the number swiftly has change,
1,057,400 users in the country were connected though Internet. Thus, the
statistic shows that 75,1% of citizens in Estonia has access to
Internet, analogous to Macedonia 51% of population of the country in
final report of 2010 (Miniwatts Marketing Group, 2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, from the statistic we can see that, most of the population
nowadays has a computer, laptop, or device in their pocket that can
connect on Internet. Despite the alarm, research indicates most children
are doing fine. Computers are certainly intriguing and captivating, and
the Internet is most assuredly alluring with its research and
communicative capacities. But overall, technology can be considered a
positive enhancement to growth(Affonso, 1999). This feature is
eloquently affirmed by author Don Tapscott (Tapscott, 1999):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“… when kids are online, they’re reading, thinking, analyzing,
criticizing and authenticating – composing their thoughts. Kids use
computers for activities that go hand-in-hand with our understanding of
what constitutes a traditional childhood. They use the technology to
play, learn, communicate and form relationships as children always have.
Development is enhanced in an interactive world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the above the influence of the Internet has caused a change in the
way we communicate, study, shop, etc. The most famous for the ability to
spread information, to communicate from a distance with a web camera,
etc. it is the Internet. But this communication revolution changed the
pure nature of interpersonal and group processes. We should be able to
see the difference between the qualities of face-to-face communication
that influence the impact of communication on people and their social
interaction. Moreover, should we be able to predict the probable
influence of any new communication technology. Nevertheless, the
researchers show that people sooner or later convert their cyber
contacts into more traditional face-to-face, as most of us do. People
use the Internet, in other words to help them achieve their real-life
goals. And rather than technology’s changing people’s social and
psychological reality, in other words, people change their use of
technology to facilitate their creation of a desired social reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Reference&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Affonso, B. (1999, December). Is the Internet Affecting the Social
Skills of Our Children? Retrieved from Sierra Source Web Design:
&lt;a href="http://www.sierrasource.com/cep612/internet.html"&gt;http://www.sierrasource.com/cep612/internet.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Association, American Psychological. (1998). Internet paradox — a social
technology that reduces social involvement and psychological well-being?
American Psychologist,53, 1017-1031.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Danko, W. D., &amp;amp; MacLachlan, J. M. (1983). Research to accelerate the
diffusion of a new invention. Journal of Advertising Research,
23(3),39-43.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kohut, A. (1994). The role of technology in American life. Los Angeles:
Times Mirror Center for the People and the Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lundmark, V., Kiesler, S., Kraut, R., Scherlis, W., &amp;amp; Mukhopadhyay, T.
(1998). How the strong survive: Patterns and significance of competence.
Unpublished manuscript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miniwatts Marketing Group. (2010). Macedonia Internet Usage and
Telecommunications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retrieved from Internet Usage and Telecommunications:
&lt;a href="http://www.internetworldstats.com/eu/mk.htm"&gt;http://www.internetworldstats.com/eu/mk.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miniwatts Marketing Group. (2010). Internet Usage Stats and Market
Report – Estonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retrieved from Internet World Statistic:
&lt;a href="http://www.internetworldstats.com/eu/ee.htm"&gt;http://www.internetworldstats.com/eu/ee.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nikolovska, M. (2007, April). The Influence Of The Internet On People’s
Social And Psychological Realities. Retrieved from EzineArticles.com:
&lt;a href="http://ezinearticles.com/?The-Influence-Of-The-Internet-On-Peoples-Social-And-Psychological-Realities&amp;amp;id=524319"&gt;http://ezinearticles.com/?The-Influence-Of-The-Internet-On-Peoples-Social-And-Psychological-Realities&amp;amp;id=524319&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robert , K., Micheal, P., Vicki, L., Sara, K., Tridas , M., &amp;amp; William ,
S. (1998). Internet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paradox. Washington, DC: American Psychological Association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tapscott, D. (1999). The kids are alright: technology doesn’t make them
‘little criminals’. Retrieved from Victoria Point Multimedia:
&lt;a href="http://www.victoriapoint.com/child_technology.htm"&gt;http://www.victoriapoint.com/child_technology.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;University of Minnesota Duluth. (2011, 04 04). Web Design References:
Glossary. Retrieved from Information Technology Systems &amp;amp; Services:
&lt;a href="http://www.d.umn.edu/itss/support/Training/Online/webdesign/glossary/d.html"&gt;http://www.d.umn.edu/itss/support/Training/Online/webdesign/glossary/d.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitalari, N., Venkatesh, A., &amp;amp; Gronhaug, K. (1985). Computing in the
home: Shifts in the time allocation patterns of households.
Communications of the ACM, 28(5), 512-522.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pages"></category><category term="digital divide"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="net generation"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="network generation"></category><category term="online"></category><category term="online generations"></category><category term="psychological"></category></entry></feed>