<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece - forum</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/feeds/tag/forum.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://predragtasevski.com/</id><updated>2014-07-06T23:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Stockholm Internet Forum 2014</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/posts/2014/07/stockholm-internet-forum-2014/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-06T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-07-06T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2014-07-06:/posts/2014/07/stockholm-internet-forum-2014/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Usually May in Stockholm is cold, chilly and indeed refreshing. However,
this year the weather surprised all the participants of &lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/" title="Stockholm Internet Forum 2014"&gt;Stockholm
Internet Forum
2014&lt;/a&gt;.
Although it is one of the most beautiful cities in Europe, it was even
more with rising sun every day. Especially coming from Nice where the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Usually May in Stockholm is cold, chilly and indeed refreshing. However,
this year the weather surprised all the participants of &lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/" title="Stockholm Internet Forum 2014"&gt;Stockholm
Internet Forum
2014&lt;/a&gt;.
Although it is one of the most beautiful cities in Europe, it was even
more with rising sun every day. Especially coming from Nice where the
weather was under storm, and sunny and long days in Stockholm were
unforgettable. Before I continue with description and the nature of this
year SIF, first would like to apologize for late post – I was under busy
with examination, second would like to thank the organization for
selecting me as a valuable participant.&lt;span id="more-1158"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being in Stockholm for the second time it is a privilege. And indeed,
this year SIF surprised me with the invitation. Usually the organizers
are selecting each year new participant. From their explanation only 10%
of previous year participants are invited where the rest are new.
Consequently, there were around 450 participants, from different
countries in this year SIF14. Nonetheless, it was an event for great
opportunities for networking and meeting interesting people, or see the
rear ones from the previous year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which the event and the panel discussions I might say that
I’m a bit disappointed, because of the repeating of the participant from
SIF13. Another point that I would like to stress out regarding the event
is that in this event the participants are not only a hacktivists,
policy makers, whistleblowers, activities, NGO, etc., but also companies
and so forth. I love the idea of selecting for each panel to have one
enterprise represent, however bear in mind that people will might
exploit this and take and pursue a totally different aspect of the
discussion. Therefore, I suggest for the organization to select wisely
the enterprise panelists. For instance, make sure that the topic and the
theme of the panels are emphasized and understood by the wide audience,
as well as that the chair man and the panelists will control the floor
and that the topic will not go outside of content. This is due to this
event, some panel discussions were totally misunderstood by the audience
and indeed some participants were frustrated, for instance me, but also
many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, coming back to the selection of percentage of the
participant. I frankly love the idea that you like to bring different
audience and different people each year event, however in my opinion and
as well as from other that we discussed during the event is that will be
much better that from the 10% is either 15-20%. This is due to fact that
most if the time these topics and events only and usually bring new
topics and questions, and not give answers to them. So in this respect
you will have a continuing discussions and most probably some answers,
coupled with outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also I would like to take an opportunity to respond to the participant
that were emphasizing the participation of one of the hot topic and
indeed well known person, today – Edward Snowden. In respect to their
request where is Snowden and so on, I would like to point out few
things: first in international law it is firstly impossible to bring him
in Sweden because of his status in Russia; moreover there is no need for
him to take participation in the event where we talk about freedom of
Internet, as well as the espionage, privacy, policy, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum, again thanks to the organization for inviting me once again to
the event. Second, by taking into account the above suggestions,
personally thing that the event will be more progressive, as well as
proactive by having outcome. Further, bring people, panelists which are
wisely selected compliance to the topic and theme of the event and/or
discussion. In the end, looking forward seeing you in the next year, as
well hope that I will be taking place this time as one of panelist.
Where not only that I could contribute with the discussion but also
bring some new important questions in the podium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Pictures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="375"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705209908%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705209908%2F&amp;set_id=72157648705209908&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705209908%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648705209908%2F&amp;set_id=72157648705209908&amp;jump_to=" width="500" height="375"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pages"></category><category term="sctockholm"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="freedom"></category><category term="forum"></category><category term="2014"></category><category term="cyber security"></category></entry><entry><title>Stockholm Internet Forum 2013</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/06/stockholm-internet-forum-2013/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-06-05T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2013-06-05T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2013-06-05:/posts/2013/06/stockholm-internet-forum-2013/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year the Stockholm Internet Forum 2013 was addressing the freedom
of Internet, human rights, freedom of speech, censorship, privacy as
well as importance of security. Among the topics, also we have touched
the cyber security, surveillance, importance of information security
coupled with critical information infrastructure and critical
infrastructure. Once …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year the Stockholm Internet Forum 2013 was addressing the freedom
of Internet, human rights, freedom of speech, censorship, privacy as
well as importance of security. Among the topics, also we have touched
the cyber security, surveillance, importance of information security
coupled with critical information infrastructure and critical
infrastructure. Once Alex Levin has said – “The reason there is so
little crime in Germany is that it’s against the law.” – What a hack he
was talking? Was he right or wrong? For this reason, the SIF was held
this year with more than 94 different countries participants, from all
over the world. And indeed, it was one of the best conference organized
so far. Nevertheless the number of differential participants let the
talks and the conference topics just to flow. Even that the four days of
talking was not enough. However, this was just a start, or for someone
the beginning of an idea due to the poverty of our thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opening speech was by Carl Bildt where he presented in fact an
importance of digital revolution, African development through
connectivity, political debates for freedom of Internet. In addition, he
gave a couple of great examples, such as legislations of blocking sites
in Russia, violations of human rights in Syria, Vietnam among the
others. Also, he noted the security importance of cyber security, where
security should be thought but of course should not be used in purpose
to limit the human rights. One very good quote, even after two weeks
from the conference I still have it in my head, is &lt;strong&gt;*“Free societies
are strong societies”&lt;/strong&gt;. Last but not least, was that we should take an
examples from the leading nations of ICT, such as, Sweden, where the
security coupled with human rights are presented on Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frankly, in the opening session we have touched the issue with
surveillance and software used for this purpose, coupled with the
viability of digital divide popular in Africa and among others.
Moreover, we have purse the issue of Internet jurisdiction projects, as
well as that we have to boost the awareness of regulations united with
the important factor to increased the civil societies in freedom. For
more info please visit the summaries notes from the session, &lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/opening-session/" title="Opening session"&gt;Opening
session&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To continue with the first session again we have to come back some
example of the above issue, surveillance, where Mexico has
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Closed-circuit_television" title="Closed-circuit television - Wikipedia"&gt;CCTV&lt;/a&gt;
in private sector for 3 to 4 years. Among the surveillance we have
discuss the issue during the riots in London, Syria and Panama as a
recent examples where they have shutdown the mobile phone network.
Additionally, point in some countries is that people do trust the law
enforcement in privacy, where opposite such as in Pakistan they trust
only the companies, and not law enforcement agencies. Moreover, hate
speech, digital freedom and democracy of freedom was carried out, along
with how the law works on Internet with civil societies and that the
police need to do their own job. Nevertheless, the note was that
vocabulary of cyber security is missing, and it should become a national
security and of course the security is a huge problem. This problem is
done due to the lack of new laws, by definition of what we mean by a
single law treaty. Whom we should secure? What should be asked? In
sentence of security importance, civil society. We really need a cyber
security strategy, by introducing the legislation and laws throughout
experience. In spite of vocabulary e should define and terms, such as,
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hacktivism" title="Hacktivism - Wiki"&gt;hacktivism&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cyberterrorism" title="Cyberterrorism - Wiki"&gt;cyberterrorism&lt;/a&gt;.
One important note was mentioned that we do not want global cyber
security law. For more info of the session please visit the following
link &lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/session-1/informal-summary/" title="Session 1: Reconciling freedom and security in cyberspace"&gt;Reconciling freedom and security in
cyberspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned above the frustration was between the west and
developing countries in sentence of digital divide. Also one note was
that Sweden people trust to the government agencies, as well as that
e-voting system in Sweden will help ICT to boost. The session where
split into three parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/session-1a/informal-summary-of-session-1a/" title="1A Global security and human rights in the internet age"&gt;1A Global security and human rights in the internet
    age&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/session-1b/informal-summary/" title="1B Distributed security in a national context"&gt;1B Distributed security in a national
    context&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/program/session-1c/informal-summary/" title="1C Free and secure communication in a multinational context"&gt;1C Free and secure communication in a multinational
    context&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next day, the second day of the forum (SIF13) we have touched a facts
about the free and open Internet and open communications. The second day
I will remember forever for speech of the famous Cuban blogger Yoani
Sánchez, which said very good quote “Cuba Internet on Internet” or
another one is that if your relatives or you personally travel to Cuba
bring the old and unused gadgets with you and leave them in Cuba or just
give them, rather than you should just dispose them or throw them into
the trash. For more info please visit the &lt;a href="http://www.stockholminternetforum.se/summaries-2013/" title="Summaries 2013 | Stockholm Internet Forum"&gt;Summaries 2013
page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I might say that the SIF 13 was very successful, as well
as very important questions and topics were discussed. However, we
should concentrate for the next year forum on more specific topics,
either freedom or only a security. It is very difficult when we speak
about freedom coupled with security. Does two topics are very linked and
fragile. In the end, I would like to thank a lot to the organizers,
&lt;a href="https://www.iis.se/" title=".SE"&gt;.SE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.government.se/sb/d/2059" title="Ministry for Foreign Affairs - Sweden"&gt;Ministry for Foreign Affairs –
Sweden&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href="http://www.sida.se/Svenska/" title="SIDA"&gt;SIDA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Pictures&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="500" height="375"&gt; &lt;param name="flashvars" value="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648696553859%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648696553859%2F&amp;set_id=72157648696553859&amp;jump_to="&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="movie" value="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554"&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="https://www.flickr.com/apps/slideshow/show.swf?v=1811922554" allowFullScreen="true" flashvars="offsite=true&amp;lang=en-us&amp;page_show_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648696553859%2Fshow%2F&amp;page_show_back_url=%2Fphotos%2F29569957%40N00%2Fsets%2F72157648696553859%2F&amp;set_id=72157648696553859&amp;jump_to=" width="500" height="375"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pages"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="forum"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="stockholm"></category><category term="freedom"></category></entry></feed>