<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece - network</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/feeds/tag/network.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://predragtasevski.com/</id><updated>2011-10-12T23:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Cost of DDoS, leak of credit card numbers, infected machine and spam</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/posts/2011/10/cost-of-ddos-leak-of-credit-card-numbers-infected-machine-and-spam/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-10-12T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2011-10-12T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2011-10-12:/posts/2011/10/cost-of-ddos-leak-of-credit-card-numbers-infected-machine-and-spam/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;PURPOSE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main goal of laboratory report is to identify the costs of nowadays
most known attack  DDOS, leak of credit card numbers, infected machine
and never the less sending spam for 1 000 000 (one million) people.
There are few points that should be presented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where did we discovered …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;PURPOSE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main goal of laboratory report is to identify the costs of nowadays
most known attack  DDOS, leak of credit card numbers, infected machine
and never the less sending spam for 1 000 000 (one million) people.
There are few points that should be presented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where did we discovered the information (links or sources)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What kind of source of communication we used, for instance: instant
    messing, ICQ, IRC, which contact we have gather the information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the prices for the above attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, we must bear in mind that collecting the above information
it is presented to a numerous affected sources ( i.e. Website, news,
forums, IRC chat,etc.). By visiting the source can lead you to a virus,
trojan, malicious code, malware, etc. Which can damage your system.
Therefore, we are going to use virtual environment to find our demands.
In addition, we will use different languages and different search
engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Construction of report is separated by tasks section. Where each section
is presented with the source, communication type and the costs of the
service. In addition, in Appendix 1 we give the configuration of virtual
environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally the conclusion made of all collected data will be concise in
conclusion section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;TASKS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following list is the numeration of the tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DDoS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Credit Card Numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Infected Machines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spam for 1 000 000 people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;TASK 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source where we can find information about the cost of DDoS attacks are
provided in Russian most known [Hackzone] forum. This is the source will
give as more of the answers. But again be careful when you accessing
this site. It is on your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the following link we received an information about DDoS
attacks: [HackzoneDDoS]. With the following translated statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    The average price of service from $ 50 per day. Depends on the complexity of the &lt;em&gt;attacked site. Methods of payment accepted via WebMoney. The network is practically around the clock!Commands:http / https / icmp / post / syn / udp /Price:Day from $ 50Week from $ 350From $ 1200 per month(Prices may change depending of type and timing of orders on the complexity of the attacked site)Demo test for 5-10 minutes.Contact:Icq :20-**-29Inspections completed:hack-world.orgwww.xaker.nameforum.xaknet.ruMost of the DDoS attack service are around per day $ 50, here is an other source and contact details:Contact details Icq:22-**-327Icq:875-**3E-mail:anti**os@jab**r.ru

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above information is from the following link:
&lt;a href="http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/15608/"&gt;http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/15608/&lt;/a&gt;. Other sources that can be
found are with&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the following links: &lt;a href="http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/16067/"&gt;http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/16067/&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/17187/"&gt;http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/17187/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we stated above that the price is from \$50 per day and it goes until
\$350 per month and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;TASK 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of credit cards leaked in the web are numerous amount. The
prices are not that high as people expected. For card that comes from
European country is the highest price and for the other are much
cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here some information from the following link, leak from &lt;a href="http://www.hackzone.ru/memb/view/name/Support_BM/"&gt;Support_BM
Originar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source is in Russian language, so for this report is translated to
English. From the source [CartNumber].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    At the moment there is only us, ca, cvv.Databases are updated every 2-3 days, Walid varies from 75 to 90%.Price:us visa, mc cvv = $ 1.5us amex, diss = $ 1.5us without vbv \ mksk = $ 2us not tied and PayPal = $ 2EU = $ 6-9World = $ 3-6CIS is not and never will.Sorted by: bean = $ 1Sample on any other criterion = +0.5 $Sampling only on the following criteria: bin, judge, state, city, type, zip.WARNING! I do not select “No vbv”, “No attachment to the paypal”, “Give me a map that would be held there now and then.”Terms and conditions of service provision:1. Replacement non valid within 48 hours of purchase.2. I only 04/05/51 Declined, Hold-Call, check only CCN + EXP + CVV3. On messages such as “Here?” “Hi, how are” probably will not answer.4. Money Beg do not.5. Do not change the board, check it before selling.6. I believe only their own way, proven in battle, checker, so your results, another checker,&amp;nbsp;and so do not pay attention.7. Using my service, you automatically agree with everything stated in this post.8. Reserve the right to refuse service to anyone, without explanation.9. I am not responsible for the account balances card-holders.10. I do not give advice on the use of the material.11. Do not keep a bazaar talks about the reductions.12. I do not care where you do not go away if you gave Checker Walid Walid means.Card format:Credit Card Number | CVV2 | ??Exp.date | Name | Address Line | City | State | Zip Code |Country | Phone (Not Always) | Email Address (not always)Attention! Before you knock a replacement non valid, make sure that all the provided maps not valid if none of these cards will be found a valid card and a replacement will be denied.Learn to appreciate their own and other people’s time, get a checker, and live happily ever after.Contact the seller checker can provide for everyone.I accept payment only WMZ and LibertyReserveMy WMID has 70BL, as well as on-demand in icq give links to many reviews.Contact:ICQ: 604000**0JID: ***nager@thes**ure.bizPosted 13.10.2010 13:45:51 (8 days 18 hours 31 minutes 59 seconds)Other source that cross is from Russian banks Alfa debit or others the price from$175. Source is published by contact details: Jabber: v**yt@exp**it.im, ICQ: 25**165,Skype: V**yt_. On the following link:&lt;a href="http://lab-one.net/showthread.php?t=664" target="_blank"&gt; http://lab-one.net/showthread.php?t=664&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;TASK 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays it is not hard to find an infected machine/computer. Because
most of the user PC’s are based with operating system Windows and are
most of them infected. I have try so hard to find infected machine
price, but until today, I did not come up with any good source.
Therefore, I would like if it is possible to add this source and discuss
this source and information with the fellow students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;TASK 4&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spamming for one million people it sounds impossible, but still out
there someone is offering this service. Here is from Kazakhstan source
with the following information, translated in English:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;

    E-mail newsletter:1 post = 1 m., minimum order 10 000 posts.For large orders – big discounts!At present there is action: 10 000 tenge, we send 20 000 messages. + Action: 50 000 tenge, we send your letter to 360 000 email ardesov in Almaty, send 3 times in one month!The action is over, send a time.E-mail database:In Almaty:60 000 LEGAL Address – Almaty Yuredicheskie email addresses, the entire directory guide “our town” and directory site “Samruk Kazyna”430 000 – private address Almaty residents collected via mail search agent criteria:country, city, gender, age.Throughout Kazakhstan:240 000 – LEGAL person Kazakhstan LLP, Ltd., Inc., Ltd., etc. collected from various references such as “yellow pages” “compass” etc.3.4 million – individuals, all of Kazakhstan. – Collected through the mail search agent criteria: country, city, gender, age.P.S. you can build a base of email addresses to any city in Kazakhstan, or any other city in any other country, can you give us the criteria and we will collect your base, an example of criteria:I try, the city, Age, sex, online, not online.P.S. Legal mailings are engaged for 3 years, dispatching more than 5 years.To Order: +7-701-1**5575, +7 (727) -329-61-**.E-mail: d**z@i**ox.ru

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, for 10 000 KZT = 67.45 USD and the amount of message send are 20
000 spam. Then the price for one million spam is 3.372.5 USD without
discount. The above links is from the following source [Rassilka.kz].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to generalize that from the above information we see that
for any service that we looked for, it has a price. Value that are
different in other countries and currencies. Yet, before you start this
research make sure that you are not using your local machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, I have used an virtual environment to be able to collect all
the above data. Because the sites, forums, links, etc. are infected with
malicious code, or can be easily traceable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, we utter gather as much as possible different sources and
different prices. Most expensive is the spam for one million people,
second is DDoS attacks and never the last is to gain an credit card
numbers from different countries and different price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more info please refer to following source [QuinStreet Inc] why I
have chose Russia as the main source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;APPENDIX&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appendix 1 is configuration of the virtual environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;APPENDIX 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virtual environment: Oracle VirtualBox Version 4.1.2 r73507.
Downloadable from the following link:
https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Downloads&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security Fedora 14 32 bit – Client:
http://spins.fedoraproject.org/security/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Base Memory: 512 MB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acceleration: VT-x/AMD-V, Nested Paging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Display – Video memory: 12 MB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage: SATA Controller, Port 0: 8 GB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adapter 1: Adapter 1: Parvirtualized Network (NAT)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adapter 2: Adapter 2: Inter PRO/1000 MT Desktop (Host-only
    adapter, „VirtualBox Host- Only Enternet Adapter“)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hackzone: HackZone.ru, Forum, 2011, &lt;a href="http://www.hackzone.ru/"&gt;http://www.hackzone.ru/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HackzoneDDoS: Master_DDoS, Качественный DDoS Сервис,
&lt;a href="http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/17387/"&gt;http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/17387/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CartNumber: Support_BM, Качественный US\EU\WORLD картон, 2011,
&lt;a href="http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/14936/"&gt;http://www.hackzone.ru/forum/open/id/14936/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rassilka.kz: kamondimon, E-mail рассылки!, 2011,
&lt;a href="http://rassilka.kz/rassilki-rassilka-kz/47-e-mailrassylki.html"&gt;http://rassilka.kz/rassilki-rassilka-kz/47-e-mailrassylki.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QuinStreet Inc: Paul Rubens, Understanding the Russian Hacker
Underground, Aug 13, 2010,
&lt;a href="http://www.enterprisenetworkingplanet.com/netsecur/article.php/3898601/Understanding-the-Russian-Hacker-Underground.htm"&gt;http://www.enterprisenetworkingplanet.com/netsecur/article.php/3898601/Understanding-the-Russian-Hacker-Underground.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pages"></category><category term="acceleration"></category><category term="optamization"></category><category term="simmulation of attacks and defence"></category><category term="wordpress attacks"></category><category term="credit card numbers"></category><category term="cyber security"></category><category term="DDoS"></category><category term="defence"></category><category term="infected machine"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="malware"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="online"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="spam"></category></entry><entry><title>Future of human communication</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/posts/2011/06/future-of-human-communication/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-06-26T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2011-06-26T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2011-06-26:/posts/2011/06/future-of-human-communication/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;On the basis of how the communication possibilities have changed (for) most people during last decades, what’s my idea of the normal human interaction in 10..20…50 years?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand the present we must first understand the past. The
Internet has revolutionized the computer and communications world like …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;On the basis of how the communication possibilities have changed (for) most people during last decades, what’s my idea of the normal human interaction in 10..20…50 years?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand the present we must first understand the past. The
Internet has revolutionized the computer and communications world like
nothing before. The invention of the telegraph, telephone, radio, and
computer set the stage for this unprecedented integration of
capabilities. The Internet is at once a world-wide broadcasting
capability, a mechanism for information dissemination, and a medium for
collaboration and interaction between individuals and their computers
without regard for geographic location.&lt;span id="more-113"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet represents one of the most successful examples of the
benefits of sustained investment and commitment to research and
development of information infrastructure. Beginning with the early
research in packet switching, the government, industry and academia have
been partners in evolving and deploying this exciting new technology
(Barry M. , et al., 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet today is a widespread information infrastructure, the
initial prototype of what is often called the National (or Global or
Galactic) Information Infrastructure. Its history is complex and
involves many aspects – technological, organizational, and community.
And its influence reaches not only to the technical fields of computer
communications but throughout society as we move toward increasing use
of online tools to accomplish electronic commerce, information
acquisition, and community operations(Barry M. , et al., 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likelihood, computers have changed the face of communication to an
extent that we can’t consider our routine life without presence of these
machines. With the availability of technologies like internet, instant
messaging, emailing and others, the computers has fast replaced
conventional means of communicating with each other(Communication Type,
2008).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one writes letter anymore. It’s been said that longhand or cursive is
no longer taught in grade school. No need for it. People don’t write
anymore. As technology defined the late Twentieth Century, we became
both closer together and further apart. People had more time for an
online chat via the fast growing Internet than they did for a day at the
park with a dear friend. That was bad. On the other hand, we connected
to people all over the world that we might not otherwise get to enjoy.
Today, computer technology constantly changes the way we communicate
(Friends of Time, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we look through the history of computer communication from 1968 to
nowadays there are three unique market sectors: Data Communication,
Networking and Internet (Internetworking). Data communication is an
electronic transmission of information that has been encoded digitally
(as for storage and processing by computers). Computer Networking is an
interconnection of various computer systems located at different places.
In computer network two or more computers are linked together with a
medium and data communication devices for the purpose of communicating
data and sharing resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Internet is a network of networks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Millions of computers all over the world are connected through the
Internet. Computer users on the Internet can contact one another
anywhere in the world. If your computer is connected to the Internet,
you can connect to millions of computers. You can gather information and
distribute your data. It is very much similar to the telephone
connection where you can talk with any person anywhere in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As digital media takes flight, the grand slam of computer communication
has arrived. Skype . It’s free, it’s live, and it’s real face time. Not
only can people talk, but they can see each other as they talk. There
are even Skype and “skype-like” apps for Smartphones. To an extent,
communication has a more human feel again. People can see friends and
family a world away and keep very close contact. And leave it to
teenagers to figure out how to make Skype the new bedroom powwow.
Teenagers simply turn it on and hang out. They may not even be talking
to each other, but they know the other person is there (Friends of Time,
2011). With a free access of the Internet though the wireless local area
network (WLAN 1) we can chat and talk with anyone from anywhere, without
the consideration of graphical location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet and computers are offering a wide range of communication
influence. We can communicate to text messages to your friends through
computers and communication tools provided by it. From emails and
newsletters to text chats and instant messaging, micro-blogging,
computers can help you to reach your friends, relatives, business
associates and others in the matter of few seconds. Communication tools
to communicate your voice messages without facing the geographical
restrictions. Voice mails and voice chats, brought revolutionary changes
how have computers changed the way we communicate. Business
communication with the help of audio and video conferencing. The
executives of different branches of a company, located in different
geographical locations, can communicate with each other and distances
can pose no hurdles in establishing these communication systems. Other
influence of computer communication are helping and proving the
education system of offering a distant learning, gaining a degree
without being at the university location, etc. One of the popular
concepts in nowadays communication is online social networking, instance
of communication, joining different online clubs and communicates with
individuals from various parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, imagine a day without computer in your room or on the
office desk. For instance no emails, no chatting, no instant messaging
and no web camera interactions, how we are going to feel? Therefore, we
all can understand how computers have changed the way we communicate.
Life can come to a standstill without computers and similar devices
around us. Consequently, communication through computers is an important
aspect of every individual today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part of communicating through computer and Internet is that you
can practice it from any part of the world. All computer technology is
wonderful and the more access to communication the better. But it will
be a shame if the world becomes so shrouded in technology that good old
fashioned face to face people skills become a rare art instead of an
everyday norm.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, all the above describes how the computers changed the way we
communicate. This is because computers have become great contributors
towards the world of communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Reference&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barry M. , L., Vinton G. , C., David D. , C., Robert E. , K., Leonard ,
K., Daniel C. , L., et al. (2011). A Brief History of the Internet.
Retrieved from Internet Society (ISOC):
&lt;a href="http://www.isoc.org/internet/history/brief.shtml"&gt;http://www.isoc.org/internet/history/brief.shtml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication Type. (2008, October 29). Computers and Communication –
Technology Giving Way to Technology. Retrieved from Communication Type:
&lt;a href="http://www.communication-type.com/computers-and-communication-%E2%80%93-technology-giving-way-to-technology/"&gt;http://www.communication-type.com/computers-and-communication-%E2%80%93-technology-giving-way-to-technology/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friends of Time. (2011). Computer Technology Constantly Changes the Way
We Communicate. Retrieved from Friends of Time:
&lt;a href="http://friendsoftime.org/computer-technology-constantly-changes-the-way-we-communicate.html"&gt;http://friendsoftime.org/computer-technology-constantly-changes-the-way-we-communicate.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Footnote:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] WLAN: a local area network that uses high frequency radio signals to
transmit and receive data over distances of a few hundred feet; uses
Ethernet protocol&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pages"></category><category term="communication"></category><category term="future of human communication"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="networking"></category><category term="online"></category></entry><entry><title>Digital divide or not?</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/posts/2011/06/digital-divide-or-not/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-06-19T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2011-06-19T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2011-06-19:/posts/2011/06/digital-divide-or-not/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Digital divide or not?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there a psychological “digital divide”? Are people who often use the
Internet psychologically different from those who do not and in what
ways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet is changing the average citizens as much as did other
technologies, for instance: telephone, TV, computers, mobile phones etc.
The …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Digital divide or not?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there a psychological “digital divide”? Are people who often use the
Internet psychologically different from those who do not and in what
ways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet is changing the average citizens as much as did other
technologies, for instance: telephone, TV, computers, mobile phones etc.
The mainly province was to help the science, engineering, and business.
Many scholars, technologists, and social critics believe that these
changes and the Internet, in particular, are transforming economic and
social life (Robert , Micheal, Vicki, Sara, Tridas , &amp;amp; William , 1998).
In the past few years, the scholars have done many researches to make a
conclusion of difference in psychological and social tend of the
Internet to the citizens. Therefore, the term “digital divide” is the
gap that exists between those who have access to electronic and
Information Technology – Internet and those who do not (University of
Minnesota Duluth, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People use home computers and the Internet in many different ways and
for many purposes, including entertainment, education, information
retrieval, and communication. If people use the Internet mainly for
communication with others through e-mail, distribution lists, multiuser
dungeons, chats, and many other instant or voice messenger applications,
they might do so to augment traditional technologies of social contact,
expanding their number of friends and reducing the difficulty of
coordinating interaction with them. On the other hand, these
applications disproportionately reduce the costs of communication with
geographically distant acquaintances and strangers; as a result, a
smaller proportion of people’s total social contacts might be with
family and close friends. Yet other applications on the Internet,
particularly the World Wide Web, provide asocial entertainment that
could compete with social contact as a way for people to spend their
time (Robert et al., 1998).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, since the primary use of the Internet is communication,
some people might speculate that the Internet will have positive social
consequences in people’s everyday lives because it increases the
frequency and quality of interpersonal communications among people.
People with easy access to others would feel better connected and more
strongly supported by others, leading to happiness and engagement in
families, organizations, communities, and society more generally
(Nikolovska, 2007).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, on the other hand, the ease of electronic communication may lead to
weaker social ties, because people have less reason to leave their homes
and actually interact face to face with other people. The Internet
allows people to more easily work from their home, to form and sustain
friendships and even romantic attachments from their home, to bank from
their home, to vote and engage in political and social issue based
discussions with others (from home) (Nikolovska, 2007).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with watching television and using a home computer and the Internet
generally imply physical inactivity and limited face-to-face social
interaction. Some studies, including our own, have indicated that using
a home computer and the Internet can lead to increased skills and
confidence with computers (Lundmark, Kiesler, Kraut, Scherlis, &amp;amp;
Mukhopadhyay, 1998). However, when people use these technologies
intensively for learning new software, playing computer games, or
retrieving electronic information, they consume time and may spend more
time alone (Vitalari, Venkatesh, &amp;amp; Gronhaug, 1985). Some cross-sectional
research suggests that home computing may be displacing television
watching itself (Danko, W. D. &amp;amp; MacLachlan, J. M, 1983), (Kohut, 1994)
as well as reducing leisure time with the family (Vitalari et al.,
1985).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this variety of ways, Internet communications can potentially
displace face-to-face communications. This point is important because
psychologists in many researches have described and proved such face to
face and telephone connections as being of higher quality, when viewed
in terms of their contribution to satisfaction and
well-being(Nikolovska, 2007).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Question that rise is while our culture heralds the Internet as a
technological wonder; there are suggestions that Internet use has a
negative influence on individuals and their social skills. A recent
study conducted by Carnegie Mellon University concludes that Internet
use leads to small but statistically significant increases in misery and
loneliness and a decline in overall psychological
well-being(Association, American Psychological, 1998). The appropriately
named HomeNetproject studied a sample of 169 people in Pittsburg during
their first year or two online. Data showed that as people in this
sample used the Internet more, they reported keeping up with fewer
friends. They also reported spending less time talking with their
families, experiencing more daily stress, and feeling more lonely and
depressed. These results occurred even though interpersonal
communication was their most important reason for using the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Katz and Aspden’s national survey (1997) is one of the few empirical
studies that have compared the social participation of Internet users
with nonusers. Controlling statistically for education, race, and other
demographic variables, these researchers found no differences between
Internet users’ and nonusers’ memberships in religious, leisure, and
community organizations or in the amount of time users and nonusers
reported spending communicating with family and friends. From these
data, Katz and Aspden concluded that “[f]ar from creating a nation of
strangers, the Internet is creating a nation richer in friendships and
social relationships” (p. 86)(Robert et al., 1998).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the percentage of usage of the technology nowadays
drastically enhanced. Such as the state/country statistics of
information society reports during pass few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parallel between two countries with a similarity of population number:
Estonia and Macedonia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estonia since 2000 had 366,600 connected citizens though Internet.
However, in 2010 the statistic report’s the rapidly changes with the
number of 969,700 connections (Miniwatts Marketing Group., 2010). Yet
the statistic in Macedonia shows since 2000 the users that were
connected are 30,000, where in 2010 the number swiftly has change,
1,057,400 users in the country were connected though Internet. Thus, the
statistic shows that 75,1% of citizens in Estonia has access to
Internet, analogous to Macedonia 51% of population of the country in
final report of 2010 (Miniwatts Marketing Group, 2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, from the statistic we can see that, most of the population
nowadays has a computer, laptop, or device in their pocket that can
connect on Internet. Despite the alarm, research indicates most children
are doing fine. Computers are certainly intriguing and captivating, and
the Internet is most assuredly alluring with its research and
communicative capacities. But overall, technology can be considered a
positive enhancement to growth(Affonso, 1999). This feature is
eloquently affirmed by author Don Tapscott (Tapscott, 1999):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“… when kids are online, they’re reading, thinking, analyzing,
criticizing and authenticating – composing their thoughts. Kids use
computers for activities that go hand-in-hand with our understanding of
what constitutes a traditional childhood. They use the technology to
play, learn, communicate and form relationships as children always have.
Development is enhanced in an interactive world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the above the influence of the Internet has caused a change in the
way we communicate, study, shop, etc. The most famous for the ability to
spread information, to communicate from a distance with a web camera,
etc. it is the Internet. But this communication revolution changed the
pure nature of interpersonal and group processes. We should be able to
see the difference between the qualities of face-to-face communication
that influence the impact of communication on people and their social
interaction. Moreover, should we be able to predict the probable
influence of any new communication technology. Nevertheless, the
researchers show that people sooner or later convert their cyber
contacts into more traditional face-to-face, as most of us do. People
use the Internet, in other words to help them achieve their real-life
goals. And rather than technology’s changing people’s social and
psychological reality, in other words, people change their use of
technology to facilitate their creation of a desired social reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Reference&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Affonso, B. (1999, December). Is the Internet Affecting the Social
Skills of Our Children? Retrieved from Sierra Source Web Design:
&lt;a href="http://www.sierrasource.com/cep612/internet.html"&gt;http://www.sierrasource.com/cep612/internet.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Association, American Psychological. (1998). Internet paradox — a social
technology that reduces social involvement and psychological well-being?
American Psychologist,53, 1017-1031.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Danko, W. D., &amp;amp; MacLachlan, J. M. (1983). Research to accelerate the
diffusion of a new invention. Journal of Advertising Research,
23(3),39-43.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kohut, A. (1994). The role of technology in American life. Los Angeles:
Times Mirror Center for the People and the Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lundmark, V., Kiesler, S., Kraut, R., Scherlis, W., &amp;amp; Mukhopadhyay, T.
(1998). How the strong survive: Patterns and significance of competence.
Unpublished manuscript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miniwatts Marketing Group. (2010). Macedonia Internet Usage and
Telecommunications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retrieved from Internet Usage and Telecommunications:
&lt;a href="http://www.internetworldstats.com/eu/mk.htm"&gt;http://www.internetworldstats.com/eu/mk.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miniwatts Marketing Group. (2010). Internet Usage Stats and Market
Report – Estonia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retrieved from Internet World Statistic:
&lt;a href="http://www.internetworldstats.com/eu/ee.htm"&gt;http://www.internetworldstats.com/eu/ee.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nikolovska, M. (2007, April). The Influence Of The Internet On People’s
Social And Psychological Realities. Retrieved from EzineArticles.com:
&lt;a href="http://ezinearticles.com/?The-Influence-Of-The-Internet-On-Peoples-Social-And-Psychological-Realities&amp;amp;id=524319"&gt;http://ezinearticles.com/?The-Influence-Of-The-Internet-On-Peoples-Social-And-Psychological-Realities&amp;amp;id=524319&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robert , K., Micheal, P., Vicki, L., Sara, K., Tridas , M., &amp;amp; William ,
S. (1998). Internet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paradox. Washington, DC: American Psychological Association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tapscott, D. (1999). The kids are alright: technology doesn’t make them
‘little criminals’. Retrieved from Victoria Point Multimedia:
&lt;a href="http://www.victoriapoint.com/child_technology.htm"&gt;http://www.victoriapoint.com/child_technology.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;University of Minnesota Duluth. (2011, 04 04). Web Design References:
Glossary. Retrieved from Information Technology Systems &amp;amp; Services:
&lt;a href="http://www.d.umn.edu/itss/support/Training/Online/webdesign/glossary/d.html"&gt;http://www.d.umn.edu/itss/support/Training/Online/webdesign/glossary/d.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitalari, N., Venkatesh, A., &amp;amp; Gronhaug, K. (1985). Computing in the
home: Shifts in the time allocation patterns of households.
Communications of the ACM, 28(5), 512-522.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pages"></category><category term="digital divide"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="net generation"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="network generation"></category><category term="online"></category><category term="online generations"></category><category term="psychological"></category></entry><entry><title>Internet and collectivistic cultures</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/posts/2011/06/internet-and-collectivistic-cultures/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-06-06T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2011-06-06T23:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2011-06-06:/posts/2011/06/internet-and-collectivistic-cultures/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Internet and collectivistic cultures. How the Internet affects the psyche of the people from collectivistic cultures?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays everyone has a computer at home, work and even a carrying
device, example: laptop, notebook, mobile phones, IPod etc. All the
devices that are making our life easy in everyday tasks are able …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Internet and collectivistic cultures. How the Internet affects the psyche of the people from collectivistic cultures?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays everyone has a computer at home, work and even a carrying
device, example: laptop, notebook, mobile phones, IPod etc. All the
devices that are making our life easy in everyday tasks are able to
connect though the Internet. Which affects our psyche and people around.
It not only influences the thoughts, behavior and personality of
individual but it has lobby to the group of people that we socialize.
Thus, in other words the collectivistic culture beside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cultures by the membership are typically divided into two categories:
collectivist and individualist. Individualistic cultures, people are
expected to develop and display their individual personalities and to
choose their own affiliations, where in collectivist cultures, people
are defined and act mostly as members of a long-term group, such as the
family, a religious group, an age cohort, a town, or a profession, among
others (Deb, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, individualism pertains to societies in which ties are loose:
people are expected to look after themselves and their immediate family.
In addition, collectivism pertains to societies in which people are
integrated into strong, cohesive groups from birth onwards, protecting
them in exchange for unquestioned loyalty (Hall, Menno, &amp;amp; Steehouder,
2004). Cross-cultural studies have provided empirical evidence that the
individualism-collectivism dimension is the most important dimension for
pinpointing differences between cultures (Ting-Toomey &amp;amp; Gao, 1998).
Furthermore, both collectivist and individualist cultures have their
failings. People in individualist cultures are susceptible to
loneliness, and people in collectivist cultures can have a strong fear
of rejection (Psychology Wiki, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically the emphasize of groups in family and work goals in
collectivist cultures, such as those of East Asia, parts of Latin
America and some countries from Europe, like: Greece and Portugal
(Psychology Wiki, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To illustrate the traits of collectivism is that each person is
encouraged to conform to society, to do what is best for the group and
do not openly express opinions or beliefs that go against it; group,
family or rights for the common good seen as more important than the
rights of individuals; where rules promote stability, order, obedience;
fitting in or conforming to group or society is required; where
distinctions made between in-group and out-group and working with others
and cooperating is the norm. Refusal to cooperate and wanting to be
independent or stand out is seen as shameful. Everyone must rely on
others for support. Therefore, stereotype of a ‘good person’ in
collectivist cultures is trustworthy, honest, generous, and sensitive,
all characteristics that are helpful to people working in groups
(Psychology Wiki, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the present day, users of the online social networks are more
collectivistic, because of the apparent benefits to networked
interaction. Given this rise in popularity, a significant amount of
prior work has examined the social behavior and attitudes of the users
that engage in Internet network. Proponents argue that community
building technology is useful because it improves knowledge interaction
among users, enhancing interpersonal relationships. Specifically as
weblogs, playing online or through Internet network games, wikis such as
Wikipedia, social networking such as Facebook, Myspace, Hi5, etc. and
micro blogging tools such as Twitter, in particular, have attracted
attention ( Dayne, Sigi, &amp;amp; Hart, 2009).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, I do not know all of my friends in my social networks
Facebook, last.fm, twitter, myspace, etc. Yet I do like to build a
community where I can share my other activities, such as sharing my new
photography that I have taken in Estonia or somewhere else, share the
event when I am going to perform a music show in clubs in Tartu or
Tallinn. Sharing links of my new blog posts or my site update.
Therefore, still I have seen this people face to face, or at least I
have had a face to face conversation with most of them. I do rely on
their support to show in events that I am performing, or get a feedback
on the photography that I have posted recently. All the above, creates
my own society group network though Internet my own virtual world
family, where relationship permits classification in the in-group, which
relied on collectivistic culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, when collectivists meet another person, the first
thought they are likely to have is, “What is my relationship with that
person?” If the relationship permits classification in the in-group,
they are likely to behave very positively – cooperating, supporting,
going out of their way to help. In contrast, if the other person is
classified as an out-group member, they are likely to be indifferent or
even hostile. Such sharp differentiation of in-group and out-group is
not found among individualists. Collectivists use action verbs, rather
than state verbs, because they prefer to use context in their
communications. Sometime even show a generosity rule when exchanging
with in-group members, where their acceptance of paternalism and to
emphasize the importance of the nurturance of the leader. And for
further more information see (Individualism and Collectivism, 2001, p.
35).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the Internet drastically changes the psyche in-group and
out-group communication, relationship, supporting, cooperation, etc. in
human culture. Nevertheless, Internet has influence on psyche in
collectivist culture behaviors but affects the individualist. Nowadays
people are communicating through the many sources available on Internet
and develop new relationships, groups and community where they can share
and feel positive, classified, into larger groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Reference&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dayne, F., Sigi, G., &amp;amp; Hart, D. (2009, November 9). Individualist and
collectivist factors affecting online repurchase intentions. Retrieved
from School of Accounting and Business Information Systems, The
Australian: www.emeraldinsight.com/1066-2243.htm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deb. (2011, March 27). Geert Hofstede. Retrieved from wikimedia.org:
https://secure.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/wiki/Geert_Hofstede&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hall, M., Menno, d., &amp;amp; Steehouder, M. (2004, November 1). Cultural
differences and usability evaluation: individualistic and collectivistic
participants compared. Retrieved fromHighBeam Research:
http://www.highbeam.com/doc/1G1-126157549.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psychology Wiki. (2011). Collectivist and individualist cultures.
Retrieved from Collectivist and individualist cultures – Psychology
Wiki:
http://psychology.wikia.com/wiki/Collectivist_and_individualist_cultures#Traits_of_Collectivism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ting-Toomey, S., &amp;amp; Gao, G. (1998). Communicating Effectively with the
Chinese. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage Publications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TRIANDIS, H. C. (2001). Individualism and Collectivism. In D. Matsumoto,
The Handbook of CULTURE &amp;amp; PSYCHOLOGY (p. 35). Oxford: Oxfrod University
Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pages"></category><category term="collectivistic"></category><category term="cultures"></category><category term="informatics"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="online people"></category><category term="psyche"></category><category term="social"></category></entry><entry><title>Human Computer Interaction in 2020</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/posts/2011/03/human-computer-interaction-in-2020/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2011-03-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2011-03-17:/posts/2011/03/human-computer-interaction-in-2020/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In March 2007, Microsoft Research organised the “HCI 2020” meeting at
the El Bulli Hacienda Hotel near Seville, Spain. The event’s title
expressed its key question: what will Human-Computer Interaction (HCI)
be like in the year 2020? (Harper, Tom, Yvonne, &amp;amp; Abigail, 2008, p. 8)
The report that I have …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In March 2007, Microsoft Research organised the “HCI 2020” meeting at
the El Bulli Hacienda Hotel near Seville, Spain. The event’s title
expressed its key question: what will Human-Computer Interaction (HCI)
be like in the year 2020? (Harper, Tom, Yvonne, &amp;amp; Abigail, 2008, p. 8)
The report that I have read it is divided in a four parts; Part 1 it is
look back over the past 20 years or so; Part 2 it gives an outline how
does changes are transforming the nature of our interaction with
computers and the key questions that need to be addressed in the next 15
years as a result; Part 3 is concerned with HCI as a field of research
and as a community of practitioners and designers; Part 4,
recommendations, outlines specific suggestions for HCI in terms of how
the field needs to be change. Therefore, the research report it talks
about the future aspects and the future plans with an recommendations
that has to be concern in an aspect of HCI, I have chosen to write about
the part 4 where they give a good outline of the recommendations that
has to be encounter for the new actions in the future of HCI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research report came with very good seventh future directions. Each
direction will be described in an educationally signification for me,
what I have learned and what should be the next future actions in
consideration. Matter of course, no one will know in what kind of
aspects and future plans the HCI will change, but still this research
report gives vaulting and most important future recommendations that
need to be considered, and there will be more and more recommendations
and future directions as the technology and the HCI changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we start to talk about the recommendations in a field of HCI,
let’s see what HCI is. It is a term used to refer to the understanding
and designing of different relationships between people and computers.
In the late 1970’s the main concern was usability. Since then, HCI has
established and designed, developed and apply all manners to ensure that
the technologies are easy to learn and easy to use. (Harper, Tom,
Yvonne, &amp;amp; Abigail, 2008, p. 84)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting familiar with the terms and the practice of HCI let as
look though the main seventh future recommendations that were considered
by the scholars and people involved in this forum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation 1: Revisit research and design methods in HCI: it is
    a distinct research area, methods and techniques have been used have
    altered over the years. Computer system and technologies are still
    in a way of changes, thus are the approaches for 2020 that needs to
    be considered:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore new ways of understanding users. Over the last decade there
    have been techniques and design-based practices involving cultural
    probes. Usage of existing techniques of understanding that have
    emerged from scientific and engineering traditions, designs, views
    of diverse disciplines and cultural traditions; usage of conceptual
    analysis in the first stage of new HCI, where can comes from
    techniques of analytic philosophy and clarifying the systems of
    meaning and value of actions that are involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore new ways of designing and making. Designing and making it
    takes a very important influence in a way of HCI. It is very
    important to comprehend for what, which and why the system is going
    to be used, what kind of users. In the future lightweight and
    prototypes should fit the designing and engineering solutions
    together. Should be developed new technological, prototype tool for
    the future development, and consider a test of hardware and software
    within every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reconsider how to evaluate digital technologies. Create a purpose of
    usage of the system, towards the, is it going to be used in everyday
    life in houses, working spaces or other environment. For what kind
    of usability the system is going to be used. For all should be made
    evaluation tools to reconsider the criteria and techniques.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation 2: Be explicit about the remit of HCI. How far or
    whether the HCI as a research area should continue extend itself, or
    should be involved with interaction between people and digital
    technology, and should with concern itself more than in the past?
    Does are the question that should be raised. It should develop new
    design possibilities, future altering and crafting the landscape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation 3: Develop disciplinary techniques that allow HCI to
    collaborate with other research communities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disciplinary exchange. Requirement for HCI researchers to know how
    to converse with disciplines with very different traditions, they
    need to understand what philosophers can do and why philosophy is
    important. Example: economists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beyond interdisciplinary boundaries. HCI should ask what might be
    the appropriate models for allowing interdisciplinary investigations
    to happen and it is an area where investment in research theories
    and approaches, in the elements of HCI competence and skill, and in
    the foundations of the philosophy of science are required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation 4: Teach HCI to the young. Children should be
    introduced to the ‘properties and possibilities of computing’ it is
    the only way that they develop sufficient understanding of computing
    to enable them to be fully computer-literate when they are adults,
    and help them to shape the world in relation to technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation 5: More advanced training for future HCI researchers.
    HCI professionals need to move outside of the scientific community
    they have lived within and find ways to engage with society as a
    whole.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation 6: Engage with government, policy and society. More
    better technical and economical approach, where there will be wide
    range of implementing HCI in a government, but in policy and
    society. HCI should have a strong links with the society, it needs
    to interact more, not only like for policy in a trust and security
    in computer systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation 7: Offer an inclusive future in 2020. By 2020, HCI
    will need to be able to design for and support differences in human
    value, irrespective of the economic means of those seeking those
    values. In this way, the future can be different and diverse because
    people want it to be. (Harper, Tom, Yvonne, &amp;amp; Abigail, 2008, pp.
    78-83)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this article very interesting, not only in an aspect of human
interaction with computers but with the actions that were taken and the
propositions that were sum. I love to make a summer of the entire
research paper, but because of the short time period I could not make
it. Still I gained my knowledge what should be expected and where are
burrows in HCI field. It gives me a perfect view for the future
implementation of projects, aspects and techniques that can be used.
Hope that this few years since the 2007, the implementation and
recommendation directories have been successfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Reference&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harper, R., Tom, R., Yvonne, R., &amp;amp; Abigail, S. (2008). Being Human,
Human-Computer Interaction in the year 2020. Cambridge, CB3 0FB,
England: Microsoft Research Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pages"></category><category term="2020"></category><category term="future of human communication"></category><category term="HCI"></category><category term="HCI 2020"></category><category term="human computer interaction"></category><category term="internet"></category><category term="network"></category><category term="networking"></category><category term="online"></category><category term="online generations"></category><category term="social informatics"></category></entry></feed>