<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece - penetration</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/feeds/tag/penetration.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://predragtasevski.com/</id><updated>2013-11-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Penetration Testing vs. Vulnerability Assessment</title><link href="https://predragtasevski.com/posts/2013/11/penetration-testing-vs-vulnerability-assessment/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-11-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-11-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Predrag TASEVSKI - Pece</name></author><id>tag:predragtasevski.com,2013-11-11:/posts/2013/11/penetration-testing-vs-vulnerability-assessment/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past few days, months and indeed years many people have
approached me and asked me a very simple question… But bare in mind that
this simple question was and indeed it is a still a big dilemma between
many professionals in IT security, cyber security, management,
decision-makers …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past few days, months and indeed years many people have
approached me and asked me a very simple question… But bare in mind that
this simple question was and indeed it is a still a big dilemma between
many professionals in IT security, cyber security, management,
decision-makers, policy, etc.  Thereby, the question is: What is the
difference between Penetration testing and Vulnerability Assessment? And
of course this question was almost always couples with the question if
we do penetration testing does it means that we are doing as well as
vulnerability assessment? In this content, I have decided to share with
you the meanings, such as, methods, approaches of each process, as well
as a further reading – papers, articles and books – that could help you
to distinguish this difference and of course broaden your views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With no further do, firstly I would like to make sure that we are clear
with the empirical terminologies used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vulnerability Assessment&lt;/strong&gt; is the process of identifying,
    quantifying, and prioritizing (or ranking) the vulnerabilities in a
    system &lt;a href="[&amp;quot;Vulnerability"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Penetration Testing&lt;/strong&gt; - occasionally &lt;strong&gt;pentest&lt;/strong&gt;, is a method of
    evaluating computer and network security by simulating an attack on
    a computer system or network from external and internal threats &lt;a href=""&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly, the above two terms are confused with each other. In other
words, penetration testing is necessary to determine the true attack
footprint of your environment, assets, and so fort. For this reason the
the difference is highlighted and fully explained below in separated
sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Vulnerability Assessments&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is used and of course it is necessary to discovering potential
vulnerabilities throughout the environment in for instance,
organization, company, or even asset. Usually there different scope for
such an task, nonetheless sometimes does work only by available
automatic tools or through manual test as well. Usually, and please bare
this in your mind that full exploitation of systems and services is not
generally in scope for a normal vulnerability assessment task.
Most-likely, systems are typically enumerated and evaluated for
vulnerabilities and testing can be done with or without authentication.
Additionally, important in fact for the management staff is the
actionable reports, thus reports contain details about the mitigation
strategies, for instance, applying missing patches, correcting insecure
system configurations and among the others [3].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The steps to vulnerability assessments are [4]:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cataloging assets and resources in a system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assigning quantifiable value and importance to the resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifying the vulnerabilities or potential threats to each
    resource&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And mitigating or eliminating the most serious vulnerabilities for
    the most valuable resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Penetration testing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pen testing is coupled, or in other words it expands upon vulnerability
assessment efforts by introducing exploitation into the matrix. The main
purpose is to allow the business to understand if the mitigation
strategies are actually working as it was expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, pen testing requires a higher skill level than is needed
for vulnerability analysis. Particularly, this means that the price for
penetration test will be much higher than that of a vulnerability
analysis [3].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, there are two primary types of pen tests:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White box, it uses vulnerability assessment and other predisclosed
    information, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black box, it performed with very little knowledge of the target
    systems and it is left to the tester to perform their own
    reconnaissance, to gather information as much as possible..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, pen tests follow these steps [4]:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determination of scope&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Targeted information gathering or reconnaissance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploit attempts for access and escalation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sensitive data collection testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean up and final reporting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key difference between those two is that pen testing goes beyond the
level of identifying vulnerabilities and goes through the process of
exploitation, privilege escalation, and maintaining access to the target
system. Where on the other hand, vulnerability assessment provides a
better picture of any existing flaws in the system with out the
measuring the impact of the flaws to the system. However, vulnerability
assessment carefully identifies and quantifies all the vulnerabilities
in a non-invasive manner [5].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Reference&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.isaca.org/Pages/Glossary.aspx?tid=651&amp;amp;char=P" title="Glossary - isaca"&gt;“Glossary”&lt;/a&gt;.
ISACA. Retrieved 6 November 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;assessment”](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vulnerability_assessment).
Wikipedia. Retrieved 6 November 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3]: Lee Allen (May 2012). ”Advanced Penetration Testing for
Highly-Secured Environments: The Ultimate Security Guide”. Packt
Publishing Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4]: Steven Drew, 2006. &lt;a href="http://www.secureworks.com/resources/newsletter/2006-03/"&gt;Vulnerability Assessments Versus Penetration
Tests&lt;/a&gt;.
SecureWorks. Retrieved 11.11.2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[5]: Shakeel Ali and Tedi Heriyanto (2011). “BackTrack 4: Assuring
Security by Penetration Testing”. Packt Publishing Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pages"></category><category term="penetration"></category><category term="vulnerability"></category><category term="assessment"></category><category term="pentest"></category><category term="security"></category></entry></feed>